<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about 3D File Formats and APIs that can open and create 3D files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about 3D File Formats and APIs that can open and create 3D files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SMD File - Valve Studiomdl Data File - What is .smd file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/smd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/smd/</guid><description>What is an SMD file? The Valve Studiomdl Data File (.smd) format is primarily used in the development of 3D models for games that run on the Source engine, such as those created by Valve Corporation (e.g., Half-Life 2, Counter-Strike: Source).
Key features of the SMD format include
Structure:
Vertices: Each vertex is defined by its position in 3D space (x, y, z coordinates). Normals: Information about the surface normal for lighting calculations.</description></item><item><title>MDX File - Warcraft 3 Model File - What is .mdx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mdx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mdx/</guid><description>What is an MDX file? An MDX file is a model file used in Blizzard Entertainment&amp;rsquo;s game &amp;ldquo;Warcraft 3.&amp;rdquo; These files contain 3D models, including meshes, textures, animations, and other data necessary for rendering characters, buildings, and other objects within the game. Here&amp;rsquo;s a detailed breakdown of the MDX file format in the context of Warcraft 3:
Structure of an MDX File Header
The header typically contains metadata about the model, such as the version of the file format and other general information.</description></item><item><title>BHV File - Biovision Hierarchy File - What is .bhv file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/bhv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/bhv/</guid><description>What is a BVH file? BVH, short for Biovision Hierarchy, is a file format crucial for storing motion capture data used in animations. Primarily employed in computer graphics and animation software, BVH files organize movement details of characters or objects in a hierarchical structure. Each bone within this structure is defined by its name, relationships with other bones, and rotational keyframes that outline its motion over time.
This format serves as a standardized method for exchanging motion data across different software platforms like Autodesk Maya, Blender, Unity, and Unreal Engine.</description></item><item><title>BIP File - Autodesk Character Studio Biped File - What is .bip file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/bip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/bip/</guid><description>What is a BIP file? The .bip files are proprietary files utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s Character Studio Biped, an integral plugin for 3ds Max. These files are designed to store either motion capture data or pre-defined animations specifically tailored for bipedal characters.
Animators leverage .bip files to swiftly apply intricate animations to characters, bypassing the need to manually keyframe each movement. These files encompass a spectrum of actions such as walking, running, dancing, and more, easily adaptable to suit particular scenes.</description></item><item><title>AC File - AC3D Model Definition File - What is .ac file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ac/</guid><description>What is an AC file? The AC3D model file, with the .ac extension, is the primary file format used by the AC3D software to store 3D models.
What is AC3D? AC3D is a 3D modeling software that allows users to create, edit, and manipulate 3D models. It is used in various fields, including game development, simulations, and visualizations. The software is known for its ease of use and a wide range of features that support both beginners and advanced users.</description></item><item><title>MAX File - 3ds Max Scene File - What is an .max file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/max/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/max/</guid><description>What is a MAX file? The .max file extension is associated with Autodesk 3ds Max, popular 3D modeling, animation and rendering software. The .max file is 3ds Max Scene File and it contains information about 3D scene including geometry, textures, lighting, cameras and other settings.
When you save project or scene in Autodesk 3ds Max, it is typically stored with .max file extension; this file format allows users to save and later reopen their 3D projects to continue working on them; the .</description></item><item><title>F3D File - Fusion 360 Archive - What is an .f3d file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/f3d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/f3d/</guid><description>What is an F3D file? F3D file is a Fusion 360 Archive File, which is associated with Autodesk Fusion 360. Fusion 360 is cloud-based 3D CAD/CAM tool for product design and manufacturing developed by Autodesk.
The &amp;ldquo;.f3d&amp;rdquo; file contains snapshot of Fusion 360 design project including 3D models, sketches, assemblies and other design elements. It allows users to archive and share their designs with others and it can be used for collaboration and version control.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to HTML online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-html/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-html/</guid><description>About 3MF to HTML 3MF, which stands for 3D Manufacturing Format, is applied by various applications to render 3D object models across a wide spectrum of other applications, platforms, services, and printers. HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) serves as the extension for web pages designed for presentation in web browsers. Widely recognized as the language of the internet, HTML has adapted to accommodate the evolving demands for displaying new types of information on web pages.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to DAE online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-dae/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-dae/</guid><description>About 3MF to DAE FilmBox, referred to as 3MF, was originally developed by Kaydara to ensure compatibility with MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. assumed control, establishing it as a crucial standard for seamless 3D data exchange between different software applications.
A DAE file, short for Digital Asset Exchange file, serves as a format specifically created for sharing data between interactive 3D applications. It utilizes the COLLADA (COLLAborative Design Activity) XML schema, which acts as an open standard for sharing digital assets among various graphics software applications.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to U3D online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-u3d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-u3d/</guid><description>About 3MF to U3D 3MF, which stands for 3D Manufacturing Format, serves as a means for applications to present 3D object models across a wide range of other applications, platforms, services, and printers. U3D on the other hand, also known as stereolithography, is an adaptable file format ideally suited for representing three-dimensional surface geometry.
Converting 3MF files to the U3D format is common, and many online tools provide free conversion services.</description></item><item><title>CHR File Format - 3ds Max Characters File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/chr-3ds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/chr-3ds/</guid><description>What is a CHR file? CHR file format is associated with 3ds Max, a powerful software used for 3D modeling, rendering and animation. These files serve as repositories for three-dimensional character models, which can encompass both static and animated characters. Inside &amp;ldquo;.chr&amp;rdquo; file, you&amp;rsquo;ll find comprehensive representation of character, including its geometry (shape and structure), textures (surface appearance), lighting effects and various other properties related to 3D model.
These character models are instrumental in creation of characters that find their way into various media forms, such as video games, movies and television productions.</description></item><item><title>CHR File Format - CryENGINE Character File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/chr-cryengine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/chr-cryengine/</guid><description>What is a CHR file? CHR file in context of CryENGINE refers to a CryENGINE Character File. CryENGINE is game engine developed by Crytek and these files are used for storing character models and associated data for use in video games and other real-time applications.
CryENGINE Character File A CryENGINE Character File typically contains following components:
Character Model: This is 3D model of character, including its geometry, textures and animations. These models are often created using software like Autodesk Maya or Blender and then imported into CryENGINE.</description></item><item><title>MTL File Format - OBJ Material Template Library File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mtl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mtl/</guid><description>What is an MTL file? MTL file, short for Material Template Library, is companion file format used in 3D computer graphics and modeling. It is often associated with Wavefront OBJ file format, which is common format for storing 3D models and their associated materials and textures.
MTL File Format The MTL file format is associated with 3D computer graphics and is often used in conjunction with the OBJ (Wavefront .obj) file format.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to DAE online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-dae/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-dae/</guid><description>About 3DS to DAE The file extension &amp;ldquo;.3ds&amp;rdquo; is an identifier of the mesh file format known as 3D Studio (DOS), which is employed by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio has played a prominent role in the world of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has since transformed into the powerful software known as 3D Studio MAX.
A DAE file, abbreviated from Digital Asset Exchange file, functions as a format designed for the exchange of data between interactive 3D applications.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to DWG online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-dwg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-dwg/</guid><description>About 3DS to DWG The &amp;ldquo;.3ds&amp;rdquo; file extension serves as a marker for the mesh file format called 3D Studio (DOS), utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio has held a significant presence in the realm of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has subsequently evolved into the robust software now recognized as 3D Studio MAX.
A DWG file, short for Digital Asset Exchange file, operates as a format created to facilitate data exchange between interactive 3D applications.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to GLB online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-glb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-glb/</guid><description>About 3DS to GLB The &amp;ldquo;.3ds&amp;rdquo; file extension serves as a marker for the 3D mesh file format originally associated with Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio (DOS) software. Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio has been a significant player in the realm of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has evolved into the robust software known as 3D Studio MAX.
The GLB file format is a 3D format that consolidates models, textures, and animations into a unified binary file.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to PDF online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-pdf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-pdf/</guid><description>About 3DS to PDF The &amp;ldquo;.3ds&amp;rdquo; file extension serves as a marker for the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format, which was utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Since the 1990s, Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio has been a significant player in the realm of 3D file formats and has evolved into the robust software now recognized as 3D Studio MAX.
PDF, created by Adobe in the 1990s, is a universal document format.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to GLB online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-glb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-glb/</guid><description>About 3MF to GLB The 3D Manufacturing Format, commonly referred to as 3MF, is utilized by a wide array of applications to smoothly showcase 3D object models across a broad spectrum of other applications, platforms, services, and printers. The GLB file format is a 3D format that combines models, textures, and animations into a single binary file. It stands out for its effectiveness in distributing 3D content efficiently and enabling swift loading within applications and on the internet.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to STL online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-stl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-stl/</guid><description>About 3DS to STL The .3ds file extension is indicative of the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk 3D Studio has held a significant presence in the realm of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has subsequently evolved into 3D Studio MAX. STL, short for stereolithography, serves as a versatile file format for depicting three-dimensional surface geometry.
It is a common requirement to convert 3DS to STL file format and several apps are available online that can convert 3DS to STL for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to USDZ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-usdz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-usdz/</guid><description>About 3DS to USDZ The file extension .3ds is a clear identifier of the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format, which is employed by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software has maintained a prominent role in the domain of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has subsequently transformed into 3D Studio MAX. Learn more about 3DS File Format
A .usdz file is an uncompressed, unencrypted ZIP archive for the Universal Scene Description (USD) file format.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to STL online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-stl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-stl/</guid><description>About 3MF to STL 3MF, 3D Manufacturing Format, is used by applications to render 3D object models to a variety of other applications, platforms, services and printers. STL, short for stereolithography, serves as a versatile file format for depicting three-dimensional surface geometry.
Converting 3MF files to the STL file format is a frequently encountered task, and numerous online applications offer free conversion services. If you&amp;rsquo;re a software developer looking to integrate 3MF to STL conversion capabilities into your .</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to GLTF online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-gltf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-gltf/</guid><description>About 3DS to GLTF The .3ds file extension indicates the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk 3D Studio has held a significant position in the 3D file format landscape since the 1990s and has subsequently evolved into 3D Studio MAX.
glTF, or GL Transmission Format, is a 3D file format that uses JSON notation to encapsulate 3D model data. This JSON-based approach efficiently reduces the size of 3D assets and minimizes the computational resources needed for extraction and real-time use.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to FBX online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-fbx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-fbx/</guid><description>About 3DS to FBX The .3ds file extension is indicative of the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format utilized by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk 3D Studio has held a significant presence in the realm of 3D file formats since the 1990s and has subsequently evolved into 3D Studio MAX.
FilmBox, often known as FBX, is a widely embraced 3D file format that was initially created by Kaydara to ensure compatibility with MotionBuilder.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to OBJ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-obj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-obj/</guid><description>About 3DS to OBJ A file bearing the .3ds extension denotes the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format employed by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software. Autodesk 3D Studio has been a prominent player in the 3D file format arena since the 1990s and has since transformed into 3D Studio MAX.
OBJ files are used by Wavefront&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Visualizer application for defining and storing the geometric objects.
It is a common requirement to convert 3DS to OBJ file format and several apps are available online that can convert 3DS to OBJ for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to OBJ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-obj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-obj/</guid><description>About 3MF to OBJ The 3D Manufacturing Format, known as 3MF, is employed by various applications to seamlessly present 3D object models across a diverse range of other applications, platforms, services, and printers. In contrast, OBJ files serve as a means for Wavefront&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Visualizer application to define and retain geometric objects. These files facilitate the bidirectional exchange of geometric data.
Many people often need to convert 3MF files to the OBJ file format, and there are numerous online tools that offer this conversion service for free.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to XLSX online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-xlsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-xlsx/</guid><description>About FBX to XLSX FilmBox, frequently known as FBX, is a widely used 3D file format that was initially created by Kaydara to enhance compatibility with MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. took the reins of this format, solidifying its status as a standard for effortlessly exchanging 3D data across various 3D software applications.
XLSX is a widely recognized format for Microsoft Excel documents introduced by Microsoft alongside the release of Microsoft Office 2007.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to DAE online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-dae/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-dae/</guid><description>About FBX to DAE FBX, short for FilmBox, is a widely embraced 3D file format that Kaydara initially created to enhance compatibility with MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. took over this format, solidifying its status as a fundamental standard for effortless 3D data exchange across various 3D software applications.
A DAE file, short for Digital Asset Exchange file, serves as a format for transferring data between interactive 3D applications. It relies on the COLLADA (COLLAborative Design Activity) XML schema, which represents an open standard for exchanging digital assets among various graphics software applications.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to USDZ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-usdz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-usdz/</guid><description>About FBX to USDZ FBX, short for FilmBox, stands as a widely embraced 3D file format initially crafted by Kaydara for MotionBuilder. Autodesk Inc. assumed ownership in 2006, cementing its status as a primary 3D data exchange format utilized by a multitude of 3D software tools.
A file bearing the .usdz extension represents an uncompressed and unencrypted ZIP archive tailored for the USD (Universal Scene Description) file format. It houses proxies for various file types, including textures and animations, all conveniently encapsulated within the archive.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3DS to PLY online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-ply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds-to-ply/</guid><description>About 3DS to PLY The &amp;ldquo;.3ds&amp;rdquo; file extension signifies the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format used by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio, a pivotal software in 3D file formats since the 1990s, now known as 3D Studio MAX.
PLY, short for Polygon File Format, stores 3D objects as polygons. It&amp;rsquo;s versatile, with both ASCII and Binary formats, the latter being efficient for storage and retrieval.
Converting 3DS to PLY is a frequent need, allowing you to change 3DS files into PLY format.</description></item><item><title>Convert 3MF to 3DS online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-3ds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf-to-3ds/</guid><description>About 3MF to 3DS FilmBox, known as 3MF, is a 3D file format initially created by Kaydara for compatibility with MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. took over, making it a vital standard for smooth 3D data interchange among various software applications. A file with a .3ds extension is a format used by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software, dating back to the 1990s. It contains data for 3D scenes and is widely used for importing and exporting 3D data.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to 3DS online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-3ds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-3ds/</guid><description>About FBX to 3DS FilmBox, commonly referred to as FBX, is a widely adopted 3D file format originally developed by Kaydara to facilitate compatibility with MotionBuilder. Autodesk Inc. assumed control of this format in 2006, establishing it as a key standard for the seamless exchange of 3D data among diverse 3D software applications.
A file bearing the .3ds extension signifies the 3D Studio (DOS) mesh file format employed by Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s 3D Studio software.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to GLB online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-glb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-glb/</guid><description>About FBX to GLB FBX, often referred to as FilmBox, is a highly embraced 3D file format initially created by Kaydara to enhance compatibility with MotionBuilder. Autodesk Inc. took over control of this format in 2006, solidifying its position as a vital standard for effortlessly exchanging 3D data among a variety of 3D software applications.
The GLB file format is a compact 3D format that combines models, textures, and animations into a single binary file.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to PLY online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-ply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-ply/</guid><description>About FBX to PLY FBX, commonly known as FilmBox, is a widely adopted 3D file format originally developed by Kaydara to improve compatibility with MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. assumed control of this format, cementing its role as a crucial standard for seamlessly exchanging 3D data across various 3D software applications.
PLY, short for Polygon File Format, is a 3D file format designed to store graphical objects defined by a collection of polygons.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to DWG online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-dwg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-dwg/</guid><description>About FBX to DWG FilmBox, often abbreviated as FBX, stands as a widely utilized 3D file format initially crafted by Kaydara to support MotionBuilder. Autodesk Inc. took ownership of this format in 2006, solidifying it as a primary standard for 3D data interchange across various 3D software tools. On the other hand, DWG, short for stereolithography, serves as an interchangeable file format designed to represent three-dimensional surface geometries.
Converting FBX files into the DWG format is a frequent necessity, and numerous online applications offer free conversion tools for this task.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to GLTF online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-gltf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-gltf/</guid><description>About FBX to GLTF FilmBox, commonly known as FBX, stands as a widely adopted 3D file format initially crafted by Kaydara to complement MotionBuilder. In 2006, Autodesk Inc. took the helm, propelling FBX into a prominent position as a primary 3D data exchange format embraced by a multitude of 3D software tools.
glTF, short for GL Transmission Format, serves as a 3D file format designed to encapsulate 3D model data within JSON notation.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to OBJ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-obj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-obj/</guid><description>About FBX to OBJ FBX, FilmBox, is a popular 3D file format that was developed by Kaydara for MotionBuilder. It was acquired by Autodesk Inc in 2006 and is now one of the main 3D data exchange file format used by many 3D tools. OBJ files are used by Wavefront&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Visualizer application for defining and storing the geometric objects. It is a common requirement to convert FBX to OBJ file format and several apps are available online that can convert FBX to OBJ for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert FBX to STL online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-stl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx-to-stl/</guid><description>About FBX to STL FBX, FilmBox, is a popular 3D file format that was developed by Kaydara for MotionBuilder. It was acquired by Autodesk Inc in 2006 and is now one of the main 3D data exchange file format used by many 3D tools. STL, abbreviation for stereolithrography, is an interchangeable file format for representation of 3-Dimensional surface geometry.
It is a common requirement to convert FBX to STL file format and several apps are available online that can convert FBX to STL for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to USDZ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-usdz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-usdz/</guid><description>About GLB to USDZ GLB is a popular 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). A .usdz file is essentially an uncompressed and unencrypted ZIP archive designed for the USD (Universal Scene Description) file format. This archive conveniently encapsulates and serves as a proxy for various files in alternative formats (e.g., textures and animations) that are neUSDZed within it. These files can be seamlessly utilized by the USD runtime, eliminating the necessity for any unpacking process.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to HTML online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-html/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-html/</guid><description>About GLB to HTML The use of GLB files in 3D file formats is not something new. GLB is a commonly used 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). GLB files can be converted to HTML file format which is a universal file format for displaying content in web browsers. For application developers who want to embed GLB to HTML conversion functionality in their applications.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to 3DS online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-3ds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-3ds/</guid><description>About GLB to 3DS The use of GLB files in 3D file formats is not something new. GLB is a commonly used 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). 3DS, on the other hand, represents 3D Sudio (DOS) mesh file format used by Autodesk 3D Studio. Several apps are available online that can be used for conversion of GLB to 3DS for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to DAE online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-dae/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-dae/</guid><description>About GLB to DAE The use of GLB files in 3D file formats is not something new. GLB is a commonly used 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). DAE, on the other hand, is a Digital Asset Exchange file format that is used for exchanging data between interactive 3D applications. GLB files can be converted to DAE file format using several online free apps.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to PDF online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-pdf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-pdf/</guid><description>About GLB to PDF GLB files are binary files used for saving and representing 3D modles in the GL Transmission file format. PDF file format introduced a standard for representation of documents and other reference material that is independent of application software, hardware as well as Operating System. Several apps are available online that can be used to convert GLB to PDF online for FREE. For application developers who write applications for converting GLB files to other file formats, you can use the Aspose.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to GLTF online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-gltf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-gltf/</guid><description>About GLB to GLTF GLB is a popular 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). GLB to GLTF is a widely used operation for converting GLB files to GLTF file format. There are many apps available online that can be used for conversion of GLB to GLTF for FREE. If you are an application developer who would like to add the functionality of GLB to GLTF in his .</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to OBJ online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-obj/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-obj/</guid><description>About GLB to OBJ GLB is a popular 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). OBJ files are used by Wavefront’s Advanced Visualizer application to define and store the geometric objects. It is a common requirement to convert GLB files to OBJ file format and several apps are available onilne that can convert GLB to OBJ for FREE. You can use Aspose.3D API for converting GLB to OBJ in your .</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to FBX online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-fbx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-fbx/</guid><description>About GLB to FBX GLB is a popular 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). FBX, FilmBox, is another popular 3D file format that was originally developed by Kaydara for MotionBuilder. GLB to FBX is a widely used operation for converting GLB files to FBX file format. There are many apps available online that can be used for conversion of GLB to FBX for FREE.</description></item><item><title>Convert GLB to STL online for FREE</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-stl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb-to-stl/</guid><description>About GLB to STL GLB is a popular 3D binary file format that represents 3D models in the GL Transmission format i.e. (glTF). STL, abbreviation for stereolithrography, is an interchangeable file format that represents 3-dimensional surface geometry. GLB to STL is a widely used operation for converting GLB files to STL file format. There are many apps available online that can be used for conversion of GLB to STL for FREE.</description></item><item><title>C4D File Format - Cinema 4D Model File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/c4d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/c4d/</guid><description>What is a C4D file? A C4D file is a file format used by Maxon Cinema 4D, a 3D modeling, animation and rendering software. C4D files contain 3D models, animations, lighting and other information related to scene that can be used to create 3D graphics and animations for film, television, video games, and other visual media.
C4D files can be opened and edited in Cinema 4D as well as in other 3D modeling and animation software that support the format.</description></item><item><title>BLEND File Format - Blender 3D File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/blend/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/blend/</guid><description>What is a BLEND file? A blend file is a file format utilized by Blender, a widely-used 3D modeling and animation software. It is the default file format used by Blender to save and store all the data related to a 3D scene, including 3D models, materials, textures, animations, and more..
The blend file format is a binary file which organizes and stores data in the form of hierarchical structures. These hierarchical structures contain information about the objects and their properties in a 3D scene.</description></item><item><title>POV - Persistence of Vision File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/pov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/pov/</guid><description>What is a POV file? A POV file is a plain text file that contains instructions for the POV-Ray ray tracing software. These instructions are written in a special scripting language that is specific to POV-Ray. It specifies the scene to be rendered, including the 3D objects, materials, lighting, and other properties that define the appearance of the scene. POV files use a special scripting language that is specific to POV-Ray and can be used to create complex and detailed 3D scenes.</description></item><item><title>CAF File Format - Cal3D Binary Animation File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/caf-cal3d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/caf-cal3d/</guid><description>What is a CAF file? A .CAF file typically refers to a &amp;ldquo;Cal3D Binary Animation File.&amp;rdquo; Cal3D is an open-source 3D character animation library often used in video game development and other interactive 3D applications. These &amp;ldquo;.caf&amp;rdquo; files are specifically designed to store binary animation data for characters or objects created using Cal3D framework.
CAF files play a crucial role in imparting realistic human-like movements to characters. They define animations for various actions such as walking, running or any other dynamic actions that character might perform.</description></item><item><title>DBM File - DAZ Brick Material File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/dbm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/dbm/</guid><description>What is a DBM file? A DBM (Daz Brick Material) file is a Shader Mixer network file created with 3D character modeling application, DAZ Studio. It describes the material of the 3D mode i.e. surface/displacement/interior volume. DAZ allows you to create your own custom shader by connecting a series of bricks together. This combines collectively as a DBM file that forms a shader network. It is the DBM file that specifies how a material is shaded.</description></item><item><title>MP File Format - Maya PLE Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mp/</guid><description>What is an MP file? An MP file is a project file created with the Personal Learning Edition (PLE) of 3D modelling program, Maya. It is supported by the PLE version of Maya only and is purely for non-commercial uses. For this purpose, Maya PLE edition includes a watermark on the exported file. Maya PLE provides limited functionality and can be installed on personal computers only. The MP file contains all the information about the project created with PLE and can be opened with Autodesk Maya PLE.</description></item><item><title>STP File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/stp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/stp/</guid><description>What is an STP file? An STP file is a 3D CAD file used for exchange of product data between CAD and CAM applications. It contains information about 3D objects and is saved similar to the STEP file format. STP files facilitate the exchange of data between applications as per the STEP Application Protocols ISO 10303-2xx. This ISO defines the encoding mechanism for data representation in EXPRESS data modeling language. STP files can be opened in applications such as such as Autodesk Fusion 360.</description></item><item><title>3DM</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3dm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3dm/</guid><description>What is a 3DM file? A file with .3dm extension is an open-source file format that is used for 3D graphics software. It contains 3D models along with their dependent elements such as surface, points, and curve information. 3DM file format was developed by openNURBS initiative for accurately transferring 3-D geometry between applications. 3DM files can be opened and converted with applications such as Rhinoceros, SAP VEViewer, Moment of Inspiration, and Right Hemisphere Deep View.</description></item><item><title>B3D - Blitz3D Entity Model File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/b3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/b3d/</guid><description>What is a B3D file? A file with .b3d extension is a model file used by Blitz3D which may contain video game models for characters, buildings, terrain and other objects. The Blitz3D is a programming language used to create blitz3d games. Blitz3D is a powerful, flexible and easy-to-use programming language designed for the sole purpose of writing video games. The developers can create action packed 3D games, 2D puzzlers, adventures, RPGS, whatever just by using Blitz3D.</description></item><item><title>MB - Maya Binary File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/mb/</guid><description>What is an MB file? A file with .mb extension is a binary project file created with Autodesk Maya application. Unlike the MA file format, which is in ASCII file format, MB files are stored in binary file format. These can not be opened in text editors but can be examined in Hex Editors. MB files contain information such as geometry, lighting, animation, and rendering for defining the 3D scenes.</description></item><item><title>DRC - Google Draco File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/drc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/drc/</guid><description>What is a DRC file? A file with .drc extension is a compressed 3D file format created with Google Draco library. Google offers Draco as open source library for compressing and decompressing 3D geometric meshes and point clouds, and improves storage and transmission of 3D graphics. It encodes the input data and saves it as .drc file. At the receiving end, the API reads .drc files and can output these as PLY or OBJ files.</description></item><item><title>E57 - Lidar Point Cloud Data Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/e57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/e57/</guid><description>What is an E57 file? A file with .e57 extension is a compact, vendor-neutral file format that is used for storing and exchange of three-dimensional (3D) imaging data such as point clouds, images, and metadata. Such data is often created with systems such as laser scanners. It was developed by the Data Interoperability sub-committee of the ATSM E57 Committee on 3D Imaging Systems. E57 is open source and stores 3D point data, its attributes (such as color and intensity), and 2D imagery as captured by the 3D imaging system.</description></item><item><title>USD - Universal Scene Description Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/usd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/usd/</guid><description>What is a USD file? A file with .usd extension is a Universal Scene Description file format that encodes data for the purpose of data interchanging and augmenting between digital content creation applications. Developed by Pixar, USD provides the ability to interchange elemental assets (such as models) or animation.
USD File Format USD files can have binary format (also known as Crate files) or ASCII-backed files. Both these file formats are interchangeable where the references can be linked to .</description></item><item><title>USDZ - Universal Scene Description ZIP Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/usdz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/usdz/</guid><description>What is a USDZ file? A file with .usdz is an uncompressed and unencrypetd ZIP archive for the USD (Universal Scene Description) file format that contains and proxies for files of other formats (such as textures, and animations) embedded within the archive and runs them directly with the USD run-time without any need of unpacking. USDZ files are packages whose design is based on the new Ar-level abstraction of a package.</description></item><item><title>ASE - Autodesk ASCII Scene Export File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ase/</guid><description>What is an ASE file? A file with a .ase extension is an Autodesk ASCII Scene Export file format that is an ASCII representation of a scene, containing 2D or 3D information while exporting scene data using Autodesk. Autodesk provides options to include scene components while exporting scene data. You can include Mesh definition along with vertex and face information, Material description, transform animation data for the objects, complete mesh definition of every n frames, animation data for cameras and lights and IK joint settings.</description></item><item><title>X - DirectX 2.0 File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/x/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/x/</guid><description>What is a X file? A file with .x extension refers to DirectX 3D Graphics legacy file format that was introduced with Microsoft DirectX 2.0. It was used for 3D graphics rendering in games and specifies the structures for meshes, textures, animations, and user-defined objects. It has been deprecated since 2014 as the Autodesk FBX file format serves better as a more modern format. X is template-driven and is free of any usage knowledge.</description></item><item><title>FBX - FilmBox 3D File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/fbx/</guid><description>What is an FBX file? FBX, FilmBox, is a popular 3D file format that was originally developed by Kaydara for MotionBuilder. It was acquired by Autodesk Inc in 2006 and is now one of the main 3D exchange formats as used by many 3D tools. FBX is available in both binary and ASCII file format. The format was established to provided interoperability between digital content creation applications. There are many tools available for conversion from/to FBX file format.</description></item><item><title>GLTF - GL Transmission File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/gltf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/gltf/</guid><description>What is a GLTF file? glTF (GL Transmission Format) is a 3D file format that stores 3D model information in JSON format. The use of JSON minimizes both the size of 3D assets and the runtime processing needed to unpack and use those assets. It was adopted for the efficient transmission and loading of 3D scenes and models by applications. glTF was developed by the Khronos Group 3D Formats Working Group and is also described as JPEG of 3D by its creators.</description></item><item><title>JT - Jupiter Tessellation File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/jt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/jt/</guid><description>What is a JT file? JT (Jupiter Tessellation) is an efficient, industry-focused and flexible ISO-standardized 3D data format developed by Siemens PLM Software. Mechanical CAD domains of Aerospace, automotive industry, and Heavy Equipment use JT as their most leading 3D visualization format.
JT format is a scene graph that supports the attributes and nodes that are CAD specific. Sophisticated compression techniques are used to store facet data (triangles). This format is structured to support visual attributes, product and manufacturing information (PMI), and Metadata.</description></item><item><title>PLY - Polygon 3D File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ply/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ply/</guid><description>What is a PLY file? PLY, Polygon File Format, represents 3D file format that stores graphical objects described as a collection of polygons. The purpose of this file format was to establish a simple and easy file type that is general enough to be useful for a wide range of models. PLY file format comes as ASCII as well as Binary format for compact storage and for rapid saving and loading.</description></item><item><title>3MF</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3mf/</guid><description>What is a 3MF file? 3MF, 3D Manufacturing Format, is used by applications to render 3D object models to a variety of other applications, platforms, services and printers. It was built to avoid the limitations and issues in other 3D file formats, like STL, for working with the latest versions of 3D printers. 3MF is relatively a new file format that has been developed and published by the 3MF consortium. It is rich enough to fully describe a model, retaining internal information, colour, and other characteristics that makes it extensible for supporting new innovations in 3D printing.</description></item><item><title>GLB</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/glb/</guid><description>What is a GLB file? GLB is the binary file format representation of 3D models saved in the GL Transmission Format (glTF). Information about 3D models such as node hierarchy, cameras, materials, animations and meshes in binary format. This binary format stores the glTF asset (JSON, .bin and images) in a binary blob. It also avoids the issue of increase in file size which happens in case of glTF. GLB file format results in compact file sizes, fast loading, complete 3D scene representation, and extensibility for further development.</description></item><item><title>3D2 - CAD-3D 2.0 File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3d2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3d2/</guid><description>What is a 3D2 file? A file with .3D2 extension is a CAD-3D 2.0 file that stores multiple 3D objects and information about these objects. The lightning and colour palettes information used by the 3D objects are all stored in this file. A single file can hold up to 40 objects. 3D2 had been used as an early format for computer animations. 3DS files can be opened with Quick3D application software.</description></item><item><title>3DS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/3ds/</guid><description>What is 3DS file? A file with .3ds extension represents 3D Sudio (DOS) mesh file format used by Autodesk 3D Studio. Autodesk 3D Studio has been in 3D file format market since 1990s and has now evolved to 3D Studio MAX for working with 3D modeling, animation and rendering. A 3DS file contains data for 3D representation of scenes and images and is one of the popular file formats for 3D data import and export.</description></item><item><title>AMF - Additive Manufacturing File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/amf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/amf/</guid><description>What is an AMF file? An AMF file consists of guidelines for objects description in order to be used by Additive Manufacturing processes. It contains an opening XML tag and ends with a element. This is preceded by an XML declaration line specifying the XML version and encoding of the file. The declarations can include measurement units information and, in the absence of such information, millimetres are used as default unit.</description></item><item><title>DAE - Digital Asset Exchange File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/dae/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/dae/</guid><description>What is a DAE file? A DAE file is a Digital Asset Exchange file format that is used for exchanging data between interactive 3D applications. This file format is based on the COLLADA (COLLAborative Design Activity) XML schema which is an open standard XML schema for the exchange of digital assets among graphics software applications. It has been adopted by ISO as a publicly available specification, ISO/pAS 17506. DAE files can be opened in applications such as Adobe Photoshop, AutoDesk Maya, AutoDesk AutoCAD, and APIs such as Aspose.</description></item><item><title>IPT - Autodesk Inventor Part File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ipt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ipt/</guid><description>What is an IPT file? A file with .ipt extension is native Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s Inventor Part file format for parts. It is used in combination with Autodesk assembly (.iam) files. IPT files can be imported in 3DS Max as Body Objects where the geometry in the ACIS solids format remains in the same format. 3DS Max retains the object naming as assigned in Autodesk Inventor and the component models can be edited similar to other objects including applying modifiers, alter materials, add lighting and cameras, create animation, and so on.</description></item><item><title>MA File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/ma/</guid><description>What is an MA file? A file with .ma extension is a 3D project file created with Autodesk Maya application. It contains large list of textual commands to specify information about the file. A .ma file can be opened and edited in any text editor to fix any issues with the commands in case a file gets corrupt. These files contain information for defining the 3D Scene information such as geometry, lighting, animation, and rendering.</description></item><item><title>OBJ File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/obj/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/obj/</guid><description>What is an OBJ File? OBJ files are used by Wavefront&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Visualizer application to define and store the geometric objects. Backward and forward transmission of geometric data is made possible through OBJ files. Both polygonal geometry like points, lines, texture vertices, faces and free-form geometry (curves and surfaces) are supported by OBJ format. This format does not support animation or information related to light and position of scenes.
An OBJ file is usually an end product of the 3D modeling process generated by a CAD (Computer Aided Design).</description></item><item><title>PRC File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/prc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/prc/</guid><description>The PRC file formats The &amp;ldquo;.prc&amp;rdquo; extensions are being used for Product Representation Compact 3D file format and an e-book file format by MobiPocket.
What is a Product Representation Compact (PRC) file? PRC (Product Representation Compact) is a 3D file format that is optimized to store, load, and display 3D data especially coming from CAD (Computer-Aided Design) systems. It is a sequential binary file, written in a portable way. PRC can be used to embed 3D data in a PDF file.</description></item><item><title>RVM - AVEVA PDMS Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/rvm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/rvm/</guid><description>What is RVM file? RVM data files are related to AVEVA PDMS. RVM file is an AVEVA Plant Design Management System Model project file. AVEVA&amp;rsquo;s Plant Design Management System (PDMS) is the most popular 3D design system using data-centric technology for managing projects. Numerous applications are available to open and convert RVM files to other formats such as 3DS.
RVM File Format Not much details can be found about the RVM file format other than that it can be saved in both binary and ASCII format.</description></item><item><title>STEP File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/step/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/step/</guid><description>What is a STEP file? STEP file is a widely used data exchange format for Computer-aided design (CAD). It was standardized in 1994 by the ISO committee under the name of &amp;ldquo;ISO 10303-21&amp;rdquo;. ISO 10303-21 defines the encoding mechanism for representing data in EXPRESS data modeling language. A STEP- file is also known as p21-File and STEP Physical File. The file extensions used for STEP-file are .stp and .step.
Basic History In 1994, the original Part 21 specification was issued.</description></item><item><title>U3D - Universal 3D File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/u3d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/u3d/</guid><description>What is a U3D file? U3D (Universal 3D) is a compressed file format and data structure for 3D computer graphics. It contains 3D model information such as triangle meshes, lighting, shading, motion data, lines and points with color and structure. The format was accepted as ECMA-363 standard in August 2005. 3D PDF documents support U3D objects embedding and can be viewed in Adobe Reader (version 7 and onwards).
U3D format was developed keeping in view the aim to establish a universal standard for three-dimensional data storage and exchange.</description></item><item><title>VRML File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/vrml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/vrml/</guid><description>What is a VRML file? The Virtual Reality Modeling Language (VRML) is a file format for representation of interactive 3D world objects over the World Wide Web (www). It finds its usage in creating three-dimensional representations of complex scenes such as illustrations, definition and virtual reality presentations. The format has been superseded by X3D. Many 3D modelling applications can save objects and scenes in VRML format.
VRML File Format VRML is a text file format that specifies information such as vertices and edges of a 3D polygon along with information such as surface colour, UV mapped textures, shininess, transparency and so on.</description></item><item><title>X3D - 3D Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/x3d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/3d/x3d/</guid><description>What is a X3D file? X3D is an XML based 3D graphics file format for presentation of 3D information. It is a modular standard and is defined through several ISO specifications. The format supports vector and raster graphics, transparency, lighting effects, and animation settings including rotations, fades, and swings. It became successor of VRML file format in 2001. X3D has the advantage of encoding colour information (unlike STL) that is used during printing the model on a colour 3D printer.</description></item></channel></rss>