<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Page Description Language and APIs that can open and create PDL files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Page Description Language and APIs that can open and create PDL files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AVERY File - Avery Design &amp; Print Label File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/avery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/avery/</guid><description>What is a AVERY file? An AVERY file is a printable document that contains one or more labels for printing purpose. It is created with the Avery Design &amp;amp; Print or Design &amp;amp; Print Online software. The labels inside an AVERY file may comprise of different element such as text, graphics, and page layout information. This information is used by printing companies for printing variety of design elements such as business cards, name tags, binder inserts, address labels, disc labels, obituary templates, and greeting cards.</description></item><item><title>OXPS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/oxps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/oxps/</guid><description>What is an OXPS file? The file format OXPS is known as Open XML Paper Specification. It’s a page description language and document format. Microsoft is the developer of this format. OXPS file format is very much familiar to these PDF files. The setup of the OXPS file is the same as an XPS format. The only difference is the description of OXPS as an open format. The .oxps file extension is the most current version of the XPS file format originated by Microsoft and Ecma International.</description></item><item><title>What is an SVG file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/svg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/svg/</guid><description>What is an SVG file? An SVG file is a Scalar Vector Graphics file that uses XML based text format for describing the appearance of an image. The word Scalable refers to the fact that the SVG can be scaled to different sizes without losing any quality. Text-based description of such files makes them independent of resolution. It is one of the most used formats for building a website and print graphics in order to achieve scalability.</description></item><item><title>EPS File Format - Encapsulated PostScript File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/eps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/eps/</guid><description>What is an EPS file? A .eps file is an image file that is saved to disc in Encapsulated Postscript file format. It may contain any combination of text, graphics and images. EPS files may also include a bitmap preview image encapsulated inside for display by applications that can open such files.
Brief History of EPS File Format A quick look at EPS file format from history perspective reveals the following information:</description></item><item><title>INDD - Adobe InDesign Page Layout File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/indd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/indd/</guid><description>What is an INDD file? An file with .indd extension is an Adobe InDesign project file that contains the page layout information of the project. INDD stands for InDesign Document. These files commonly store page formatting information, books, magazines, newspapers, flyers, brochures or other print media like mobile &amp;amp; webpage mockups. INDD file type is proprietary file format of Adobe and is the default file format for InDesign. Graphic Designers, journalists, marketers, and publishers working with InDesign use this file type.</description></item><item><title>INDT - Adobe InDesign Page Layout Template File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/indt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/indt/</guid><description>What is an INDT file? A file with .indt extension is an Adobe InDesign layout template file that contains predefined settings. The design and contents of these files include templates of newsletters, books, magazines, flyer, and print media. Once editing is finished, the INDT file can be saved to disc as INDD file. User can also create new INDT file from within the InDesign and convert it to other formats such as PDF, EPUB, or JPEG.</description></item><item><title>CGM File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/cgm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/cgm/</guid><description>What is a CGM file? Computer Graphics Metafile (CGM) is free, platform-independent, international standard metafile format for storing and exchanging vector graphics (2D), raster graphics, and text. CGM uses an object-oriented approach and many function provisions for image production. CGM uses these object-oriented characteristics for remolding graphical elements to render an image. A metafile contains necessary information that defines other files. In CGM, a text-based source file contains all graphical elements that can be later compiled into a binary file.</description></item><item><title>PCL</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/pcl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/pcl/</guid><description>What is a PCL file? PCL stands for Printer Command Language which is a Page Description Language introduced by Hewlett Packard (HP). HP created PCL to provide an efficient way for controlling printer features across many different printing devices. The format was originally developed for HP&amp;rsquo;s dot matrix and Inkjet printers, but has been part of various thermal, matrix and page printers with the passage of time. The format underwent several different revisions, resulting in different versions where each version was enhanced to meet the demands of time with respect to the printer control features.</description></item><item><title>PS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/ps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/ps/</guid><description>What is a .PS file? PostScript (PS) is a general-purpose page description language used in the business of desktop and electronic publishing. The main focus of PostScript (PS) is to facilitate the two-dimensional graphic design. Most languages require a distinct compilation stage before the code execution while Post Script (PS) format support a runtime straight forward interpretation. Its early version defines the graphical shapes, different text appearances and modelled imageries on printed pages or displayed pages, following the rules of Adobe imaging model.</description></item><item><title>SWF File - Shockwave Flash Movie File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/swf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/swf/</guid><description>What is an SWF file? An SWF file is an animation file that is created with Adobe Flash. It may contain different type of elements such as text, vector images, raster images, actionscripts, objects such as circles, lines, squares, and rectangle to create the animation. SWF files arrange these multimedia items in frames that can be played on different frames per second (fps). SWF means Short Web File but is also known has Shockwave Format.</description></item><item><title>TEX File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/tex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/tex/</guid><description>What is a TEX File? TeX is a language that comprises of programming as well as mark-up features, used to typeset documents. Donald Knuth from Stanford University, is the creator of this resourceful typesetting system. Across the world, TeX is the ultimate choice of authors and publishers to produce high quality technical documents. TeX performs an outstanding job of formatting complex mathematical expressions. In conjunction with a high-quality phototypesetter, TeX competes the results generated by the best traditional typesetting systems.</description></item><item><title>XPS - Page Layout File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/xps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/xps/</guid><description>What is an XPS file? An XPS file represents page layout files that are based on XML Paper Specifications created by Microsoft. It was developed as a replacement of EMF file format and is similar to PDF file format, but uses XML in layout, appearance, and printing information of a document. It is, in fact, more justified to say that XPS is an attempt on PDF, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get enough popularity as owned by PDF for many reasons.</description></item><item><title>XSLFO</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/xslfo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/page-description-language/xslfo/</guid><description>What is an XSL-FO file? XSL-FO (XSL Formatting Objects) is a powerful stylesheet language for formatting XML documents. The semantics of the bounded form of paper and print is expressed by XSL-FO when the dimensions are fixed. In contrast to HTML, which represents the semantics of the unbounded form of a browser window with variable dimensions. The XML documents formatted by XSL-FO are mostly used to generate PDF files. XSL (Extensible Stylesheet Language) is a set of feature-complete W3C technologies intended to design for formatting and exchanging XML documents and XSL-FO part of this language.</description></item></channel></rss>