<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Video File Formats and APIs to open and create Video files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Video File Formats and APIs to open and create Video files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TTML2 File - Timed Text Markup Language 2 - What is TTML2 file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ttml2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ttml2/</guid><description>What is TTML2? Timed Text Markup Language 2 (TTML2) is an XML-based language designed for the representation of timed text media, such as subtitles and captions. It serves as a standardized format for the interchange, authoring, and distribution of timed text content across various platforms and systems.
TTML2 is intended for:
Interchange: Facilitating the exchange of timed text information among different authoring systems. Transcoding: Converting timed text content into various legacy distribution formats used in subtitling and captioning.</description></item><item><title>WebVTT File - Web Video Text Tracks - What is WebVTT file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/webvtt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/webvtt/</guid><description>What Is WebVTT? WebVTT (Web Video Text Tracks Format) is a text-based subtitle format used to add timed text tracks to videos. It is the official format supported by HTML5 through the &amp;lt;track&amp;gt; element, allowing you to add:
Subtitles (translated speech) Captions (speech and sound effects) Descriptions (visual information for screen readers) Chapters (navigable points in the video) Metadata Basic Structure of WebVTT A WebVTT file consists of: An optional header (WEBVTT).</description></item><item><title>BNP File - Sony Camcorder Video Data - What is .bnp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bnp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bnp/</guid><description>What is a BNP file? The .bnp file format is associated with Sony Camcorders and typically functions as a metadata file that supports video and other media recorded on Sony devices. Here’s a breakdown of what this format does:
Overview of BNP file
File Type: Sony Camcorder Video Data File Primary Function: Stores metadata information for video and media files. Associated with: AVCHD and other video files saved on Sony camcorders.</description></item><item><title>MJP File - MJPEG Video File - What is .mjp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mjp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mjp/</guid><description>What is an MJP file? The .mjp file format, typically associated with Motion JPEG (MJPEG) video files, contains sequences of JPEG images stored as individual frames, making it a type of video file.
Here are key details about MJP file
Format Type: Video format that uses a series of JPEG images to create a video sequence. Compression: Relies on JPEG compression for each frame, which results in a high-quality image at the cost of relatively larger file sizes.</description></item><item><title>ASS File - Advanced SubStation Alpha - What is .ass file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ass/</guid><description>What is an ASS file? An ASS file, short for Advanced SubStation Alpha, is a subtitles file created with Aegisub, a cross-platform application for generating customized subtitles. These files are commonly used with movies, anime, and karaoke tracks, formatted using Advanced SubStation Alpha syntax, which offers robust styling and formatting features.
The key features of an ASS file include:
Customizable styles: Users can modify the subtitle text&amp;rsquo;s style, including font, color, size, and orientation.</description></item><item><title>DRP File - DaVinci Resolve Project - What is .drp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/drp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/drp/</guid><description>What is a DRP file? A DRP file stands for DaVinci Resolve Project file, created specifically by Blackmagic Design&amp;rsquo;s DaVinci Resolve software. This file format is used to store all the necessary data to load a video editing project inside Resolve. However, it’s important to note that DRP files don’t directly contain video, audio, or media files. Instead, they contain references to the media files that are part of your project.</description></item><item><title>DCE File - DriveCam Event File - What is .dce file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dce/</guid><description>What is a DCE file? DCE file format typically refers to DriveCam Events, which are events recorded by a DriveCam system. DriveCam is a type of in-vehicle video camera system often used in the context of fleet management and driver safety. The system is designed to capture video footage when certain events or behaviors are detected, such as harsh acceleration, sudden braking, sharp turns, or collisions.
When a DriveCam Event (DCE) occurs, the system records video footage leading up to and following the triggering event; this footage can be valuable for assessing driver behavior, improving safety, and investigating incidents; the video data is usually stored in a specific file format known as DCE file format.</description></item><item><title>INSV File - Insta360 Panoramic Video File - What is .insv file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/insv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/insv/</guid><description>What is an INSV file? An INSV file is a type of file format used to store panoramic video captured by Insta360 cameras. Insta360 cameras are designed to capture immersive, panoramic video and images, allowing users to create content that provides complete view of their surroundings. These cameras are popular among videographers, photographers, and enthusiasts who want to explore innovative ways of storytelling and capturing moments.
What does INSV file contain?</description></item><item><title>MP5 File - Chinese Portable Media Player Video - What is an .mp5 file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mp5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mp5/</guid><description>What is an MP5 file? MP5 file format is a file with &amp;ldquo;.MP5&amp;rdquo; extension and refers to video file specifically designed for playback on Chinese MP5 portable media players. These MP5 files are essentially similar to standard .MP4 files as they use MPEG-4 or MPEG-H codecs for encoding. The primary distinction lies in optimization of MP5 files ensuring they are well-suited for playback on Chinese MP5 media players. Essentially, it is a specialized video format tailored for compatibility and optimal performance on these particular portable media devices.</description></item><item><title>CPI File Format - AVCHD Video Clip Information</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/cpi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/cpi/</guid><description>What is a CPI file? CPI stands for &amp;ldquo;Clip Information&amp;rdquo; and is used to store metadata about individual video clips within an AVCHD directory structure. These .CPI files contain information about video clips, such as start and end times of each clip, format of video (resolution, frame rate, etc.) and other details.
The .CPI files are usually stored in subfolder within AVCHD directory structure on camcorder or other recording device. These files are essential for organizing and playing back video clips, as they provide necessary information for software and devices to understand and display video content correctly.</description></item><item><title>M2V File Format - MPEG-2 Video</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m2v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m2v/</guid><description>What is an M2V file? The M2V file format is a file extension commonly associated with MPEG-2 Video. MPEG-2 is widely used video compression standard that is often used for DVDs, digital television broadcasting and other video distribution methods. The M2V format specifically contains only video data, which means it does not include audio or any other multimedia components. It is essentially raw or elementary stream of video.
M2V files can be used for various purposes, including authoring DVDs or creating video content for broadcast.</description></item><item><title>BDMV File Format - Blu-ray Disc Movie Information File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bdmv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bdmv/</guid><description>What is a BDMV file? A BDMV file is a type of file format used in Blu-ray Disc (BD) video discs. BDMV stands for &amp;ldquo;Blu-ray Disc Movie&amp;rdquo; and is a container format used to store high-definition video, audio, and other related content on Blu-ray discs. BDMV files are part of the Blu-ray Disc&amp;rsquo;s directory structure and contain various components of a Blu-ray movie, including video streams, audio tracks, subtitles, and menu structures.</description></item><item><title>PAR File Format - Dedicated Micros DVR Recording</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/par/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/par/</guid><description>What is a PAR file? The Dedicated Micros DVRs utilize a proprietary digital video format known as NetVu for recording and storing video footage. Additionally, the DVR systems utilize .par files, which are configuration files specific to Dedicated Micros DVRs. These files store settings, parameters, and configurations for the DVR system, such as camera settings, recording schedules, and network configurations.
The .par files can be downloaded to a computer along with the recorded video files using the NetVu software.</description></item><item><title>EXP File Format - DX Series Exported Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/exp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/exp/</guid><description>What is an EXP file? The DX Series Exported Video File with &amp;ldquo;.exp&amp;rdquo; extension is a proprietary file format associated with the DX Series digital video recorders (DVRs) manufactured by certain vendors, such as DX4100 or DX4800.
The &amp;ldquo;.exp&amp;rdquo; file format is used to store surveillance video footage recorded by these DVRs. It typically employs MPEG-4 compression to efficiently encode the video data while maintaining reasonable quality. In addition to the video stream, the file also contains metadata that provides important information about the recording, such as the date and time of the footage, camera number, video format, and recording mode.</description></item><item><title>NUT File Format - NUT Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/nut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/nut/</guid><description>What is a NUT file? The NUT (NUT Open Container Format) is a video container format similar to AVI, ASF, and MKV. It is designed to support various audio and video codecs, as well as subtitle information. The NUT format aims to provide a flexible container for multimedia content, allowing for the inclusion of different audio and video streams within a single file. It supports features such as multiple audio tracks, multiple video tracks, and subtitles.</description></item><item><title>MPEG File Format - MPEG Video</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpeg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpeg/</guid><description>What is an MPEG file? An MPEG file, also known as an MPEG video file, is a digital video file format that uses the Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) standards for video compression. MPEG is a widely used format for storing and transmitting video data.
The MPEG format employs lossy compression, which means that some information is discarded to reduce the file size. This compression technique allows for efficient storage and streaming of video content while maintaining reasonable video quality.</description></item><item><title>PDS File Format - PowerDirector Script File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/pds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/pds/</guid><description>What is a PDS file? A PowerDirector Script file (PDS) is a video project file or slideshow created with CyberLink PowerDirector, a comprehensive digital video-editing program. These files serve as containers for all the necessary information to produce a video project.
When you create a video project in PowerDirector, the PDS file is generated and acts as a central hub that references audio and video files used within the project. This includes details such as the locations of the media files, as well as settings for menus, effects, transitions, and other elements essential to the production of home videos.</description></item><item><title>PSV File Format - Pluralsight Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/psv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/psv/</guid><description>What is a PSV file? A &amp;ldquo;Pluralsight Video File&amp;rdquo; (PSV) is a proprietary video file format used by the Pluralsight online learning platform. Pluralsight provides video-based courses and tutorials on various topics related to software development, IT, and creative skills.
PSV files are specifically encoded and encrypted for use within the Pluralsight platform and are not intended for direct playback outside of the official Pluralsight application or website.
To access and watch Pluralsight courses, you generally need a valid Pluralsight subscription or access provided by your organization.</description></item><item><title>FLH File Format - FLIC Animation File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/flh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/flh/</guid><description>What is an FLH file? An FLH file is a video file format that follows the FLIC animation format, which is specifically designed for animation sequences, it makes use or utilize a compression algorithm that is optimized to efficiently store video and audio data e.g. in the context of Lego Rock Raiders, FLH files are utilized to hold both video and audio information. Most FLIC animations use the .FLC file extension.</description></item><item><title>LRV File Format - Low Resolution Video File by GoPro</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/lrv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/lrv/</guid><description>What is an LRV file? An LRV file, also known as Low-Resolution Video file, is a video file format that contains lower resolution version of video, commonly used in video editing workflows and video production to create low-resolution copies of high-resolution video files, are used to facilitate faster and smoother editing processes, especially when working with large video files or on systems with limited processing power.
LRV files are typically generated by camera systems, such as GoPro cameras, which create a lower-resolution version of original video during recording process, allowing users to quickly review footage, perform basic editing tasks and make selections without the need to handle larger, high-resolution files.</description></item><item><title>SCC File Format - ScreenFlow Screen Recording</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/scc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/scc/</guid><description>What is a SCC file? SCC files are video files created by ScreenFlow, a Mac OS X desktop screen recording application. It stores the captured video in a proprietary format and may also include audio captured from a computer microphone or from computer&amp;rsquo;s sound card.
SCC files are used by ScreenFlow as temporary files to store unrendered video data before it is exported to final video format, during editing process in ScreenFlow, when you make changes to your video, apply effects or perform other edits, the software saves project progress in SCC files which contain raw video data and editing instructions.</description></item><item><title>SUB File Format - MicroDVD Subtitle File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sub/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sub/</guid><description>What is a SUB file? A SUB file is a MicroDVD subtitle file format used to display subtitles in videos, typically have .sub file extension. These files contain timing information and text for each subtitle entry.
MicroDVD subtitle files use simple text-based format where each subtitle entry consists of several lines. The first line contains the subtitle&amp;rsquo;s timing information, including the start and end timestamps. The subsequent lines contain actual subtitle text.</description></item><item><title>OGV File Format - Ogg Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ogv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ogv/</guid><description>What is an OGV file? The OGV file format, also known as Ogg Video, is a container format designed to hold video and audio data. It is part of Ogg multimedia framework, which was developed by Xiph.Org Foundation. The OGV format is based on open-source Ogg container and typically uses Theora video codec and Vorbis audio codec.
The Theora video codec is a free and open video compression format, which provides reasonable video quality and is suitable for web streaming and other applications.</description></item><item><title>DV File Format - Digital Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dv/</guid><description>What is a DV file? A .dv file is a video file format commonly used in digital video recording. It stands for Digital Video and was introduced by Sony and Panasonic in 1990s. DV files are typically saved with .dv extension and contain compressed audio and video data.
DV files are commonly used in professional video production and editing workflows. They offer high-quality video and audio, making them suitable for broadcast and professional applications.</description></item><item><title>3GPP File Format - 3GPP Media File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3gpp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3gpp/</guid><description>What is a 3GPP file? A 3GPP file is a multimedia file format used for storing audio and video content on mobile devices particularly in 3rd Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) compliant devices. The 3GPP is a collaboration between various telecommunications standards organizations that develops and maintains standards for mobile communication systems.
The 3GPP file format is based on MPEG-4 Part 14 container format, commonly known as MP4. It supports storage of audio, video and other media types including text and images.</description></item><item><title>SAMI File Format - Subtitles And Metadata Interchange File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sami/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sami/</guid><description>What is a SAMI file? A file with the extension &amp;ldquo;.sami&amp;rdquo; typically refers to a Subtitles And Metadata Interchange (SAMI) file. SAMI is a captioning format used for displaying subtitles or closed captions in videos. It was originally developed by Microsoft for their Windows Media Player.
SAMI files contain timing information and text content for subtitles or closed captions, allowing them to be synchronized with a video playback. The format supports basic formatting options such as font style, color, and positioning of the subtitles on the screen.</description></item><item><title>AEP File - After Effects Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/aep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/aep/</guid><description>What is a AEP file? An AEP file is a project file created by Adobe After Effects when you save an After Effect project. It is the main file type used by After Effects to save all the settings and data related to the project such as video footage, still images, audio files, and any other effects. AEP file contains information about the composition, layers, keyframes, effects, and other elements that are part of the After Effects project.</description></item><item><title>STR File - YouTube Livestream Recording File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/str/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/str/</guid><description>What is an STR file? An STR file is a recording file created by YouTube for a livestream that was hosted by user&amp;rsquo;s streaming event. The file is saved automatically by Youtube at its backend once the live streaming is over. A live streaming video can be broadcasted to multiple channels so as audience can interact with publisher via comments. These SRT files are accessible using YouTube livestream API that provides access to the YouTube&amp;rsquo;s servers.</description></item><item><title>KINE File Format - KineMaster Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/kine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/kine/</guid><description>What is a KINE file? A KINE file is a project file used by the KineMaster video editing software. It contains all the information about the edited video, such as the timeline, media files used, effects applied, and audio tracks. The KINE file is used to save the progress of a video project and can be opened later to continue editing. The KineMaster software is widely used for creating and editing videos on mobile devices.</description></item><item><title>MSWMM File Format - Windows Movie Maker Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mswmm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mswmm/</guid><description>What is a MSWMM file? MSWMM (Movie Maker Project) is a file format used by the Windows Movie Maker application, which is a video editing software developed by Microsoft for Windows operating systems. MSWMM files are used to save movie projects created using Windows Movie Maker. Just like WLMP files, MSWMM files are not video files, but rather project files that contain information about the arrangement of video clips, photos, and audio tracks in a movie project, as well as the applied effects and transitions.</description></item><item><title>WLMP File Format - Windows Live Movie Maker Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/wlmp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/wlmp/</guid><description>What is a WLMP file? WLMP (Windows Live Movie Maker Project) is a proprietary file format used by the Windows Live Movie Maker application to save movie projects. It contains information about the arrangement of video clips, photos, and audio tracks in a project, as well as the effects and transitions applied to them. WLMP files cannot be played on media players, they need to be exported as a video file format such as WMV or MP4 to be played.</description></item><item><title>BIK - Bink Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bik/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/bik/</guid><description>What is a BIK file? The files with .bik extension are used for playing movie clips in video games on both PCs and gaming consoles. BIK file enables standard video to be compressed greatly while optimizing video quality for the target platform. BIK videos can be run on Windows Media Player (WMP) but you should have the Windows 7 Codec Pack installed on your computer. You may see a warning message while playing that WMP doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the file format but you can still play the video.</description></item><item><title>VEG File Format - MAGIX VEGAS Video Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/veg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/veg/</guid><description>What is a VEG file? The VEG file format is a proprietary project file format used by MAGIX VEGAS Pro, a professional video and audio editing software. VEG files store all of the elements and information required for a video project, including video and audio clips, transitions, effects, and timeline and sequence settings. The file format is optimized for use with MAGIX VEGAS Pro and is not compatible with other video editing software.</description></item><item><title>PIV File Format - Pivot Animator Animation</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/piv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/piv/</guid><description>What is a PIV file? A .piv file is a file format used by Pivot Animator, a software used for creating stick figure animations. The .piv file contains the animation data created by the user in the software. The format is specific to Pivot Animator and may not be supported by other animation software.
Relation with Pivot Animator Pivot Animator is a freeware application that allows users to create 2D stick figure animations and save them as .</description></item><item><title>PRPROJ File Format - Adobe Premiere Pro Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/prproj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/prproj/</guid><description>What is a PRPROJ file? The PRPROJ file format is the proprietary project file format used by Adobe Premiere Pro, a video editing software. PRPROJ files store all of the elements and information required for a video project, including video and audio clips, transitions, effects, and timeline and sequence settings. The file format is optimized for use with Premiere Pro and is not compatible with other video editing software. To open and edit a PRPROJ file, you must have Adobe Premiere Pro installed on your computer.</description></item><item><title>M4S File - What is an M4S file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m4s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m4s/</guid><description>What is an M4S file? An M4S file is a small segment of a video that is streamed over the internet using the MPEG-DASH streaming technique. It contains a video segment in the form of binary data. The receiving application (usually a web browser or media players) plays these segments in the order they are received. The first M4S segment is identified by the initialization data that it contains. In summary, M4S files are small individual media segments of a complete file.</description></item><item><title>IDX - High Efficiency Video Codec</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/idx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/idx/</guid><description>What is an IDX file? An IDX file is a subtitles index file that points to the list of metadata information for subtitles inside a .sub (VobSub Subtitles) file. It is created and used by the VobSub software application that lets users extract subtitles from DVDs and dump in a SUB file. IDX files contain timestamps and byte offsets used to point to every single subtitle. VobSub always creates an IDX file along with the corresponding SUB file.</description></item><item><title>IFO File - What is an IFO file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ifo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ifo/</guid><description>What is an IFO file? A .ifo file is an information file that is part of DVD specifications. The acronym IFO stands for information. IFO files provide information about the contents of the disc to the DVD player such as about the video files, menus, subtitles, and any special features that the DVD may have. This is the file that tells the DVD player what to display when the menu appears, the start of different chapters in the DVD, and the location and time of the video and audio files on the DVD.</description></item><item><title>EXO File Format - YouTube Video Chunk File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/exo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/exo/</guid><description>What is a EXO file? An EXO file is a video chunk file, downloaded by Android version of YouTube in the EXO format. When a user wants to download a video for offline playback, the video is divided into small chunks and each chunk is downloaded and saved to user&amp;rsquo;s device as an EXO file. These multiple EXO files are joined together for offline playback by YouTube app.
EXO File Format EXO files are saved in YouTube&amp;rsquo;s proprietary file format.</description></item><item><title>SEC File Format - Samsung Security Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/sec/</guid><description>What is an SEC file? A SEC file is a video file that is created with Samsung DVR surveillance system. Video is captured from surveillance cameras and stored to disc in SEC format. The recorded SEC video can be played back with Samsung&amp;rsquo;s video software that can manage video feed from multiple cameras.
SEC File Format - More Information SEC files contain h264/AVC stream inside using proprietary file format. The header of an SEC file starts with the model number of the SRD-1670D.</description></item><item><title>NSV File Format - NullSoft Streaming Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/nsv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/nsv/</guid><description>What is an NSV File? An NSV (NullSoft Stream Video) file is a streaming video file format used by NullSoft for streaming videos on the internet. The format was introduced and developed by NullSoft who was also the maker of Winamp media player. NSV supports MP3 and VP3 as its default audio and video formats. Lateral enhancements lets NSV to use lateral version of VP codecs for video such as VP6, VP8, and VP9.</description></item><item><title>MPV File Format - MPEG Elementary Stream Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpv/</guid><description>What is an MPV file? An MPV file is an MPEG elementary stream video file that consists of raw, uncompressed video data. The video contents inside an MPV file comprise of integrated MPEG-2 compression specifications. MPV files do not contain any audio data. The MPV file format is also used as input to video processing applications as the MPEG elementary stream use the MPEG-2 encoding standards primarily. MPV files can be opened and played with software applications that support MPEG-2 video file formats.</description></item><item><title>ARF - WebEx Advanced Recording File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/arf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/arf/</guid><description>What is an ARF file? An ARF (Advanced Recording File) file is a Network-Based Recording (NBR) file created from an online meeting conducted via WebEx. It contains higher quality video and audio, and is the widely used file format in WebEx meetings. Information contained in an ARF file includes video data, table of contents, attendee list, desktop recording, application sharing, and other meeting content. ARF files can not be directed edited, but start and end of playback can be truncated.</description></item><item><title>MPE File - MPEG Movie File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpe/</guid><description>What is an MPE file? An MPE file is a video file encoded and saved in the MPEG file format. It was extended with additional bit-rates to be supported as the next version of MPEG-2 compression. MPEG-2, however, is the most commonly used MPEG compression type. The .mpe extension was used initially as a short for the .mpeg file format.
References MPEG-1 - Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>VID File - Bethesda Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vid/</guid><description>What is a VID file? A VID file is an old file format used to store video data for games developed by Bethesda Softworks. The company has developed several games and used the VID file format for storing game recordings. In addition to video, these can also store audio data related to the game. Some of the famous games by Bethesda using VID file format include Skynet and The Elder Scrolls II: Daggerfall.</description></item><item><title>DAV File - CCTV DVR Video</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dav/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/dav/</guid><description>What is a DAV file? A DAV file is a compressed and encrypted video file created by DVR365 or Dahua Technology&amp;rsquo;s digital surveillance system. These systems connected to a closed-circuit television (CCTV) camera surveillance system. The footage videos received from these camera is store as DAV file in the system. Since DAV files are encrypted, only the CCTV system that created them or some specialized media players can open them. DAV files can also be converted to AVI file format.</description></item><item><title>VTT File Format - Web Video Text Tracks File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vtt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vtt/</guid><description>What is a VTT file? A VTT file is a text file that contains information for displaying timed text tracks (such as subtitles or captions) using the Web Video Text Tracks (WebVTT) format. The timed text tracks includes information such as subtitles or captions. The purpose of VTT file is to add text overlays to a . The format is somewhat similar to the SRT files. WebVTT based text files are encoded using UTF-8.</description></item><item><title>TS File Format - Video Transport Stream File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/ts/</guid><description>What is a TS file? A file with .ts extension is a video stream that stores the data on DVDs. It uses MPEG-2 (.mpeg) compression algorithm to achieve maximum efficiency and compatability across different media types such as internet streaming and broadcasting. TS file format was created so that it can be played on devices with poor internet connections, such as smart TV.
TS File Format - More Information Data in a TS file is similar to MP4 file, but it is divided into tiny chunks.</description></item><item><title>MTS File Format - AVCHD Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mts/</guid><description>What is an MTS file? An MTS file is an AVCHD (Advanced Video Coding High Definition) video file shoot by typical camcorders. This file format is a standard video format that is used by many AVCHD compatible camcorders such as Sony and Panasonic HD camcorders. MTS allows you to record high-definition (HD) videos to transform or share them on your computer. The MTS file is being applied widely by many professionals and home users as their video file format in this modern era.</description></item><item><title>MPG File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mpg/</guid><description>What is an MPG file format? The file with a .mpg extension belongs to the group of file extensions for MPEG-1 or MPEG-2 audio and video compression. MPEG-1 Part 2 video is not easily available, and this extension (MPG file format) typically points to a MPEG program stream which is defined in MPEG-1 and MPEG-2, or an MPEG transport stream which is defined in MPEG-2. Other extensions such as .m2ts also exist specifying the accurate container, in this case, MPEG-2 TS, but this has little pertinence to MPEG-1 media.</description></item><item><title>VP9 - TrueMotion Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp9/</guid><description>What is a VP9 file? Google has developed the VP9 codec as a royalty-free, open-source video coding standard as the successor to VP8. It was originally designed to compress the ultra HD content on YouTube because it expands and enhances the coding efficiency of its predecessor. If we talk about the original VPX codecs, they came from On2 Technologies, which was assimilated by Google in 2010. Google later open-sourced the codec.</description></item><item><title>VP8 - TrueMotion Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp8/</guid><description>What is a VP8 file? VP8 is announced by Google as one of the best video formats having the best picture quality data rate and encoding speed. The best advantage of VP8 is that its a royalty-free substitute of H.264. It is a specific format for encoding and decoding high-quality video as a file or a bitstream. It&amp;rsquo;s free because Google has released all the VP8 patents under a royalty-free public license.</description></item><item><title>H265 - High Efficiency Video Codec</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/h265/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/h265/</guid><description>What is an H265 file? H.265 is also known as HEVC (High-Efficiency Video Coding) is a successor to H.264. It is the newest video compression standard that is said to double the data compression proportion as compare to H.264 with the same video quality. Video encoded with HEVC will uphold the high visual quality but at a smaller file size. It was developed in response to the increasing need for higher compression of moving pictures for different applications such as:</description></item><item><title>H264 - Advanced Video Coding</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/h264/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/h264/</guid><description>What is an H264 file? The file extension H264 is used when mentioning an H.264 encoded video file or as digital video compression. As a consequence of the high popularity of this video compression format, it can be used for video recording and also compresses and distributes the video. MPEG-2 video is compressed half as much by H.264 to deliver the same high-quality video. Now you can enjoy HD video without compromising speed or performance.</description></item><item><title>ASF - Advanced Systems File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/asf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/asf/</guid><description>What is an ASF file? A file with .asf extension is a multimedia file format for storing and playing digital media streams over the network. It is a container file format that can have both video and audio content for streaming online. You will rarely find ASF files, and more probably come across the Windows Media Audio (WMA) and Windows Media Video (WMV) files that both specify ASF files having content encoded with respective codecs.</description></item><item><title>MJPEG - Motion JPEG File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mjpeg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mjpeg/</guid><description>What is an MJPEG file? A file with .mjpeg (Motion JPEG) extension is a video file that is created by compressing an individual video frame as a JPEG image. It is different from the standard MPEG-1 and MPEG-2 file formats where the compression is interframes and is decided based on the prediction of contents in subsequent frames. MJPEG is supported by a wide range of applications that include web browsers, media players, digital cameras, webcams, streaming servers.</description></item><item><title>PZ File Format - Panzoid Video Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/pz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/pz/</guid><description>What is a PZ file? A PZ file is a project file created with the online video clips making application Panzoid. It contains information about the video project and its contents such as scene, objects, effects, lighting, FX, audio and music. Panzoid allows you to create videos online using their ClipMaker video editing facility.
PZ files can be opened with Panzoid ClipMaker and Panzoid Backgrounder.
PZ File Format PZ files are saved as binary files to disc.</description></item><item><title>QT File Format - Quick Movie File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/qt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/qt/</guid><description>What is a QT file? A file with a .qt extension is a multimedia container file that is used by the QuickTime framework to store multimedia file contents. Developed by Apple Inc. the QuickTime File Format (QTFF) is a multimedia container file that contains audio, video, or text for playback later on. It is the format of choice for the exchange of digital media between devices, applications, and operating systems. QT files are also saved in MOV format that was also developed by Apple Inc.</description></item><item><title>VP6 - TrueMotion Video File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vp6/</guid><description>What is a VP6 file? VP6 is a lossy compression video format that was introduced by On2 technologies in May 2003. It is a part of series of video codecs developed by TrueMotion including V3, V4 and V5. The format was used shortly in broadcasting field such as with BBC reports and QuickLink software. VP6 was succeeded by VP7 Codec in January 2005 with better compression compatibility.
VP6 File Format Complete specifications for V6 files are not available publicly.</description></item><item><title>3G2 File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3g2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3g2/</guid><description>What is a 3G2 file? 3G2(3GPP2 file format) is a multimedia container format similar to the 3GP file format. 3G2 is defined by the Third Generation Partnership Project 2 (3GPP2) for 3G CDMA2000 multimedia services. 3G2 files are stored with the .3g2 extension. As compared to 3GP files, 3G2 files consume less space and bandwidth.
Technical Details The 3G2 format is based on the ISO base media file format defined in ISO/IEC 14496-12 – MPEG-4 Part 12.</description></item><item><title>3GP File – What Is It and How to Play It?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3gp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/3gp/</guid><description>What is a 3GP file? 3GP(3GPP File Format) is a multimedia container format used on 3G mobile phones. It can also be played on some 2G and 4G phones. 3GP is defined by the Third Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) for 3G UMTS (Universal Mobile Telecommunications System) multimedia services. 3GP files are stored with the .3gp extension. 3GP file format was designed for GSM-based (Global System for Mobile Communications) phones and is the standard format for media files sent via MMS (Multimedia Messaging Service).</description></item><item><title>AVI File Format - An Audio Video Interleave File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/avi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/avi/</guid><description>What is an AVI file? The AVI file format is an Audio Video multimedia container file format that was introduced by Microsoft. It holds the audio and video data created and compressed using several codecs (Coders/Decoders) such as XVid and DivX. Since different codecs can be used to encode the AVI contents, the retrieving applications i.e. AVI players, should be able to open these only if they have the required codecs installed with which the AVI contents were created.</description></item><item><title>F4V File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/f4v/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/f4v/</guid><description>What is an F4V file? F4V (Flash MP4 Video File) is a video file saved with the .f4v extension. It is based on the ISO base media file format (MPEG-4 Part 12). It is very similar to MP4 which is why it is also referred to as the Flash MP4 informally. FLV had limitations when streaming H.264/ACC contents which resulted in Adobe Systems creating the new F4V format. Flash Player can play F4V files since the release of Flash Player 9 Update 3.</description></item><item><title>FLV File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/flv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/flv/</guid><description>What is an FLV file? FLV (Flash Video) is a container file format with the .flv extension. FLV is used to deliver audio/video content over the internet by using the Adobe Flash Player or Adobe Air. The data in FLV files are encoded in the same way as SWF files. The direct support was added to Flash Player 7 in 2003. Adobe systems created F4V in 2007 due to the restrictions of FLV.</description></item><item><title>M4V</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m4v/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m4v/</guid><description>What is an M4V file? M4V file format, developed by Apple, is a video container optionally protected with Digital Rights Management (DRM) copy protection to protect privacy or copy. Videos and audio tracks are wrapped around by container files to indexing and organizing playback streams. In addition, containers also provide the feature of chapters similar to those on DVDs. Apple uses M4V to encode videos in its iTunes Store. It protects unauthorized reproduction through Apple’s FairPlay copy protection by allowing M4V files to be played on only authorized computers having the accounts used to purchase the video.</description></item><item><title>MKV File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mkv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mkv/</guid><description>What is an MKV File? MKV (Matroska Video) is a multimedia container similar to MOV and AVI format but it supports more than one audio and subtitle track in the same file. An MKV file is the Matroska multimedia container format used for video. MKV is based on Extensible Binary Meta Language and it supports several video and audio compression formats. The major difference between MKV and other video formats is that MKV is a container and not a codec.</description></item><item><title>MOV File - Apple QuickTime Movie File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mov/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mov/</guid><description>What is a MOV file? A MOV file is a video file type, developed by Apple Inc., that contains one or more tracks. Each track stores a movie, audio, movie clips, and subtitles. It is a multimedia container that can store different type of media elements. MOV video format is compatible with both Windows and Macintosh systems. It uses MPEG-4 coded for compression and tracks are maintained in objects called atoms which are placed in a hierarchical data structure.</description></item><item><title>MP4 File Format - What Is It and How to Open One?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mp4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mp4/</guid><description>What is an MP4 file? MP4(short for MPEG-4 Part 14) is a file format based on ISO/IEC 14496-12:2004 that is based on QuickTime File Format but formally specifies support for Initial Object Descriptors (IOD) and other MPEG features. It is mostly used to store video and audio but can also be used to store subtitles and still images. MP4 files are stored with the .mp4 extension. MP4 is an international audio-visual coding standard.</description></item><item><title>MXF - Material Exchange Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mxf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mxf/</guid><description>What is an MXF File? A file with .mxf extension is a multimedia container format that contains digital video and audio media along with metadata information about the file. It follows the SMPTE (Society of Motion Picture and Television Engineers) standard that is a global association of professionals from engineering, technology, and executives working in the media and entertainment industry. MXF files can be converted to other file formats such as AVI or MOV.</description></item><item><title>RM File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rm/</guid><description>What is an RM file? RealMedia is a proprietary multimedia container format developed by RealNetworks that uses the .rm extension. It is used with the combination of RealAudio (RA) and RealVideo(RV) for streaming over the internet. These streams are of constant bitrate. For variable bitrate, RealNetworks developed the RealMedia Variable Bitrate (RMVB) format. RealMedia is suitable for streaming content over the internet and can be used for streaming live television for example.</description></item><item><title>RMVB File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rmvb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rmvb/</guid><description>What is a RMVB file? RealMedia Variable Bitrate (RMVB) is an extension of the RealMedia (RM) container format. The RMVB files use the .rmvb file extension. RealMedia (RM) holds streaming media encoded at constant bitrate whereas RealMedia Variable Bitrate (RMVB) has variable bitrate. RMVB is typically used for the files stored locally.
Technical Details The compression used in RealMedia is similar to MPEG-4 Part 10. In RMVB files, the amount of output data per time segment varies.</description></item><item><title>RV File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/rv/</guid><description>What is an RV file? RealVideo (RV) is a proprietary video format developed by RealNetworks and released in 1997. The RealVideo files are stored with the .rv extension. RealVideo is supported on multiple platforms like Windows, Mac, Linux, etc.
Usually, RealVideo is paired with RealAudio (RA) in the RealMedia (RM) container. It is suitable for streaming content over the internet and can be used for streaming live television for example.</description></item><item><title>What Is an SRT File, How It Works and a Sample SRT File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/srt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/srt/</guid><description>What is an SRT file? SRT (SubRip file format) is a simple subtitle file saved in the SubRip file format with the .srt extension. It contains a sequential number of subtitles, start and end timestamps, and subtitle text. SRT files make it possible to add subtitles to video content after it is produced.
SRT file Structure Each subtitle has four parts in the SRT file.
A numeric counter indicating the number or position of the subtitle.</description></item><item><title>VOB File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vob/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/vob/</guid><description>What is a VOB file? VOB files are stored typically in the VIDEO_TS directory on a DVD with a .vob extension. VOB files contain video and audio data as well as other data like menus and subtitles. VOB is based on MPEG-2 program stream format but it has additional limitations and specifications in private streams. VOB files are a strict subset of MPEG program streams so all VOB files are MPEG program streams but all MPEG program streams are not VOB compliant.</description></item><item><title>WEBM - WebM Video File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/webm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/webm/</guid><description>What is a WEBM file? A file with a .webm extension is a video file based on the open, royalty-free WebM file format. It has been designed for sharing video on the web and defines the file container structure including video and audio formats. WebM is 100% free, implementing high-quality based on open technologies such as HTML, HTTP, and TCP/IP which are open to anyone for implementation. WebM has been specifically designed for serving video on the web which makes it optimized for streaming with a low computational footprint.</description></item><item><title>WMV File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/wmv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/wmv/</guid><description>What is a WMV file? The Advanced Systems Format (ASF) is a digital multimedia container designed primarily for storing and transmitting media streams. Microsoft Windows Media Video (WMV) is the compressed video format and Microsoft Windows Media Audio (WMA) is the compressed audio format along with additional metadata in the ASF container developed by Microsoft. Once the WMV or WMA files are encoded with Windows Media Video and Windows Media Audio codecs then they are represented with .</description></item><item><title>Xvid File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/xvid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/xvid/</guid><description>What is an Xvid file? Xvid is not a video format like MP4 but rather is a video codec library following the MPEG-4 Part 2 Advanced Simple Profile (ASP) coding standard. Xvid is a competitor of the proprietary DivX codec developed by DivX Inc. In contrast to DivX, Xvid is free software distributed under the GNU General Public License. Because of this, Xvid is used on all platforms for which the source code can be compiled.</description></item><item><title>AMV File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/amv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/amv/</guid><description>What is an AMV file? The AMV acronym as Actions Media Video is classified as a video file format produced for Chinese portable MP4 media players and S1 MP3 players with video playback. The AMV video basically has two different formats: The earlier one for the Actions chip and the latest one for ALi’s M5661 chip; the format for ALi one was ALIAVI. The video format is a variant of Motion JPEG, with fixed rather than variable division tables.</description></item><item><title>AVCHD File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/avchd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/avchd/</guid><description>What is an AVCHD file? An AVCHD file is a recording file format introduced for saving high-definition(HD) videos to DVDs, hard disk drives, and memory cards. AVCHD videos, recorded onto DVD and Blu-ray, can be played easily on most Blu-ray Disc players. Also, the AVCHD stuff can also be recorded on SD cards and played by many Blu-ray Disc players, television sets, and media consoles. The ffdshow tryouts and Libavcodec are the open-source codecs that can decode the AVCHD files.</description></item><item><title>M2TS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m2ts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/m2ts/</guid><description>What is M2TS file? An M2TS file contain the high definition video on Blu-ray Disc and AVCHD. This file format is based on the MPEG-2 transport stream container and used for multiplexing audio, video and other streams. M2TS files can be played on the devices supporting playback of AVCHD, such as, Sony PlayStation 3s, Sony Bravia TVs, Western Digital WDTVs, Xtreamer media player, Amkette FlashTV HD Media Player and Panasonic Viera TVs supporting AVCHD.</description></item><item><title>MK3D File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mk3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mk3d/</guid><description>What is an MK3D file? The MK3D files belong to the Matroska video formats family. These files are actually stereoscopic 3d videos created using Matroska 3D format. The MKV file Container uses a StereoMode field&amp;rsquo;s value to define the type of stereoscopic 3D video stuff. A StereoMode value is also available to display the old stereo 3D videos by separating cyan and red colors (AnaGlyph)
Technical Details The 3D videos can be compressed in the following two ways:</description></item><item><title>MKS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/video/mks/</guid><description>What is an MKS file? The MKS files are generally known as Matroska files containing subtitles only. Although the Matroska is a general file container, it avoids keeping the information of specific formats. Since subtitles are being used in some of the audio or video containers, Matroska is paying attention to store some common subtitle formats. It helps Matroska to be consistent with the growth rate. You need to follow the points as given below to store the subtitles in Matroska:</description></item></channel></rss>