<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Web File Formats and APIs that can open and create Web files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Web File Formats and APIs that can open and create Web files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CCBJS - CopperCube JavaScript File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ccbjs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ccbjs/</guid><description>What is a CCBJS file? A CCBJS file is a Javascript file created by the 3D app, game, and website editor, CopperCube. It contains the JavaScript code that is generated as part of the .html file created from the .ccb file. CopperCube provides a user-friendly scripting interface to develop gameplay logic and interactions without writing any code. Other file formats supported by CopperCube include .ccscene, .ccmodel, .ccmaterial, .cctex, .ccjs, .ccp, and .</description></item><item><title>CPG File - Concept Server Page File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cpg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cpg/</guid><description>What is a CPG file? A CPG file is a project file created by Web page editor software, Cool Page. The software has become obsolete many years ago and is no more used. CPG file contained details about the objects used in the web page and the properties of these objects. CPG project files could be opened in the Cool Page software and after finalizing, the web page could be exported as HTML web page.</description></item><item><title>CPHD File - CloudChan Pre-processed Hypertext Document Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cphd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cphd/</guid><description>What is a CPHD file? A CPHD file is a Hypertext document used by the CloudChan pre-processor engine. It contains HTML and scripts to create dynamic web pages and documents. Scripts inside a CPHD file resembles the syntax used by Java. The CPHD web page returns an HTML document when executed on a CloudChan processes. CPHD format can work with any XML document.
CPHD File Format CPHD files are stored to disc as plain text files.</description></item><item><title>BROWSER File - ASP.NET Browser Definition File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/browser/</guid><description>What is a BROWSER file? A file with .browser extension is used by ASP.NET web applications to determine the capability and configuration of web browsers. It contains information about the browser&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, limitations, and characteristics. These characteristics help the ASP.NET framework to recognize the requesting browser and present the webpage to users accordingly.
BROWSER File Format BROWSER definition files are used by the ASP.NET application to determine the capabilities of the browser.</description></item><item><title>AXD File - ASP.NET Web Handler File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/axd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/axd/</guid><description>What is an AXD file? An AXD file is a web settings file that is used for handling and retrievign embedded resource requests in ASP.NET. It comprises of instructions for retreiving embedded resources such as images, JavaScript (.JS) files, and .CSS files. AXD files are used for injecting resources into client-side pages. This allows client pages to access these resources on server in a standard way.
AXD File Format AXD files are stored as binary files on server side.</description></item><item><title>COMPRESSED File - WordCompress Compacted Webpage File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/compressed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/compressed/</guid><description>What is a COMPRESSED file? A COMPRESSED file is a small size Wordpress compressed webpage generated with the plug-in, WordCompress. It contians a single line of code for representing the webpage that is generated by compressing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code by the plugin. These converted COMPRESSED files are small in size that helps faster loading and transfer over the internet.
COMPRESSED File Format - More Information COMPRESSED files are saved as text files that can be opened with any text editor sucha s Microsoft Notepad, Notepad++, and Apple TextEdit.</description></item><item><title>OPDOWNLOAD File Format - Opera Partially Downloaded File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/opdownload/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/opdownload/</guid><description>What is an OPDOWNLOAD file? An Opera Partially Downloaded File is a file that has been partially downloaded using the Opera web browser. Opera saves files as they download, and if a download is interrupted or paused, the partially downloaded file is saved with an &amp;ldquo;opdownload&amp;rdquo; extension. When a download is complete, the &amp;ldquo;.opdownload&amp;rdquo; extension is removed, and the file becomes usable. However, if the download is interrupted or incomplete, the &amp;ldquo;.</description></item><item><title>XPD File - XML Pipeline Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xpd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xpd/</guid><description>What is an XPD file? An XPD file is a webpage file created from an XML document. More often, this is generated through an XSLT transformation. The XPD file format specifications are available on W3 that define a way to increase interoperability of multi-process XML applications. The XML Pipeline Language defines the processing relationships between XML resources.
References XML Pipeline</description></item><item><title>SEAM File - Seam Framework Java Servlet File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/seam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/seam/</guid><description>What is an SEAM file? A SEAM file is a configuration file used by the JBOS Seam framework. It contains metadata/reference to a server-side servlet that processes requests to the web application. It also contains metadata about Seam components such as the names of classes and methods that implement the components. You can use SEAM files in conjunction with JavaServer Faces (JSF) framework for building dynamic and interactive web applications. SEAM files are usually stored in the WEB-INF directory of a Seam application.</description></item><item><title>OAM File - Adobe Edge Animate Widget File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/oam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/oam/</guid><description>What is an OAM file? A .oam file a an animated widget file exported from Adobe Edge Animate Widget. Animations exported as OAM widget file format can be inserted into other Adobe applications such as InDesign Documents (INDD file, Dreamweaver, and Muse. OAM files are like deployment packages that can be readily inserted into other Adobe&amp;rsquo;s projects to make use of them. OAM files contain information about the animation&amp;rsquo;s assets, behaviors, and actionscript code.</description></item><item><title>SITE File - GoLive Website Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/site/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/site/</guid><description>What is an SITE file? A SITE file is a project file used by website design software Adobe GoLive. It stores website project information such as files, folders, images, custom style sheets, and scripts. It also contains the website structure and links used in the site web pages. As it is a project file, it contains references to project files but do not contain the actual files itself.
Adobe GoLive has been discontinued and is no longer supported.</description></item><item><title>VDISCO File - DISCO Dynamic Discovery Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/vdisco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/vdisco/</guid><description>What is a VDISCO file? A VDISCO file is a discovery file used by Microsoft Visual Studio in its Web Services. It provides information about the available Web Services such as their URLs, namespaces, and methods. VDISCO file is similar to the DISCO file format but is generated at runtime. It is stored in the Web service application and is used by the Visual Studio to dynamically discover and use Web Services in a project.</description></item><item><title>XHTM</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xhtm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xhtm/</guid><description>What is an XHTM file? An file with .xhtm extension is a webpage file that is written in XHTML. It uses XML 1.0 as its standard implementation and is considered a reformulation of HTML 4. Like XHTML, an XHTM file contains standard HTML tags that follow a more stern XML guidelines. XHTM files are used for publishing website content and commonly use XHTML extension.
You can use web browsers such as Google Chrome, Apple Safari, and Mozilla Firefox to open XHTM files.</description></item><item><title>SVR File - Compressed Virtual World File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/svr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/svr/</guid><description>What is an SVR file? An SVR file is a 3D file format used by SuperScape to create 3D interactive worlds. These three-dimensional interactive worlds can be viewed through web browsers with the SVR plugin. SVR files are similar to VRT file format but are compressed that results in smaller file size. Thus, SVR files are loaded faster and can also be shared over internet.
SVR File Format - More Information SVR files are saved to disc in binary file formats.</description></item><item><title>HDM File - Handheld Device Markup Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hdm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hdm/</guid><description>What is an HDM file? An HDM file is a markup language webpage file that is created in the Handheld Device Markup Language (HDML). It contains markup tags similar to HTML language, but is designed for handheld electronic devices such as smartphones and PDAs. The HDML file format specifications were submitted to W3C for standardization but couldn&amp;rsquo;t become a standard. HDM is based on the HDML file format specifications available at W3 website.</description></item><item><title>Freeway File - Freeway Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/freeway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/freeway/</guid><description>What is an FREEWAY file? A FREEWAY file is a settings information file created and used by the Freeway Pro software, a WYSIWYG app on MacOS for creating websites. It contains information about a website such as site&amp;rsquo;s appearance and layout including font, background appearance, margins, and links to resources that are loaded at runtime. This information is used for creating website that has the layout and arrangement of UI elements as per the information in the file.</description></item><item><title>EPIBRW File - Adobe Edge Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/epibrw/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/epibrw/</guid><description>What is an EPIBRW file? An EPIBRW file is a generic file hosted on Microsoft IIS-based web server. The purpose of this file is not specific to any specific operations or any kind of data storage, but is general. It is most often used by .pdf files but can be utilized by several other file types as well.
When an EPIBRW file is double clicked, it may open in browser displaying the contents.</description></item><item><title>ESPROJ File - Espresso Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/esproj/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/esproj/</guid><description>What is an ESPROJ file? An ESPROJ file is a project file created by webpages creating software, Espresso. It is available on Mac OS and contains a list of the related files that are part of the website project. When you open the ESPROJ file in Espresso, it opens all the related files in the editor for editing or updating the source code. ESPROJ file also contains server publishing settings and other related user preferences.</description></item><item><title>EWP File - Ewisoft Website Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ewp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ewp/</guid><description>What is an EWP file? An EWP file is a project file created with EWISoft Website Builder software. It is linked to a binary database file that contains all the information for the project. EWP file is commonly used for saving web development progress. It is a template-driven web design software that lets users create websites from website templates.
EWP File Format - More Information EWP files are project files that don&amp;rsquo;t need to be compiled or hosted on any server.</description></item><item><title>FCGI File - FastCGI File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fcgi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fcgi/</guid><description>What is an FCGI file? An FCGI file is a source code file that contains source code written for FastCGI (FCGI). It can be written in several different programming languages and contains the extension of CGI standard used for more robust handling of Web server requests. The most commonly support languages for FCGI includes Perl that provides support for both Perl code and the strong external interface of FastCGI API.</description></item><item><title>DOWNLOAD File - Partially Downloaded File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/download/</guid><description>What is a DOWNLOAD file? A DOWNLOAD file is a partially downloaded file from internet that is still in the process of getting downloaded. When you download a file from internet using Apple Safari browser, it may take some time for the download to complete. This partially downloaded file is saved to Downloads folder. If the download is interrupted for any reason, the file can be double-clicked for trying to resume it.</description></item><item><title>DOCMHTML File Format - Microsoft Word MIME HTML Document File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/docmhtml/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/docmhtml/</guid><description>What is a DOCMHTML file? A DOCMHTML file is an old variant of web archive saved by the earlier versions of Microsoft Word. It is no more supported by the latest version of Microsoft Word. A DOCMHTML file contains HTML representation of the original .doc word document. It can be opened in Microsoft Word as well as in web browser. When a DOCMHTML is published, it can be hosted on a web server that is accessible to users via web request.</description></item><item><title>DOTHTML File - Microsoft Word HTML Document Template File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dothtml/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dothtml/</guid><description>What is a DOTHTML file? A DOTHTML file is a Microsoft Word template document saved in HTML version. It can be opened in web browser and contents are displayed as any other web page. DOTHTML files are generated from Microsoft Word .DOT files that contain pre-formatted settings for generating these files. When a DOT file is converted to DOCHTML, all these settings are retained and the converted DOTHTML file is displayed with similar formatting as the original DOT file.</description></item><item><title>DISCO File - DISCO Discovery Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/disco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/disco/</guid><description>What is a DISCO file? A DISCO file is a Microsoft Discovery file format that is used for publishing and discovering Web Services. It is stored in XML file format and lets the Web Services Discovery tools to locate or discover one or more related documents for describing the available XML services. DISCO file stores information such as discovery documents, XSD schemas, and service descriptions. XML Web services use this information to get to the available XML web services at a given URL.</description></item><item><title>DISCOMAP File - DISCO Discovery Output File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/discomap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/discomap/</guid><description>What is a DISCOMAP file? A DISCOMAP file is an output file that is created by the Microsoft Web Services Discovery Tool, Disco.exe. It contains the results that are ASP.NET Web Services discovered at at specific URL. Common examples of such discovered services include locations of a .DISCO or .WSDL files. When the Microsoft Web Discovery tool runs, it searches for discovering information based on the XML content found in the DISCO file.</description></item><item><title>DO File - Java Servlet File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/do/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/do/</guid><description>What is a DO file? A DO file is a Java servlet file that is used by web servers for delivering web-based Java applications. It is commonly associated with the Struts controller of applications that processes files. This allows DO files generate dynamic webpages that contain visual appearance as well as data retrieved from databases. Java servlets sends these dynamically generated web application pages to requesting browser for display.
DO File Format DO files are saved as web files that are opened in browser when a user sends a request to the server.</description></item><item><title>PEM File - Privacy Enhanced Mail Certificate File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pem/</guid><description>What is a PEM file? A PEM file is a security certificate file that is used to establish a secure communication channel between a web server and a browser. It is Base64-encoded and may contain a private key, server certificate, and/or a combination of other certificates. PEM files are similar to .der certificate files in terms of usage but is stored as Base64-encoded text rather than binary data. Other similar certificate file formats include .</description></item><item><title>DER File - DER Certificate File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/der/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/der/</guid><description>What is a DER file? A DER file is a digital certificate file that is created and stored in binary format. It is a binary encoding for the X.509 certificates and private keys. In contrast to PEM files (CRT, CER), DER files do not contain human-readable plain text statements such as &amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;BEGIN CERTIFICATE&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;. They are mostly used in context of Java.
DER File Format - More Information DER Files are stored to disc in binary file format that is not human-readable.</description></item><item><title>CSR File - Certificate Signing Request File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/csr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/csr/</guid><description>What is a CSR file? A CSR file is a Certificate Signing Request file that is used to request for SSL/TLS certificate. When you need to have your SSL/TLS certificate, you generate the CSR on the same server where it will finally be installed. This CSR file is shared with the Certificate Authority (CA) for creation of the certificate. It contains information such as common name, organization, country, and, more importantly, the public key that is integrated within your certificate file and is signed with the corresponding private key.</description></item><item><title>CRL File - Certificate Revocation List</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crl/</guid><description>What is a CRL file? A CRL (Certificate Revocation List) file is a blacklist of X.509 digital certificates that a certificate authority (CA) revokes prior to their assigned revocation date. It contains information about the issue and the revocation date that lets the security administrators to block affected digital certificates. CRL doesn&amp;rsquo;t include expired certificates as its main purpose is to notify about the untrusted and invalid certificates.
Applications that can open CRL files include OpenSSL, Microsoft IIS Server, and Citrix NetScaler.</description></item><item><title>CMS File - Content Management System File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cms/</guid><description>What is a CMS file? A CMS file is a web page published by content management systems (CMS) that is used to generate documents for publishing over the internet. It is generated at run time and published to the web server for getting LIVE on the internet. A website generated with a CMS is most oftenly based on a theme based template that is used to create the CMS files. Since the same template is used for generating all the pages, all the pages are same in look and feel.</description></item><item><title>CON File - Concept Application Source File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/con/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/con/</guid><description>What is a CON file? A CON file is a source code file for application developed for the Concept Application Server. It is used for writing applications for exchange of data between the server and the user. CON files hosted on the server are accessible with a Web browser provided the Concept Client is installed on user end. Concept Application server is a webserver with small scale programming language that may have an SQL subset database engine (TinDB).</description></item><item><title>CSP File - Concept Server Page File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/csp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/csp/</guid><description>What is a CSP file? A CSP file is a dynamic web page file that contains content written to be executed on RadGs Concept Application Server. It is compiled and executed on server side, after which it is served to requesting user&amp;rsquo;s browser via HTTP protocol. Unlike CON file format, CSP files do not require the Concept client to be installed at user for viewing these files. You can view CSP files similar to any other server side pages such as PHP and ASP.</description></item><item><title>CHA File - IRC Chat Configuration File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cha/</guid><description>What is a CHA file? A CHA file is a user settings file created by the IRC clients such as mIRC. It contains parameters such as the server, port, channel name and, optionally, a password for opening an IRC channel. IRC clients are used to communicate with others on the IRC networks around the world. These are used for one-to-one private discussions or in multi-group conferences. When a CHA file is clicked, the IRC client automatically opens with the details mentioned in the file.</description></item><item><title>CHAT File - IRC Chat Configuration File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/chat/</guid><description>What is a CHAT file? A CHAT file is a configuration file used by the IRC (Internet Relay Chat) for connecting to an IRC channel. It contains connection parameters such as server, port, name of the IRC channel, and optionally a password for opening an IRC channel. The settings are used by the client to connect to other channels. The chats and discussions on IRC are one-to-one and are private.</description></item><item><title>BOK File - ProStores Dynamic Webpage File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bok/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bok/</guid><description>What is a BOK file? A BOK file is a webpage file created by ProStores, once a popular web-based e-commerce platform that was later acquired by eBay. Like other webpages, BOK file contains dynamic content generated from the data available in the ProStores database. The BOK webpage is then hosted to the ProStores platform for listing products that are available to users for purchase. BOK page owners used to generate their store pages on ProStores and list the products for customers.</description></item><item><title>BR File - Brotli Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/br/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/br/</guid><description>What is a BR file? A BR file is a compressed web file generated by applying the open source data compression algorithm, Brotli. It is used to store webpage assets such as stylesheets (CSS), images (SVG), XML, and scripting files (JS). Modern day websites, such as Chrome and Firefox, use BR files to reduce the page loading time, resulting in better user experience.
BR File Format BR files are compressed web files that are generated using the Brotli compression algorithm.</description></item><item><title>BWP File - Brotli Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bwp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bwp/</guid><description>What is a BWP file? A BWP file is a web page script file created in the programming language, BuRg3r. It is specific to BuRg3r and may contain HTML code with sections of BuRg3r source delimited by tags. BuRg3r is a general purpose programming language that is also a game engine that was developed by Fluffy Smoke Entertainment.
References BuRg3r - Github</description></item><item><title>AWM File - AllWebMenus Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/awm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/awm/</guid><description>What is an AWM file? An AWM file is a project file created by the Web menu builder program, AllWebMenus. It contains project related data for creating HTML based drop-down menus. An AWM file is compiled into a finalized web package that integrates into the websites to display the menus. It contains all the project related data such as appearance settings, menu entries, style (vertical or horizontal), colors, and other related information.</description></item><item><title>APPCACHE File - HTML5 Cache Manifest File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/appcache/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/appcache/</guid><description>What is an APPCACHE file? An APPCACHE file is a text file that contains the list of resources to be cached by browsers for offline access to the web applications. This is useful when there is no internet connection. In such situation, the browser uses the offline cache resources to provide access to the web contents. APPCACHE file contains web resources such as images (for example PNG, WEBP, etc.), stylesheets ([CSS])(/web/css/), and script files (such as Javascript JS files).</description></item><item><title>ASR File Format - Active Page File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asr/</guid><description>What is an ASR file? An ASR file is an ActionScript file created with Adobe Dreamweaver that is loaded and run on server-side. It is also often created by Contribute HTML editor that has now been discontinued long ago. ASR file contains script written in the standard scripting language and has the capability to access built-in server-based features in ColdFusion.
ASR File Format ASR file contains script that is developed in standard scripting language.</description></item><item><title>ATOM File - Atom Syndication Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/atom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/atom/</guid><description>What is an ATOM file? An ATOM file is a Syndication format for the structure of Atom feed and entry documents. Similar to .RSS files, ATOM file format is an XML-based syndication format that is a standard for publishing content. An ATOM file is used for web feeds that allow software programs to check for updates that are published on the website. It contains entries that can be of different types such as headlines, full-text articles, excerpts or links to content on a website</description></item><item><title>ATT File - Web Form Post Data File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/att/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/att/</guid><description>What is an ATT file? An ATT file is an intermediate file generated by Web forms when a user submits data using the form in a web browser. When the data is submitted using the web form, the data is stored in the ATT file and is also emailed to the designated user. The ATT files are received as an attachment to the emails in cases where the encoding type is incorrect.</description></item><item><title>A4P File Format - What is an A4P file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/a4p/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/a4p/</guid><description>What is an A4P file? An A4P file is a project file created by A4Desk Pro software program that is used for creating Flash Websites. It is created with the templates included with the A4Desk Pro and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one to have in-depth knowledge of Flash. A4P files created with templates can include website content in the form text and Flash animations. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Flash, it was used to create animations that could be exported to SWF as well as GIF file formats for inclusion in websites.</description></item><item><title>JNLP File Format - What is a JNP file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jnlp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jnlp/</guid><description>What is a JNLP file? A JNLP file is a Java Web Start (JWS) file that contains XML information for launching a Java program over the network. It is saved in Java Network Launching Protocol (JNLP) format. It is used by the Java Web Start (JWS) technology that is an application deployment technology to download and run an application. A JNLP file contains the remote address of the server from which the program is downloaded and launched on local machine.</description></item><item><title>PRO File Format - What is a PRO file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pro/</guid><description>What is a PRO file? A PRO file is a mockup of a website or mobile application created by Adobe Proto, a defunct Adobe Touch app. It includes one or more UI layouts for a webpage or mobile app, each of which may include interactive elements. CSS, WebKit, and jQuery technologies are supported in PRO files.
Brief History of PRO File Format PRO files were created by Adobe Proto that was replaced by Adobe XD.</description></item><item><title>KEY File Format - Privacy-Enhanced Mail Private Key File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/key/</guid><description>What is a KEY file? A KEY file is the private part of a security mechanism that is saved to disc in Privacy-Enhanced Mal (PEM) file format. It is used to decrypt information exchanged between a web browser and the web server that serves the browsing requests. A KEY file contains encoded strings that are useless for human eye but are the essence of encrypting/decrypting information exchange as part of SSL certificate on web servers.</description></item><item><title>KIT File Format - CodeKit File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/kit/</guid><description>What is a KIT file? A file with .kit extension is an HTML file that is created with the CodeKit programming language application. It contains imports and variables in addition to existing HTML files, making it ideal for static sites. CodeKit compiles KIT files to HTML that can be readily used as static website files.
KIT File Format KIT files are HTML files that additionally include imports and variables. These are stored as plain text files and can be opened with any text editor or web file editors.</description></item><item><title>WEBBOOKMARK File Format - Safari Web Bookmark File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/webbookmark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/webbookmark/</guid><description>What is a WEBBOOKMARK file? A WEBBOOKMARK file is a bookmarks file saved with Apple&amp;rsquo;s Safari web browser on macOS. It contains informaiton about the webpage that user has saved from the browser. Information stored in a WEBBOOKMARK file includes the page title, URL, and the bookmark group to which this page is stored. When a webpage is bookmarked, Safari browser asks the group for storing the bookmarked page. Most users save the bookmarks in Bookmarks folder which is the default location offered by common browsers.</description></item><item><title>DOCHTML File Format - Microsoft Word HTML Document File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dochtml/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dochtml/</guid><description>What is a DOCHTML file? A DOCHTML file is the HTML format of a document generated with Microsoft Word. It is the HTML version of the document created that can be used for publishing to web server. DOCHTML files can be opened in web browser for viewing the contents of the converted word document. The outlook and appearence of the DOCHTML file is same as that of the original Word document.</description></item><item><title>OBML File Format - Opera Mini Saved Webpage File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml/</guid><description>What is an OBML file? An OBML (Opera Binary Markup Language) file is an offline version of a webpage saved by Opera Mini mobile web browser. It is a self-contained, compact version of the HTML files that contains all the elements of the page for display on specific devices while offline. The OBML file format has upgraded to several versions with OBML15 and OBML16 being used at large. An important point to keep in consideration is that each Opera Mini version is only compatible with one OBML format.</description></item><item><title>OBML15 File Format - Opera Mini Saved Webpage File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml15/</guid><description>What is an OBML15 file? An OBML15 file is a webpage saved to mobile devices using Opera Mini mobile web browser. It is based on the Opera Binary Markup Language (OBML) that was the initial version of this type of file format. OBML15 replaced OBML with the release of Opera Mini version 5, while it was itself replaced by OBML16 later on. Each Opera Mini version is compatible with one OBML format only i.</description></item><item><title>OBML16 File Format - Opera Mini Saved Webpage File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/obml16/</guid><description>What is an OBML16 file? An OBML16 file is a webpage saved using the Opera Mini mobile web browser. It is based on the Opera Binary Markup Language (OBML) and is a compact format for giving fast access to saved webpages. It replaced the OBML15 file format when Opera Mini version 7 was launched. All these variants of Opera Mini webpages were upgraded from the base OBML file format and each upgrade of Opera Mini is compatible with one OBML format only.</description></item><item><title>JSPA File Format - Java Servlet Alias</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jspa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jspa/</guid><description>What is a JSPA file? A JSPA file is a reference shortcut file that points to a Java Server (.jsp) file. The URL pointed to by the JSPA file is a logical name and may be mapped to a Servelet, JSP or any other thing at the backend. A JSPA file can run multiple pages when called.
References JS - Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>FWTEMPLATE File Format - Freeway Template File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwtemplate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwtemplate/</guid><description>What is a FWTEMPLATE file? An FWTEMPLATE is a template document to create websites without writing any code. It was developed by Freeway Pro and provides a way to create multiple templates that can be readily used to create website documents. FWTEMPLATE files contains information about a website&amp;rsquo;s appearance (UI) and its layout for organizing various parts of the website. This can be used to create a theme based template once and use mutliple times.</description></item><item><title>FWTEMPLATEB File Format - Freeway Template File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwtemplateb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwtemplateb/</guid><description>What is a FWTEMPLATEB file? An FWTEMPLATEB file is a website template document bundle used by the Freeway Pro, a software app for creating websites without writing any code. It contains multiple website templates that can be shared with other Freeway Pro users as well. Each template website in the bundle contains information about the layout and appearance of the site.
FWTEMPLATEB File Format FWTEMPLATEB files are saved as a collection of website templates and contain information related to the site appearance.</description></item><item><title>WEBSITE File Format - Internet Explorer Pinned Site Shortcut File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/website/</guid><description>What is a WEBSITE file? A WEBSITE file is a website shortcut file created with Microsoft Internet Explorer (IE). It contains a URL and an icon (ICO) file that points to the website&amp;rsquo;s favicon. The icon is used for displaying the shortcut. WEBSITE file format was introduced with the release of IE version 9. Previous versions of IE used to save shortcuts to webpages as .url files.
WEBSITE File Format A .</description></item><item><title>TS File Format - Qt Translation Source File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ts/</guid><description>What is a TS file? A TS file is a translation file generated with the lupdate software utility that comes bundled with the Digia&amp;rsquo;s Qt SDK. The SDK is available for Windows, Mac and Linux Operating Systems. TS file contains phrases in one language and their translations into another language. The translations stored inside a TS file are specific to a particular application. TS files can be opened with the Digia Qt SDK.</description></item><item><title>LESS File - LESS Style Sheet File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/less/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/less/</guid><description>What is a LESS file? A LESS file is a style sheet used for webpages and created with the Leaner Style Sheets (LESS). It implements additions to the standard CSS language, that makes it easy to learn and implement. A LESS file extends the CSS by adding features such as Variables, Mixins, Nesting, Operations, Functions, Namespaces and Accessors.
Leaner Style Sheets File Format LESS files are created in the format of CSS, extending its capabilities by the additional features that it offers.</description></item><item><title>XOJ File - Xournal Notebook File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xoj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xoj/</guid><description>What is an XOJ file? An XOJ file is a notebook file that contains notes taken using the hand note-taking software Xournal. Xournal is a free, multi-platform application that lets you create notes with different content types such as text, images, and hand-written doodles. XOJ files are created when a new notebook file is created with Xournal. These XOJ files can be shared with other users as well for data sharing.</description></item><item><title>WBS File - WebBlender Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/wbs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/wbs/</guid><description>What is a WBS file? A WBS file is a project file created by WebBlender that is a presentation and web site creation program for kids. The WBS file is created when a new project is initiated in WebBlender. All the site features added to the project such as pages, images, text, animations and so on, are referenced in the WBS project file. Once the project is ready, it publishes the site contents as HTML file.</description></item><item><title>WHTT File - HTTrack Website Copier File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/whtt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/whtt/</guid><description>What is a WHTT file? A WHTT file is an offline version of a website which is downloaded using the HTTrack Website Copier software. It contains all the contents of a website including HTML webpages, images, stylesheets, links and directories. All the pages of a website are downloaded recursively and saved to disc as offline mirror. When a website is downloaded by the HTTrack software, it can be viewed offline without the need of being connected to the internet.</description></item><item><title>WSDL File Format - Web Services Description Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/wsdl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/wsdl/</guid><description>What is a WSDL file? A WSDL file is a Web Services Description Language file that is written in XML language for describing Web services. It contains information about the endpoints or interfaces for connectivity to the outside world in a universally accepted format. WSDL file format specifications (maintained by W3C.org) define the terms for publishing data feeds for exchange of data in order to have remote application access over ports and endpoints.</description></item><item><title>GDOCX File - Google Drive Document Shortcut</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gdocx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gdocx/</guid><description>What is a GDOCX file? A GDOCX file is a type of shortcut file created that points to an online word processing documents stored in Google Drive. It is created with Google Docs and is saved to the user&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive by default. GDOCX files are similar to GDOC that are most commonly used. The target file information is stored in GDOCX files in plain text that can be opened with any text editor.</description></item><item><title>GNE File - Google Drive Document Shortcut</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gne/</guid><description>What is a GNE file? A GNE file is a webpage that is dynamically generated and used by the Flickr photo-sharing website. The pages are hosted on the server from where these are served to the requesting user&amp;rsquo;s browser. GNE files are similar to PHP and ASP pages, but are developed in a proprietary programming language whose details are not available for developer&amp;rsquo;s reference.
GNE File Format - More Information GNE files were used by the computer game, Game Never Ending, developed by Ludicorp.</description></item><item><title>GSP File - IMail Error Message File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gsp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gsp/</guid><description>What is a GSP file? A GSP file is an error message file that indicates a problem with the delivery of the email. It is sent by IMail Server, an email server program that is used for email communication by numerous small and medium businesses. The error could be due to a number of reasons such as huge amount of data, loss of data in the MSG file, or out of memory errors.</description></item><item><title>GDOC File - Google Docs Shortcut</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gdoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/gdoc/</guid><description>What is a GDOC file? A GDOC file is a shortcut file that points to a file located on Google Drive, a cloud-based document storage service. When Google Drive client is installed on a computer and a document is created inside it, the drive creates a document in the online cloud storage and writes the URL of this document in the GDOC file in local Google Drive folder. When this shortcut file is double clicked, the default web browser opens the document from the URL location.</description></item><item><title>WEBLOC - macOS Website Location File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/webloc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/webloc/</guid><description>What is WEBLOC? A WEBLOC file is a shortcut file on macOS that points to a web URL on internet. It is generated by dragging the web URL from browser&amp;rsquo;s address bar to desktop or any other folder where it is meant to be saved. The URL to destination site is stored inside this shortcut file and can be viewed by opening the file in a text editor such as Microsoft Notepad, Notepad++, or Apple TextEdit.</description></item><item><title>AAE - What is a .aae file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aae/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aae/</guid><description>What is an AAE file? AAE is a file type found on iOS 8 and newer, macOS 10.10 or later systems. It stores information about any edits made to .jpg photos in the Photos app. AAE files are in addition to original files and let users revert photos to their original state if required. When images are imported from macOS to Windows, the accompanying AAE files also get transferred.
AAE File Format AAE files are saved to disc as XML files which is a human readable file format.</description></item><item><title>ARO File Format - SteelArrow Web Application File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aro/</guid><description>What is an ARO file? An ARO file is a server side web page file that is generated with SteelArrow Web Application. It contains HTML and SteelArrow tags and scripts. These are executed on server to generate complete response page before sending these to user&amp;rsquo;s browser. ARO files contain almost 95% of HTML content while the remaining consists of SteelArrow code. For ARO files to work for you, SteelArrow Web Applications server should be installed and running on the web server machine.</description></item><item><title>ASA - ASP Configuration File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asa/</guid><description>What is an ASA file? An ASA file is configuration file, created for ASP/ASP.NET projects. It contains declarations of variables, contains and functions that are meant to be accessible on Global level in the application. All the pages in the project can access these variables and functions, thus avoiding the requirement of rewriting these. One such example is the Global.asa page that is stored in the root directory to be accessible by other ASP website pages.</description></item><item><title>Handheld Device Markup Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hdml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hdml/</guid><description>What is an HDML file? A file with .hdml (Handheld Device Markup Language) extension is a markup language for creating web pages for portable electronic devices such as handheld computers, smartphones, and information display appliances. HDML is said to be an extension of the SGML language. HDML is similar to HTML but for wireless and handheld devices that have small displays such as PDA, mobile phones and so on. It was replaced with WML for which it acted as an important influence.</description></item><item><title>DAP - Microsoft Access Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dap/</guid><description>What is a DAP file? A file with .dap extension is a Microsoft Access Data Page file that is created from within Microsoft Access and has access to the data stored in the database. Data stored in such a web file is accessible over the network (intranet and internet) which is different than the Access&amp;rsquo;s MDB files which are developed for desktop applications specifically. Such databases can be created using Access 2010 and Access Services (an optional component of SharePoint).</description></item><item><title>CFML - ColdFusion Markup Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cfml/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cfml/</guid><description>What is a CFML file? A file with .cfml extension is a ColdFusion Markup Language file that is used to create web page. It refers to a set of rules used to define how the ColdFusion application will be developed by the programmer. ColdFusion is a programming language that is used to to create sever-side web applications quickly and with less than other technologies such as ASP, PHP, etc. Some of the applications that can open CML files include Adobe ColdFusion 2018, Adobe ColdFusion Builder, and Adobe Dreamweaver.</description></item><item><title>CODASITE File Format - Coda Site File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/codasite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/codasite/</guid><description>What is a CODASITE file? A CODASITE file is a website project file created with Coda webpages creation and publishing software. It contains a list of all the files that are part of the project. This includes webpages as HTML files, cascading stylesheet CSS files, Javascript JS files, and any other related supporting files. CODASITE project files also contain information for website publishing to the web server.
CODASITE File Format CODASITE project file is saved to disc as binary files inside the ~/Library/Application Support/Coda 2/Sites/ directory.</description></item><item><title>DBM - ColdFusion Server File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dbm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dbm/</guid><description>What is a DBM file? A file with .dbm (Database Markup Language) extension is a ColdFusion Server File that was developed by Adobe Systems. It is a server-side file that is executed on web server having ColdFusion. It is similar to the ASP and PHP files and generate HTML when a user requests the page in the web browser. DBM files can be opened in applications such as Adobe ColdFusion, Adobe ColdFusion Builder, MacroMates TextMate, and Apple Safari.</description></item><item><title>DCR - Shockwave Media File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dcr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dcr/</guid><description>What is a DCR file? A DCR file is a media file that is created and saved in the Adobe Shockwave format. It is used for creation of web games and interactive games similar to those designed and saved in SWF files. DCR files were earlier created with Adobe Director that was later discontinued after acquisition by Adobe systems. DCR files are similar to SWF files created by Adobe Flash.</description></item><item><title>DWT - Dreamweaver Webpage Template File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dwt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dwt/</guid><description>What is a DWT file? A file with a .dwt extension is a webpage template file created with Dreamweaver software. It is used as a starting point to develop multiple pages that have the basic settings defined already in the template. New HTML pages can be built using copies of these templates and changing the content where necessary, while keeping the common sections unchanged. The non-editable regions of these templates such as header, footer, and menu remain the same across all the webpages.</description></item><item><title>ECE File - Escenic Dynamic Web Page File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ece/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ece/</guid><description>What is an ECE file? An ECE file is a dynamically generated web page by the content management platform, Escenic Content Engine (ECE). It contains server-side code that is processed by the web server and served back to the user browser as HTML page. ECE file format is not very commonly popular as compared to other server side file formats such as ASP and PHP. These files are rendered internally and served to end users for display purpose.</description></item><item><title>EDGE - Adobe Edge Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/edge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/edge/</guid><description>What is an EDGE file? A file with .edge extension is Adobe Edge Project file that is created when a project is created and saved with Adobe Edge. Adobe Edge lets web designers to create interactive HTML animators for web, digital publishing, and rich media advertising for both desktop and mobile browsers. This is achieved using HTML/HTML5, JavaScript, and CSS3. Edge files are generated as plain text files and can be opened with several different applications such as Microsoft Notepad, Apple TextEdit, and Notepad++.</description></item><item><title>FMP - 123 Flash Menu Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fmp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fmp/</guid><description>What is an FMP file? A file with .fmp file is an animated menu file created with 123 Flash Menu application. It contains animated menus for website including the components such as as fonts, menu&amp;rsquo;s style, colors, dimensions, sounds, and animations. The 123 Flash Menu application doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any special computer skills as the application itself incorporates all the functionality to develop such menus. The FMP menu files can be exported to the all time famous Flash&amp;rsquo;s .</description></item><item><title>FWP - Microsoft Expression Web Package</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/fwp/</guid><description>What is a FWP file? A file with .fwp file is an archive file created with Microsoft Expression Web and contains all the files and folders for a design. Microsoft Expression Web is a general web design software product by Microsoft and is based on HTML editor. It has been discontinued since 2012 and available free for download by Microsoft. FWP files can be exported and saved as Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s .cab format.</description></item><item><title>MJS - Node.js ES Module Javascript File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mjs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mjs/</guid><description>What is an MJS file? A file with .mjs extension is a JavaScript source code file that is used as an ECMA Module (ECMAScript Module) in Node.js applications. Node.js&amp;rsquo;s natvie module system is CommonJS that is used to split the code in different files to keep the JS code organized. MJS is the only way used by Node.js to identify if the module is a CommonJS or an ES6. ECMAScript modules are standard formta for packaging JavaScript code for reuse.</description></item><item><title>CER - Certificate File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cer/</guid><description>What is a CER file? A file with an extension .cer is responsible for storing some information about the owner certificate and the specific public key. This format of files cannot store the private keys and have the capacity to store only one certificate which is x509. The specifically secured certificate authorities are those which belong to HTTPS, a trusted and secured protocol for browsing
The CER is a certificate of your server.</description></item><item><title>CFM - Cold Fusion Markup</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cfm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cfm/</guid><description>What is a CFM file? The web pages and files used in Cold Fusion Markup Language contain extensions of CFM and are named CFM web pages. This web development scripting language runs on Google App Engine, .NET framework, and JVM. It can contain a programming language or code of the language. When any of its pages are accessed by the user, the webserver of ColdFusion executes it. CFScript (that is close to JavaScript) or tags can be used to write CFML.</description></item><item><title>HAR - HTTP Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/har/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/har/</guid><description>What is a HAR file? A file with .har (HTTP Archive) file is an HTTP archive file that stores session data transferring over many browsers (such as Chrome, Safari, IE, Firefox, etc.) in JSON file format. The data transferred over the internet between the server and the client (in this case user&amp;rsquo;s browser) contains HTTP request and response headers that are stored in HAR file. It further contains detailed information about performance data about web pages loaded in the browser.</description></item><item><title>SPC - Software Publisher Certificate File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/spc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/spc/</guid><description>What is an SPC file? A file with .spc extension is a digital security certificate file created in the PKCS # 7 format. Several applications, create these certificate files for secure exchange of information. Few such applications include OpenSSL and the Signcode.exe application included with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s .NET Framework. Like other certificate files such as .cer, .p7c, and .ssp, the SPC files contain the public key information that is encrypted with a private key.</description></item><item><title>SSP - Scala Server Pages File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ssp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ssp/</guid><description>What is an SSP file? A file with .ssp extension is web page created with Scala code for expressions instead of plain HTML only. It acts as a server side script using the combination of HTML and Scala. These files reside on the server and are used to create static webpages to be served to users. Scala itself is a general-purpose programming language whose syntax is familiar to users who have worked with Velocity, JSP or Erb.</description></item><item><title>PART - Partially Downloaded File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/part/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/part/</guid><description>What is a PART file? A part file or .part extension is a partially downloaded file. It is used when downloads are in progress or have been interrupted due to any issue, giving the download manager an opportunity to resume the download whenever possible. This means that the browser, such as Firefox or file transfer programs like eMule, eMule plus, FlashGet, etc. stores a portion of the file, called Part file, while the downloading is occurring on your device.</description></item><item><title>RSS - Really Simple Syndication</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rss/</guid><description>What is an RSS file? A file with the extension .rss is known as Really Simple Syndication. RSS is a readily or easily read file type by the computer, the XML file. These XML files are automatically updated with any changes in data or updates of a website or webpage. The updated information along with the metadata (author&amp;rsquo;s name, publisher&amp;rsquo;s name, publishing date, etc.), and other web content of the website are extracted by the user&amp;rsquo;s RSS files and presented in an easy-to-read format.</description></item><item><title>DML - DynaScript HTML File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dml/</guid><description>What is a DML file? A file with .dml extension is a web script page code file created with DyanScript. DynaScript is a dynamic HTML scripting language that is compatible with ECMAScript and provides most of the same features as other scripting language. It is similar to ColdFusion code and Microsoft Active Server Pages (ASP) code. DML files can be opened and viewed in standard web browsers similar to other HTML pages.</description></item><item><title>PAC - Proxy Auto-Configuration (PAC) file</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/pac/</guid><description>What is a PAC file? A file with .pac (Proxy Auto-Configuration) extension is a configuration file that contains rules sending web requests directly to internet or route these via a proxy server. It contains a JavaScript function that routes the web requests via some web proxy server instead of sending these directly to the destination. A proxy server is like a man-in-the-middle that accepts requests from multiple clients and serves these by forwarding to destinations.</description></item><item><title>RHTML - Ruby HTML Page</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rhtml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rhtml/</guid><description>What is an RHTML file? A file with .rhtml extension is a server side HTML file that contains Ruby code or scripts. The code is executed on the server using the Ruby on Rails running at the backend. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know about Ruby on Rails, it is a full-stack framework for developing web applications with backend databases based on the Model-View-Control pattern. Simply said, RHTML is a combination of HTML and Ruby where the power of Ruby scripting/programming is available to web developers using HTML tags.</description></item><item><title>RJS - Ruby Javascript File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rjs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/rjs/</guid><description>What is an RJS file? A file with .rjs extension is a combination of Ruby code and JavsScript that allows Rails developers to use Ruby to produce dynamic JavaScript code. Ruby code is embedded in Java functions and is compiled on the web server that requires Ruby engine to be to be running on the server. RJS is similar to RHTML; the only difference is that the lateral contains Ruby code in HTML while it contains Ruby code in Javascript functions.</description></item><item><title>XD - Adobe XD Document</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xd/</guid><description>What is an XD file? A file with .xd extension is a mockup created for website or mobile applications using the Adobe XD software. Designers, creative teams, and organizations use these files to design applications by referring these. A single XD file contains design elements such as images, shapes, and text that provide complete feature set to develop fast and intuitive wireframe prototypes for developers to start developing these as applications.</description></item><item><title>XHT</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xht/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xht/</guid><description>What is an XHT file? A file with .xht extension is a web file associated with the XHTML (Extended Hypertext Markup Language) file type, which itself is an XML based markup file. Both these files are similar to HTML but have a more stringent XML-like syntax. XHT files are designed in a way to be more structured, involves less scripting, and are generic in addition to using the existing facilities of XML.</description></item><item><title>XUL - XML User Interface Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xul/</guid><description>What is an XUL file? A file with a .xul extension (XUL stands for XML User Interface Language) is an XML based markup language file for creating user interfaces. It was developed by Mozilla for developers to create graphical user interface elements similar to other markup languages used for creating web pages. XUL has been widely in use by Mozilla in its Firefox browser where it used the Mozilla codebase. XUL rendering is carried out using the Gecko engine.</description></item><item><title>ZUL - ZK User Interface File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/zul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/zul/</guid><description>What is a ZUL file? A file with .zul extension is a web file created with the User Interface Markup Language (ZUML) and contains definitions for user interface elements. Ajax and Java classes support using the XML-based ZUML for developing server side files. ZUL file format was developed by ZK, a UI framework that enables you to build web and mobile applications without the knowledge of JavaScript or AJAX.
ZUL File Format ZUL files are XML-based, consisting of different elements to construct user interface.</description></item><item><title>SHTML - Server Side Include HTML File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/shtml/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/shtml/</guid><description>What is an SHTML file? A file with .shtml extension is a webpage that is written in HTML and includes server instructions. It may also contain server-side includes similar to ASP files for faster loading. The server side files can also contain executable code that can make the server to load slower than usual. SHTML files are similar to HTML but they also allow the use of simple server commands. These server commands are performed in a simple computer programming language called Server Side Includes (SSI).</description></item><item><title>STML - SSI HTML File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/stml/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/stml/</guid><description>What is an STML file? A file with .stml extension is a webpage with server side instructions that are executed when a user loads the page in web browser. STML pages contains server side code that contains server side includes to perform tasks that are not possible to achieve with plain HTML. Though similar to HTML, STML offers more power by running the commands on server, also called Server Side Includes (SSI).</description></item><item><title>What is STC File Extension?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/stc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/stc/</guid><description>What is a STC file? A file with .stc extension is a connection file used by Adobe Contribute software to store the connection information. It contains connection information such as username, host url, protocols such as FTP, SFTP, etc. for reuse from within the existing website. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Adobe Contribute used to be a specialized HTML editor that was used to push updates to existing websites including content based articles known as blogs.</description></item><item><title>XSLT File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xslt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xslt/</guid><description>What is an XSLT file? A file with a .xslt extension is an Extensible Stylesheet Language Transformation file that is used to transform and style an XML file using XSL instructions. The format is used to transform XML documents into standard output formats such as a text document or .html web page. This transformation creates a new document based on the content of the existing XML document. XSLT is making it theoretically capable of arbitrary computations.</description></item><item><title>A5W - Alpha Five Webpage File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/a5w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/a5w/</guid><description>What is an A5W file? An A5W file is a server-side webpage created wit Alpha Five software and contains code that is served to users when accessed via browser. It is similar to the .asp and .php pages but differs in syntax as these are written in Alpha Five syntax. Alpha Five is a cross platform web and mobile applications development tool for rapid application tool. It also lets you create dynamic webpage components and browser-run desktop-like applications.</description></item><item><title>ADR - Opera Bookmarks File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/adr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/adr/</guid><description>What is an ADR file? An ADR file (saved with .adr extension) is a list of bookmarks created by the Opera Web browser. This list gets populated as user keeps bookmarking web URLs. These bookmarks are stored in the ADR file that can be backed up and restored when required. Since most browsers such as Chrome and Firefox save bookmarks in HTML format, these can be converted to ADR file format for importing in Opera browser.</description></item><item><title>AEX - Alpha Five Compiled Global Functions File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aex/</guid><description>What is an AEX file? An AEX file (with .aex extension) is a compiled Xbasic file that contains compiled program code for global functions. It can be used in web applications by calling them from server side .a5w pages. AEX files were loaded and unloaded by calling a5w_load_aex and a5w_unload_aex functions respectively from A5W files. However, in new implementation, these files are loaded into memory by including in the a5_application.5i file.</description></item><item><title>ALX - What is an ALX file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/alx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/alx/</guid><description>What is an ALX file? An ALX file is an ActiveX file that is embedded in Web pages in the form of HTML components. ActiveX controls were formally known as OLE controls or OCXs. ALX files can be used to insert a variety of functionalities in a web page such adding a timer control for updating the page&amp;rsquo;s content periodically, or add a Popup window control for displaying tooltip-style help based on user action.</description></item><item><title>AN - Adobe Edge Animate Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/an/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/an/</guid><description>What is an AN file? A file with .an extension is an Adobe Edge Animate project file that contains information about the animation. A .html file is created when the project is saved which contains the references to the associated .css and .js files generated by Adobe Edge Animate. The AN file is saved along with these files that can be used to open the project file. Adobe edge animate can be used as an alternative to creating animated webpages using Adobe Flash, which is no more supported by browsers.</description></item><item><title>AP File Format - Active Page File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ap/</guid><description>What is an AP file? An AP file is an Active Web Page that runs on a web server and is used to create dynamic web pages. These web pages are then served to the requesting browser and displayed to user. AP file consist of HTML and JavaScript code that is executed on the server. Being more generic, AP files use .ap extension instead of the conventional server side .php or .</description></item><item><title>APKG  Anki Flashcard Deck File Format: What It Is and How to Open It</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/apkg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/apkg/</guid><description>What is an APKG file? A file with .apkg extension is a deck of flashcards generated to be used in Anki software application which is a flashcard-based learning program. It contains HTML text to be loaded and displayed in Anki application and can additionally have images and sounds for visual and audible learning. Anki allows users to create their own Anki flashcard decks as well as import other user&amp;rsquo;s flashcard decks.</description></item><item><title>ASAX - ASP.NET Server Application File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asax/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asax/</guid><description>What is an ASAX file? A file with .asax extension is a file used by ASP.NET applications that resides on the server side. It contains code for responding to application-level and session-level events raised by ASP.NET or by HTTP modules. This also includes handling certain events when the application launches or shuts down. ASAX files are optional and only a single ASAX file is added to web applications to handle the application-level events and errors at the global level.</description></item><item><title>ASCX File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ascx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ascx/</guid><description>What is an ASCX file? A file with .ascx extension is a user control that is used as a reusable component in webpages. It is referenced in any ASP website by dragging it from the control box to the page. ASCX users controls are added to the project as a central source, resulting in any change in the user control to be reflected across the whole website. Unlike ASMX files which define a mechanism to communicate within 2 objects over the internet, ASCX files are user controls for embedding in pages or website.</description></item><item><title>ASHX File Extension - An ASP.NET Web Handler File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ashx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/ashx/</guid><description>What is an ASHX file? An ASHX file is a webpage that is used by the ASP.NET HTTP Handler to serve user with the pages that are referenced inside this file. The ASP.NET HTTP Handler processes the incoming request, references the pages from the .ashx file, and sends back the compiled page back to the user&amp;rsquo;s browser. The method of processing is mostly similar to that of ASPX files with the differecne that in this case, the referenced pages/documents are processed and sent back.</description></item><item><title>ASMX - ASP.NET Web Service File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asmx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asmx/</guid><description>What is an ASMX file? A file with .asmx extensions is an ASP.NET Web Service file that provides communication between two objects over the internet using the Simple Object Access Protocol (SOAP). It is deployed as a service on the Windows-based Web Server to process incoming request and return the response. Unlike ASPX files which contain the code for visual display of ASP.NET webpages, ASMX files run at the server in background and perform different tasks such as connecting to database, retrieving data, and returning it in a format in which the request was made.</description></item><item><title>ASP - Active Server Pages File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/asp/</guid><description>What is an ASP file? ASP stands for Active Server Pages which is a development framework for creating web pages. It enables computer code to be executed by an internal server to serve the web requests. When a request is generated for an ASP fileby web browser, the server reads the the file and executes any code/script inside it to generate the HTML result which is returned to the browser for display.</description></item><item><title>ASPX File Format - What Is an ASPX File and How to Open It</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aspx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/aspx/</guid><description>What is an ASPX file? A file with .aspx extension is a webpage generated using Microsoft ASP.NET framework running on web servers. ASPX stands for Active Server Pages Extended and these pages are displayed in web browser at user end when the URL is accessed. It is successor of ASP technology which are also generated at server end but does not use .NET framework. ASP.NET pages may contain C# or VB.</description></item><item><title>BML File Format - Bean Markup Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/bml/</guid><description>What is a BML file? A file with .bml extension is a Bean Markup Language file that stores Java classes for supporting Java apps. This allows access to Java objects and methods, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to create new functionality using Java classes. It specifies how the components are connected to each other for performing useful tasks. BML was developed by IBM alphaWorks to describe the structures and components relationships. BML files can be opened and viewed using any text editor such as Web Browsers, Microsoft Notepad and Notepad++.</description></item><item><title>CDF - Channel Definition Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cdf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cdf/</guid><description>What is a CDF file? A file with .cdf extension is an XLM based information distribution file format that was used to publish frequent updates as &amp;ldquo;channels&amp;rdquo;. The information is published from any web server and is automatically delivered to computers with compatible receiving programs such as web browsers. Users subscribe to active channels and have scheduled updates delivered to their desktop. CDF files were earlier used in conjunction with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Active Channel, Active Desktop and Smart Offline Favorites technologies.</description></item><item><title>CHM - Compiled HTML Help File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/chm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/chm/</guid><description>What is a CHM file? The CHM file format represents Microsoft HTML help file that consists of a collection of HTML pages. It provides an index for quick accessing the topics and navigation to different parts of the help document. The CHM file can be searched for contents via the provided search option. CHM is Microsoft Proprietary online help file format that is often used for software documentation. In addition, it is used in several other applications like training guides, interactive books, and electronic newsletters.</description></item><item><title>CRDOWNLOAD - Chrome Partially Downloaded File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crdownload/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crdownload/</guid><description>What is a CRDOWNLOAD file? A CRDOWNLOAD file is a partially downloaded file that is created when you download a file from internet using Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome, or Chromium browsers. The contents of file being downloaded are stored in this file until the download completes. Once the download completes, the .crdownload extension is removed and is replaced with the original file extension of the file being downloaded.
CRDOWNLOAD File Format A CRDOWNLOAD file can be in text as well as binary format.</description></item><item><title>CRT - Security Certificate File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/crt/</guid><description>What is a CRT file? A file with .crt extension is a security certificate file that is used by secure websites for establishing secure connections from web server to a browser. Secure websites make it possible to secure data transfers, logins, payment card transactions, and provide protected browsing to the site. If you open a secure website, you see a &amp;ldquo;lock&amp;rdquo; icon in the address bar. If you click on it, you can view the details of the installed certificate.</description></item><item><title>CSHTML - ASP.NET Razor Webpage</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cshtml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/cshtml/</guid><description>What is a CSHTML file? A file with .cshtml extension is a C# HTML file that is used at server side by Razor Markup engine to render the webpage files to user&amp;rsquo;s browser. This server side coding is similar to the standard ASP.NET page enabling dynamic web content creation on the fly as the webpage is written to the browser. The server executes the server-side code inside the page before sending the generated page to the browser.</description></item><item><title>CSS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/css/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/css/</guid><description>What is a CSS file? CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) are files that describe how HTML elements are displayed on the screen, paper, etc. With HTML, you can have either embedded styles or styles can be defined in an external stylesheet. For embedding the styles, the &amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt; tags are used. The external stylesheets are stored in files with the .css extension. With the external CSS, you can include it on multiple HTML pages to update the style of those pages.</description></item><item><title>DHTML - Dynamic HTML File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dhtml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/dhtml/</guid><description>What is a DHTML file? A file with a .dhtml extension is a dynamic HTML file that is used to creating dynamic contents of a webpage. A web element created in DHTML is event driven and does not require to reload the page. In most of the cases, a DHTML file is used to create the dynamic contents of a webpage such as drop-down menus, floating layers, rollover buttons, and other dynamic content.</description></item><item><title>DRAWIO - Diagram.net Diagram File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/drawio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/drawio/</guid><description>What is a DRAWIO file? A file with a .drawio extension is a drawing file created with diagrams.net&amp;rsquo;s draw.io that is an open-source program for working with diagrams. It contains overall information for the content and formatting of the diagram elements such as text, images, layout, shapes and positioning. Diagrams supported by DRAWIO include flowcharts, organization charts, maps, engineering elements, process diagrams, charts and more. DRAWIO files can be exported to several different formats such as JPG, PNG, BMP, XML, PDF, HTML and VSDX.</description></item><item><title>HTACCESS File - Apache HTACCESS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htaccess/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htaccess/</guid><description>What is an HTACCESS file? An HTACCESS file is an Apache configuration file that provides a mechanism to allow configuration changes for different folders/directories of a website. It includes configuration directives that are applicable to the directory and sub-directories.
An HTACCESS file performs a number of checks such as defining the index page of a website, listing the 404 (Page Not Found) error page, performing the 301 or 302 page redirects, blocking access from a specific IP address or other websites.</description></item><item><title>HTC File - HTML Component File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htc/</guid><description>What is an HTC file? An HTC file is a web file format file used by Microsoft Internet Explorer. It contains definitions for HTML components that perform small functions for performing different tasks inside the web browser. Functionality defined inside HTC files is reusable and is accessible across multiple HTML pages.
HTC File Format - More Information HTC files are saved in plain text file format. This means you can open these in any text editor and make changes to the functionality.</description></item><item><title>HTM File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htm/</guid><description>What is an HTM file? Files with .htm extensionrepresentHypertext Markup Language for creating web pages for display in web browsers such as Google Chrome, Internet Explorer, Firefox and a number of others. It defines the markups for creating static pages to be published on World Wide Web (WWW) for access by others. These markups tell the browsers how to display a web page&amp;rsquo;s contents. Such pages can contain plain text, images, hyperlinks to other pages, videos and other media information.</description></item><item><title>HTML File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/html/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/html/</guid><description>What is an HTML file? HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) is the extension for web pages created for display in browsers. Known as language of the web, HTML has evolved with requirements of new information requirements to be displayed as part of web pages. The latest variant is known as HTML 5 that gives a lot of flexibility for working with the language. HTML pages are either received from server, where these are hosted, or can be loaded from local system as well.</description></item><item><title>HTX File - HTML Extension File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/htx/</guid><description>What is an HTX file? An HTX file is actually an HTML file that contains data variables for displaying the database query results as a webpage. Mostly created with Microsoft FrontPage Web development software, HTX files are saved to be saved in the same folder as the corresponding Internet Database Connector (.IDC) file.
HTX files can be opened with applications such as Microsoft FrontPage and any text editor such as Notepad, TextEdit, or Atom.</description></item><item><title>HXS File - Help 2 Compiled Help File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hxs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hxs/</guid><description>What is an HXS file? An HXS file is a help file compiled and used for Microsoft Help 2.x file. It is compiled and generated from a set of topic pages and written in a subset of HTML that is similar to the earlier CHM Help File Format. HXS files are stored in compressed format and is created from a .HxC main project file, a .HxF include file, a .HxT table of contents, a .</description></item><item><title>HYPE File - Hype Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hype/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/hype/</guid><description>What is a HYPE file? A HYPE file is a project file saved using the Hype software that is used for creation of web content with HTML5. It contains web elements such as graphics, text, animation, scene information and other elements that collectively make up the content. Web content in a HYPE file can be exported to web files that can be published on a webpage.
A HYPE file can be opened with Tumult Hype software.</description></item><item><title>JHTML - Java HTML File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jhtml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/jhtml/</guid><description>What is a JHTML file? A file with .jhtml extension is an HTML file with Java code that is executed on server when a client requests this page in a browser. The server processes the requests, executes the Java functions contained in the function, and returns the page to the client&amp;rsquo;s browser. The Java objects embedded in the JHTML pages run on server to handle requests for pages of this type.</description></item><item><title>JS File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/js/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/js/</guid><description>What is a JS file? JS (JavaScript) are files that contain JavaScript code for execution on web pages. JavaScript files are stored with the .js extension. Inside the HTML document, you can either embed the JavaScript code using the &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; tags or include a JS file. Similar to CSS files, JS files can be included in multiple HTML documents for code reusability. JavaScript can be used to manipulate the HTML DOM.</description></item><item><title>JSON File Format - What is a JSON file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/json/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/json/</guid><description>What is a JSON file? JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) is an open standard file format for sharing data that uses human-readable text to store and transmit data. JSON files are stored with the .json extension. JSON requires less formatting and is a good alternative for XML. JSON is derived from JavaScript but is a language-independent data format. The generation and parsing of JSON is supported by many modern programming languages. application/json is the media type used for JSON.</description></item><item><title>MASTER File - ASP.NET Master Page File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/master/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/master/</guid><description>What is a MASTER file? A MASTER file is a master webpage template file created with ASP.NET. It is used as a starting point for creating multiple pages that have the same layout and settings as the MASTER file. The template MASTER file includes settings for header, navigation menus, footer, font and styling information. Using a MASTER file helps create multiple webpages quickly.
You can open a MASTER file using Microsoft Visual Studio 2022 and above.</description></item><item><title>MHT - MIME HTML File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mht/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mht/</guid><description>What is a MHT file? A file with .mht extension is a MIME enabled archiving file format that contains different types of data into a single file. It can store data such as text, images, page styling in the form of CSS files, JavaScript, and other resources as embedded resources in it. MHT files, having MIME type message/rfc822, encapsulate all the contents of an HTML file as a single archive file for storing on archiving on storage devices.</description></item><item><title>MHTML - MIME HTML File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mhtml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/mhtml/</guid><description>What is an MHTML file? Files with MHTML extension represent a web page archive format that can be created by a number of different applications. The format is known as archive format because it saves the web HTML code and associated resources in a single file. These resources include anything linked to the webpage such as images, applets, animations, audio files and so on. MHTML files can be opened in a variety of applications such as Internet Explorer and Microsoft Word.</description></item><item><title>P7B - PKCS 7 Certificate File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/p7b/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/p7b/</guid><description>What is a P7B file? A P7B file is a security certificate file that contains secure digital certificate for authenticating a person or a device. Similar to a .cer certificate file, a P7B file can be installed using the &amp;ldquo;Install Certificate&amp;rdquo; option by using the right click option on the file. P7B uses different formatting option than the CER file format. It contains one or more X.509 digital certificate files that use base64 (ASCII) encoding.</description></item><item><title>P7C - PKCS 7 Certificate File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/p7c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/p7c/</guid><description>What is a P7C file? A P7C file, like other security certificate files, is a digital certificate that is used to authenticate identity over the network. Applications using certificates authenticate identity using the public key included in these certificate files. Public-key cryptography, or asymmetric cryptography, uses pair of keys of which one is the public key and the other is known as private key. The private key is kept secure for effective security, while the public key can be shared with others.</description></item><item><title>Sass File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/sass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/sass/</guid><description>What is a SASS file? Sass (syntactically awesome style sheets) is a preprocessor scripting language. It is compiled into CSS and is stored with the .sass extension. Sass consists of two syntaxes, the original based on indentations that uses the .sass extension and the newer SCSS with block formatting like CSS that uses the .scss extension.
Why use Sass Sass is really helpful in maintaining styles as it provides many features like introduces variables, nesting, mixins, imports, and selector inheritance that make working with styles fun.</description></item><item><title>SCSS File Format - Sass Cascading Style Sheet</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/scss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/scss/</guid><description>What is an SCSS file? SCSS is the second syntax of Sass (Syntactically Awesome Stylesheet) that uses brackets instead of indentations. SCSS was designed in such a way that a valid CSS3 file is also a valid SCSS file. SCSS files are stored with the .scss extension.
Why use SCSS As the designs of websites are becoming complex resulting in large CSS files. Such files are harder to maintain. This is where SCSS comes in.</description></item><item><title>TPL - HTTP File Server Template</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/tpl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/tpl/</guid><description>What is a TPL file? A file with .tpl extension is a template file created and used by HTTP File Server (HFS) which is a file sharing application program to send and receive files over the web technology HTTP instead of the FTP protocol. It is used to build HTML pages dynamically based on the template information that is defined to have settings with similar layout, styling and scripts. Applications that require the same settings can be assigned the same template file and HFS will return the requested page dynamically on runtime based on this template file.</description></item><item><title>URL - Internet Shortcut File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/url/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/url/</guid><description>What is an URL file? A file with .url extension is a website URL shortcut that can be saved to computer with any website address. When it is opened by double clicking, the URL will open the website in default browser and the page will be displayed to user. URL files are usually referred to as shortcut files to websites and are represented by the icon of the default browser. URL files can be opened and edited in any text editor such as Microsoft Notepad, Notepad++, or Apple TextEdit.</description></item><item><title>VRT - Virtual World File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/vrt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/vrt/</guid><description>What is a VRT file? A VRT file is a 3D file format that contains three-dimensional worlds that can be viewed in web browser with Viscape SVR plugin. It is used by the plugin to load and display the 3D world data to user for visualization and analysis. Information stored in a VRT file may comprise of data such as textures, sounds, dimensions, and behaviors. The most recent VRT files are stored in SVR file format which is a compressed version of the VRT file.</description></item><item><title>XAML - XML Based Markup Language</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xaml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xaml/</guid><description>What is a XAML file? XAML, Extensible Application Markup Language, extension files describe the user interface elements for software applications based on Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF). Though a language, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require to be programmed as it is based on standard format of XML which is easy to use and understand. XAML (pronounced as &amp;ldquo;zammel&amp;rdquo;) was developed by Microsoft with specific aim for creating user interfaces. Its acronym original stood for Extensible Avalon Markup Language, where Avalon was the code-name for WPF.</description></item><item><title>XHTML - Extensible Hypertext Markup Language File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xhtml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xhtml/</guid><description>What is an XHTML file? The XHTML is a text based file format with markup in the XML, using a reformulation of HTML 4.0. These files are well suited to be open or viewed in a web browser. XHTML was designed to be more structured, less scripting, generic; using all the existing facilities of XML and more device independent. XHTML provides a generally worthwhile set of elements and attributes, with extension options in combination with style sheets.</description></item><item><title>XML File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xml/</guid><description>What is an XML file? XML stands for Extensible Markup Language that is similar to HTML but different in using tags for defining objects. The whole idea behind creation of XML file format was to store and transport data without being dependent on software or hardware tools. Its popularity is due to it being both human as well as machine readable. This enables it to create common data protocols in the form of objects to be stored and shared over network such as World Wide Web (WWW).</description></item><item><title>XOML - Windows Workflow File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xoml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/web/xoml/</guid><description>What is an XOML file? XOML is acronym for Extensible Object Markup Language and is a serialization format for Windows Workflow Foundation&amp;rsquo;s workflow objects. Based on XAML, it is mostly used for creating user interfaces in plain XML. These are used to declare the workflow for user interface and are compiled along with the separate file containing implementation logic. It contains a tree based structure that defines a root workflow node, nested sub-elements and embedded segments of code.</description></item></channel></rss>