<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Database File Formats and APIs that can open and create Database files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Database File Formats and APIs that can open and create Database files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CRYPT10 File Format - WhatsApp Encrypted Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt10/</guid><description>The CRYPT10 file format is associated with WhatsApp encrypted chat backups stored on Android devices. It is a variant of WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s .crypt series, which are used for encrypting chat backups stored in the /sdcard/WhatsApp/Databases/ directory.
Understanding CRYPT10 Files File Name Example: msgstore.db.crypt10 Purpose: Stores encrypted chat messages and media metadata. Location: Typically found in /sdcard/WhatsApp/Databases/ on Android devices. Encryption: Uses a proprietary encryption method by WhatsApp. How to Decrypt a CRYPT10 File?</description></item><item><title>CRYPT15 File Format - WhatsApp Encrypted Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt15/</guid><description>What is a CRYPT15 file? The .crypt15 file format is associated with WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s encrypted backup files stored on Google Drive or local storage. It is part of the WhatsApp Crypt series (e.g., .crypt14, .crypt12, etc.), which encrypts chat backups for security.
Key Details About .crypt15 Files Used by: WhatsApp to store chat backups securely. Encryption: End-to-end encrypted using a key stored in the phone&amp;rsquo;s internal memory. Storage Locations: Local Storage: /sdcard/WhatsApp/Databases/msgstore.</description></item><item><title>CRYPT13 File Format - WhatsApp Encrypted Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt13/</guid><description>What is a CRYPT13 File? A .crypt13 file is an encrypted backup of WhatsApp messages stored on Android devices. WhatsApp periodically creates these backups to help users restore their chat history if they reinstall the app or switch devices.
File Type: WhatsApp chat database backup Encryption: AES-256 encryption File Name: msgstore.db.crypt13 Storage Path: /sdcard/WhatsApp/Databases/msgstore.db.crypt13 (Or /storage/emulated/0/WhatsApp/Databases/ in newer Android versions.) Encryption Details WhatsApp encrypts chat backups using AES-256 and stores the encryption key separately on the device.</description></item><item><title>NWDB File - Neat Database File - What is .nwdb file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nwdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nwdb/</guid><description>What is an NWDB file? The NWDB file format is known as the Neat Database File and is associated with Neat 5 which is a digital document management application designed to organize scanned documents, receipts, and contacts. An NWDB file is created when user scans documents using Neat software. It contains images of these scanned documents along with metadata which helps in organizing and retrieving the files.
Even though it uses the .</description></item><item><title>TVDB File - Apple TV Database - What is a .tvdb file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/tvdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/tvdb/</guid><description>What is a TVDB file? A TVDB file is a type of database file that is associated with Apple TV. It&amp;rsquo;s typically stored within your TV Library, which is the file responsible for holding your Apple TV library data. TVDB files serve as repositories of information related to either your Apple TV settings or your Apple TV library contents. These files play a role in maintaining and organizing data relevant to your Apple TV setup and media library.</description></item><item><title>FPT File Format - FileMaker Pro Database Memo File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt/</guid><description>What is an FPT file? In FileMaker Pro, &amp;ldquo;.fpt&amp;rdquo; files are used to store memo comments or textual information associated with a database. These memo comments provide a way to describe the contents of the database using raw text. This is especially useful when you want to provide additional context or details about the database that might not fit within the standard database fields, which often have character limits.
FPT files in FileMaker Pro are used to store memo comments that provide descriptive textual information about a database.</description></item><item><title>JET File Format - Microsoft JET Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/jet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/jet/</guid><description>What is a JET file? A JET database file, also known as a Microsoft Access database file, is a file format used by Microsoft Access, a popular database management system (DBMS). JET stands for Joint Engine Technology, which was the original name of the database engine that Microsoft Access used. Later versions of Access have used different database engines, but the term &amp;ldquo;JET database&amp;rdquo; is still commonly used to refer to Access databases.</description></item><item><title>RPD File Format - RIB Project Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/rpd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/rpd/</guid><description>What is an RPD file? RPD file format is specific to the iTWO application suite used for construction planning and engineering. An RPD file is a database file that stores a Progress ObjectStore Database. This database contains all the data for an iTWO planning project, serving as a backend storage format for the application.
In the iTWO context, the RPD file contains structured information related to construction projects, such as project plans, resources, schedules, budgets, and other project-related data.</description></item><item><title>UDB File Format - Microsoft Dynamics AX User Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/udb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/udb/</guid><description>What is a UDB file? The UDB file format, which stands for &amp;ldquo;Dynamics AX User Database File,&amp;rdquo; is associated with Microsoft AX business management software, now known as Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations. This file format is used to store important information related to user management and system components within the software.
The UDB file typically includes a list of users who have access to the Dynamics AX system. It also contains information about the Component Object Model (COM) and the Application Object Server (AOS), which are integral components of the Dynamics AX architecture.</description></item><item><title>ECO File Format - ECCO Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/eco/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/eco/</guid><description>What is an ECO file? The &amp;ldquo;ECO&amp;rdquo; file format is associated with the NetManage ECCO (Enterprise Core Objects) application. ECCO was a personal information manager (PIM) and database software that allowed users to organize and manage their data in a flexible and customizable manner. It was popular during the 1990s and early 2000s.
The ECCO database files have the extension &amp;ldquo;.eco&amp;rdquo; and contain structured data stored in a proprietary format. The application allowed users to create custom data fields, forms, and views to organize their information efficiently.</description></item><item><title>USR File Format - FileMaker Pro Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/usr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/usr/</guid><description>What is a USR file? USR file is a FileMaker database file in a specialized format utilized by FileMaker Pro, a powerful software application designed for creating, organizing, and distributing databases. This file serves as a container for user-specific databases, housing data and related components in a proprietary structure unique to FileMaker.
With FileMaker Pro, users can efficiently import data from various sources, such as text files, Excel documents, or Bento databases.</description></item><item><title>What are PDB Files? Understanding PDB Files: A Crucial Tool for Structural Biology</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pdb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pdb/</guid><description>Understanding PDB Files: A Crucial Tool for Structural Biology In the realm of structural biology, the Protein Data Bank (PDB) serves as a valuable resource for scientists and researchers. PDB files, the standardized format for storing three-dimensional (3D) structures of proteins and other macromolecules, play a pivotal role in elucidating their atomic coordinates and providing insights into their function. In this article, we will delve into the world of PDB files, exploring their significance, structure, and the wealth of knowledge they offer to the scientific community.</description></item><item><title>ABS File Extension - Delphi Absolute Database File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abs/</guid><description>What is an ABS file? A file with .abs extension is a database generated and used by Absolute database which is a database engine for the Delphi software development IDE. It replaced the Borland Database Engine (DBE) and is more compact, high-speed, robust and easy-to-use. ABS database compiles as part of the application EXE file, making your application faster and smaller. Data is stored in an ABS file in a structured, relational format.</description></item><item><title>ABX File Extension - WordPerfect Address Book File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abx/</guid><description>What is an ABX file? A .abx file is an address book exported from the WordPerfect Office software developed by Corel. WordPerfect was a word processing software developed by Corel Corporation and has been in use for quite some time. ABX files contained information about the contacts information extracted from the WordPerfect e-mail client. The exported contacts information can be transferred to other devices and used accordingly.
ABX File Format - More Information ABX files are stored in their own proprietary file format and the internal file format details of ABX files are not known.</description></item><item><title>4DL - 4th Dimension Database Log File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4dl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4dl/</guid><description>What is a 4DL file? A 4DL log file is utilized to record modifications made to a 4D database (.4DD) file. This file is stored alongside the database file and shares a similar filename. Its purpose is to accurately track and maintain a comprehensive record of the updates implemented within the database. A 4DD file, as compared to the 4DL file, is mainly associated with the 4th Dimensions by the 4D Inc.</description></item><item><title>BAK File Format - Act! Database Backup</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak-act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak-act/</guid><description>What is a BAK file? A .BAK file also serves as a database backup file generated by Swiftpage Act!, which is a customer relationship management (CRM) software. This file includes a duplicate of an Act! database (usually an .ADF file), effectively preserving essential data such as customer contacts, company details, group information, notes, historical records, and activity data stored within the database.
Swiftpage Act! Swiftpage Act! is a software application used for customer relationship management (CRM).</description></item><item><title>BAK File Format - Microsoft SQL Server Database Backup</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak-sqlserver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak-sqlserver/</guid><description>What is a BAK file? A &amp;ldquo;.bak&amp;rdquo; file, in the context of Microsoft SQL Server, is a backup file format used to store copies of a SQL Server database. These files contain a snapshot of the database at a specific point in time, including its schema, data, and other related information. They are generated using SQL Server&amp;rsquo;s built-in backup and restore functionality and serve several crucial purposes:
Data Recovery: .bak files provide a means to recover a database in case of data loss, corruption, or other issues.</description></item><item><title>FPT File Format - FoxPro Table Memo</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt-foxpro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt-foxpro/</guid><description>What is an FPT file? An &amp;ldquo;FPT&amp;rdquo; file is a file extension associated with the FoxPro database management system. In FoxPro, the FPT file contains memo fields associated with a table. Memo fields are used to store large amounts of text or binary data, such as lengthy descriptions, documents, or images, which may not fit in a regular database field.
Here is how the FoxPro file structure works:
DBF (Database File): This is the main file that contains the structured data in tabular format, including regular fields.</description></item><item><title>CHCK File - Microsoft Exchange Server Database Check File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/chck/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/chck/</guid><description>What is a CHCK File? A CHCK file is created as a result of health monitoring checks on Microsoft Exchange Server. It contains informaiton about the overall status and operationalization of the server&amp;rsquo;s database. Microsoft Exchange Server is used primarily as emailing server and lets you maintain your business contacts and calendars. Exchange server administrators use its EseUtil to check it&amp;rsquo;s database health.
CHCK File Format The internal file format of CHCK file is not known and there is no reference material available for reading/writing CHCK files.</description></item><item><title>CAF File - Cathy Catalog File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/caf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/caf/</guid><description>What is a CAF file? A CAF file is a catalog file created with the media organizing software tool, Cathy. It contains a list of indexed catalog that points to all the available media on externa devices sucha s flash disks and CDs. These catalog files help you maintain a clean list of media that is easily searchable and accessible. CAF files offer to search media by name, size, and date.</description></item><item><title>BC3 File - FIEBDC-3 Database File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bc3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bc3/</guid><description>What is a BC3 file? A BC3 file is a database file for storing information related to construction database exchange format. It was developed based on the Spanish standard construction database exchange format. A BC3 file stores information that has data records including details construction materials, cost of materials, and price of labor. The data cna be exchanged between other applications without converting the data to other formats.
BC3 File Format BC3 files are stored as binary files with details specified as per the FIEBDC standards.</description></item><item><title>PAN File Format - Panorama Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pan/</guid><description>What is a PAN file? A PAN file, in the context of Panorama, refers to a database file created by Panorama database software. Panorama is a database management system developed by ProVUE Development for macOS.
The PAN file extension is used to represent a Panorama database file, which stores structured data in a tabular format. These files can contain tables, records, fields, and data entries. Panorama provides tools for managing and manipulating data within these databases.</description></item><item><title>NMONEY File - Denaro Account File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nmoney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nmoney/</guid><description>What is an NMONEY file? An NMONEY file is a financial data storage database file that contains track record of financial transactions. It was developed by Nickvision and was used int he Nickvision Denaro software which is a personal financial software application. Data stored inside a NOMONEY file includes credit and debit transactions information to an account.
NOMONEY files can be opened with Github application.
About Denaro Software Denaro was initially developed by Nickvision as a product that was later converted to an open-source software app hosted on Github.</description></item><item><title>DXL File Format - Domino XML Language File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dxl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dxl/</guid><description>What is a DXL file? A DXL file is an XML based data storage file created for the enterprise level business collaboration software, Lotus Domino. It contains data related to a Lotus Domino database such as schemas, design elements, view, forms, documents, and the database data itself. XML is a universal file format that can be read by software applications written in any programming language. It is also human-readable and can be opened with any text editor.</description></item><item><title>FPT File Format - Alpha Five Table Memo File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt-alphafive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fpt-alphafive/</guid><description>What is an FPT file? An &amp;ldquo;Alpha Five Table Memo File&amp;rdquo; with an .fpt extension is associated with the Alpha Five database software. Alpha Five is a relational database management system that was used to create and manage databases, particularly in small to medium-sized businesses. The .fpt file format is used to store memo fields in a database table.
In the context of databases, a &amp;ldquo;memo field&amp;rdquo; typically refers to a field that can hold large amounts of text or binary data, such as lengthy notes, descriptions, or even files like images, documents, or other multimedia.</description></item><item><title>PDM File Format - PowerDesigner Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pdm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/pdm/</guid><description>What is a PDM file? A PowerDesigner Database File, also known as .pdm file, is a file format used by PowerDesigner software from SAP. PowerDesigner is a data modeling and design tool that is used to create and manage database models, business process models and other types of models.
The .pdm file contains database model created using PowerDesigner, including tables, relationships, keys, and other metadata related to the database structure. The file format is specific to PowerDesigner and can only be opened and edited using the PowerDesigner software.</description></item><item><title>RPD File Format - Roleplay Designer Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/rpd-roleplay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/rpd-roleplay/</guid><description>What is an RPD file? An &amp;ldquo;RPD&amp;rdquo; file is a specialized data file associated with Roleplay Designer, a collaborative e-learning development system tailored for crafting decision-based training modules. Within this system, these files store essential information that outlines the structure of the training scenarios that have been meticulously designed. Each &amp;ldquo;RPD&amp;rdquo; file holds a blueprint of the interactive elements, branching paths, and various decision points that make up the training experience.</description></item><item><title>XEM File Format - PowerDesigner Model definition File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/xem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/xem/</guid><description>What is a XEM file? XEM file is XML metadata interchange file that can be used to export metadata information about PowerDesigner model to external file. XEM file includes information about the model including entities, relationships, keys, diagrams and other relevant metadata. The file can be used to transfer or share model with other users or systems or to create a backup of the model for safekeeping.
To export PowerDesigner model to .</description></item><item><title>CRYPT12 File Format - WhatsApp Encrypted Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt12/</guid><description>What is a CRYPT12 file? A CRYPT12 file is a file format used by WhatsApp Messenger app to store encrypted message data on an Android device. The file is used to store all of the message data, including text, images, videos, and other attachments exchanged between WhatsApp users. The CRYPT12 file format is an encrypted database file that contains all of chat history for individual or group conversation in WhatsApp. The encryption key used to protect contents of CRYPT12 file is tied to specific device where the WhatsApp account is installed.</description></item><item><title>CRYPT14 File Format - WhatsApp Encrypted Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/crypt14/</guid><description>What is a CRYPT14 file? A CRYPT14 file is a type of file used by the messaging app WhatsApp to store encrypted message data on an Android device. When you use WhatsApp to send and receive messages, the app encrypts those messages so that they can&amp;rsquo;t be read by anyone who intercepts them. WhatsApp stores those encrypted messages in a database file on your Android device. The database file has a .</description></item><item><title>FIC File Format - WinDev HyperFileSQL Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fic/</guid><description>What is a FIC file? The FIC file in WinDev is a compiled version of a HyperFileSQL Database. The acronym FIC stands for &amp;ldquo;Fichier de Code&amp;rdquo; in French, which translates to &amp;ldquo;Code File&amp;rdquo; in English. In WINDEV, a FIC file is a compiled file that contains the executable code of a project. The file has the extension .fic and it is created when you compile a WINDEV project. Once a project is compiled into a FIC file, it can be distributed to users as an executable program or an installation package.</description></item><item><title>EPIM File Format - EssentialPIM Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/epim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/epim/</guid><description>What is an EPIM file? The .epim file extension is used by EssentialPIM, a personal information manager software that allows users to organize and manage their contacts, appointments, tasks, and notes. The .epim file is a database file that stores all the data entered into the program, including personal information, calendar events, and task lists. This file can be backed up, exported and imported to another EssentialPIM installation. The software is available for Windows, Android, and iOS platforms.</description></item><item><title>FDB File Format - Microsoft Dynamics NAV Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fdb/</guid><description>What is a FDB file? A .fdb file is a file extension used for the database files in Microsoft Dynamics NAV. The .fdb file extension stands for &amp;ldquo;Firebird Database File&amp;rdquo; and it is the file format used by the Firebird Database Management System, which is the underlying database engine used by Microsoft Dynamics NAV. The .fdb file contains all the data, tables, and structures of the NAV system, including financial data, inventory data, customer data, and more.</description></item><item><title>DSN File Format - Database Source Name File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dsn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dsn/</guid><description>What is a DSN file? DSN stands for &amp;ldquo;Data Source Name&amp;rdquo; and it is a file format used to store database connection information. DSN files are typically used in conjunction with ODBC (Open Database Connectivity) and allow for easy access to a specific database by providing the necessary information to connect to it, such as the server name, username, and password. The file is usually in plain text and can be created and edited using a text editor.</description></item><item><title>DB-WAL File Format - SQLite Database Write-Ahead Log File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db-wal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db-wal/</guid><description>What is a DB-WAL file? The file extension .db-wal is associated with SQLite, a popular open-source relational database management system. The WAL file format (short for Write-Ahead Log) is an alternative to the traditional rollback journal used by SQLite. It provides more concurrency control, allowing multiple processes to read the database at the same time, while still providing crash-recovery capabilities. The .db-wal file is used to store changes made to the database that have not yet been committed to the main database file (with .</description></item><item><title>DLIS File Format - Well Log Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dlis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dlis/</guid><description>What is a DLIS file? The .dlis file format is a standard file format for the storage and exchange of well log data in the oil and gas industry. The format was developed by the Logging Industry Data Standard (LIDS) committee and it stands for &amp;ldquo;Digital Log Information Standard.&amp;rdquo; The format is designed to store well log data in a way that is easy to read, write and exchange between different systems.</description></item><item><title>CAT File Format - Advanced Disk Catalog Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/cat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/cat/</guid><description>What is a CAT file? CAT file belongs to Advanced Disk Catalog software, developed by ElcomSoft Co. Ltd, Russian software company that develops various computer security and forensic software tools. Some of its products include software for password recovery, mobile device acquisition, and cloud extraction. The company was founded in 1990 and has offices in Russia and the United States. They are well known for their forensic software and overall their software is used by both private companies and government agencies to perform forensic analysis and investigations.</description></item><item><title>DBS File Format - SQLBase Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbs/</guid><description>What is a DBS file? A .dbs file, specifically those with the SQLBase extension, refers to a database file utilized by the SQLBase RDBMS. SQLBase, is a RDBMS developed by Gupta Technologies, it helps to manage and store relational databases. It stores data in a structured format, allowing for efficient querying and data manipulation. SQLBase is a popular RDBMS for small to medium-sized businesses and is used to manage and store large amounts of data in a variety of different types of applications.</description></item><item><title>ABCDDB File Format - Apple Address Book Contact List Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abcddb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/abcddb/</guid><description>What is an ABCDDB file? The file with extension .ABCDDB stands for Apple Address Book Contact List Database. It belongs to Address Book application also commonly known as Contacts. It is a built-in application and included with iOS and macOS operating systems. Contacts application enables users to save and organize information related to their contacts, including individuals, businesses, and organizations. This app allows users to keep track of details such as names, addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses, as well as to categorize their contacts into groups.</description></item><item><title>FMP12 File Format - FileMaker Pro 12 Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fmp12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fmp12/</guid><description>What is a FMP12 file? An FMP12 file is a database file created with FileMaker Pro 12 database development program. It contains the overall database structure (also known as database schema) along with the data inside it. The structure of an FMP12 file is based on tables where each table consists of a number of database fields having different data types. Some data types that are supported by FMP12 file format include text, custom forms, reports, datetime, blobs, and other database objects.</description></item><item><title>FMPSL File Format - FileMaker Pro 12 Snapshot Link File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fmpsl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fmpsl/</guid><description>What is an FMPSL file? An FMPSL file is a snapshot file of database created with FileMaker Pro 12. It stores the queried results from the database along with other information such as visual layout and visible information. The FMPSL file can be used to restore all this data in another instance of FileMaker Pro database. This file format was introduced with the launch of FileMaker Pro v 12. Prior to this version, the snapshot links were introduced as FPSL file format in FileMaker Pro v 11.</description></item><item><title>FP5 File Format - FileMaker Pro 5 Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fp5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fp5/</guid><description>What is a FP5 file? An FP5 file is a database file created with FileMaker Pro version 5 or 6. It stores user as well as organizational data in the form of records inside tables. FileMaker Pro is a database management system having support for Macintosh and Windows operating systems. FP5 is an older file format that was supported by the then available FileMaker Pro version. The latest FileMaker Pro database format is FMP12 that was introduced with the launch of FileMaker Pro v 12.</description></item><item><title>FP7 File Format - FileMaker Pro 7+ Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fp7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/fp7/</guid><description>What is a FP7 file? A file with .fp7 extension is a database file created with FileMaker Pro versions 7-11. It stores data in tables with records where each record contains one or more fields. FP7 files have the capability to store large data including personal databases data and organizational records. A more newer version of FileMaker Pro is FMP12 that was introduced with the launch of FileMake Pro version 12.</description></item><item><title>TE File Format - Textease CT Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/te/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/te/</guid><description>What is a TE file? A TE file is a database file created with the education application Textease that is based on Information and Communications Technology (ICT). It contains data that is stored inside multiple fields including forms, text, images, and other data. Textease Studio CT is no more developed and support for TE files is no longer available. TE files can be opened with Lightbox Education Textease Studio CT software.</description></item><item><title>TEACHER File Format - SMART Response Teacher Database File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/teacher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/teacher/</guid><description>What is a TEACHER file? A .TEACHER file is an educational settings file created by SMART Response software. It is used in educational setups to provide a complete environment of managing classroom information, class lists, schedules, holidays, student profiles, exams routine, and assessment results. SMART Response™ assessment software is installed on the computer that will be used to deliver SMART Response assessments.
TEACHER File Format TEACHER files are stored to disc in binary file format.</description></item><item><title>TRM File Format - Oracle Trace Map File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/trm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/trm/</guid><description>What is Oracle TRM file? A TRM file is a metadata file format used by Oracle 11g relational database management system (RDBMS). It is stored alongside the Oracle Trace files (.trc) and contains structural information about the trace file. The purpose of TRM file is to facilitate for searching and navigation the records using the metadata informaiton. Oracle software can be used to open TRM files.
TRM File Format TRM files are saved in Oracle&amp;rsquo;s proprietary file format and the TRM file format details are not available publicly.</description></item><item><title>ITW File Format- InTouch With Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/itw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/itw/</guid><description>What is a ITW file? An ITW file is a database file format used by the InTouch CRM application. It stores contents in InTouch&amp;rsquo;s Proprietary file format and its internal file format details are not available. ITW files store customized information for storing names, addresses that are further used for printing envelopes and labels. This informaiton is also used for sending emails, text messages, attractive e-newsletters, creating reusable templates, attachments and links.</description></item><item><title>GDB File Format - ESRI File Geodatabase File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/gdb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/gdb/</guid><description>What is a GDB file? ESRI file Geodatabase (FileGDB) is a collection of files in a folder on disc that hold related geospatial data such as feature datasets, feature classes and associated tables. It requires certain other files to be kept alongside the .gdb file in the same directory for it to work. Queries can be executed on the .gdb file to manage spatial as well as non-spatial data.
GDB File Format - More Information File geodatabases are made up of seven system tables plus user data.</description></item><item><title>ADN - Alpha Five Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adn/</guid><description>What is an ADN file? A file with .adn extension is a Microsoft Access blank template file that is utilized for creating Access project files with pre-stored settings. Microsoft Access project files are saved as ADP files and contains information such as Database Connection and project startup settings. ADN files exist for 2007 and 2010 versions of Microsoft Access. Microsoft Access supports other file formats such as MDB, ACCDB, ACCDC, ACCDE, and many more in addition to this ADN files.</description></item><item><title>ADP - Access Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adp/</guid><description>What is an ADP file? A file with .adp extension is a Microsoft Access project file that uses OLE DB component architecture to provide a direct and efficient connection to a Microsoft SQL Server database. Such files do not contain the actual tables, database diagrams or other database elements. ADP files can be created with Access 2007 and 2010. Files created with the earlier versions of Access can also be opened Access 2007 and 2010.</description></item><item><title>ACT! Lookup File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/alf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/alf/</guid><description>What is an ALF file? A file with .alf extension is an SQL Transaction log generated by ACT! CRM(Customer Relationship Management) software. It keeps record of activities between the ACT! and SQL, and is used to restore the ACT! database. ACT! CRM stores customer&amp;rsquo;s information such as name, email address, contact, business information, and relationship history. It stores this information in the ACT! ADF file that stores the data in tables for linking with other modules such as automatic information retrieval for an incoming call.</description></item><item><title>AQ - Ancestral Quest Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/aq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/aq/</guid><description>What is an AQ file? A file with .aq extension is a database file created with Ancestral Quest application by Incline Software, LC. It stores family tree information using the genealogical data entered by individuals using the free and premium version of the software. The database stores information such as the names, birthplaces, and relationships of family members. Ancestral Quest uses this information for linking and classifying information such as Pedigree, Descendants, Family and Timeline view.</description></item><item><title>ASK - askSam Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ask/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ask/</guid><description>What is an ASK file? A file with .ask extension is a database file created by askSam Systems, a personal information manager (PIM) application. These type of files are stored in dynamic folders and contain user data such as email messages, documents, text files, spreadsheets, addresses, and web pages. This allows askSam software to search them easily and retrieve the data for research purpose. The askSam software, though a simple Form based desktop application storing data in database, was popular for organizing and retrieving such data.</description></item><item><title>BTR - Btrieve Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/btr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/btr/</guid><description>What is a BTR file? A file with .btr extension is a database file created by Btrieve transactional database application. Unlike relational database management systems (RBMS), Btrieve is based on Indexed Sequential Access Method (ISAM), which is a way of storing data for fast retrieval. The BTR file stores a collection of records and is used to generate reports as per requirements. BTR files can be opened using Pervasive Btrieve Database Manager, Pervasive PSQL Maintenance Utility, and Legend Software BTRIEVE Viewer.</description></item><item><title>DACPAC - Data Tier AppliCation Package</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dacpac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dacpac/</guid><description>What is a DACPAC file? A file with .dacpac (stands for Data Tier AppliCation Package) extension is a database file, created with Microsoft SQL Server data tier application, that contains the database model for representation of database objects. As it contains the complete model of the database, it is used to restore a database from the details available in the model. DACPAC files are usually handed over to deployment teams for installation at customer&amp;rsquo;s premises to restore database.</description></item><item><title>ACCDR - Access Runtime Application</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdr/</guid><description>What is an ACCDR file? A file with .accdr extension is a Runtime database file created with Microsoft Access database that is used to created relational databases. It is created as readonly database file that can be opened for viewing only and cannot be edited. Microsoft Access also allows to create other type of database files such as ACCDB, ACCDC, and ACCDT. ACCDR files in reality are ACCDB files, but with no provision to add, update or delete data from these files.</description></item><item><title>ACCDW - Microsoft Access Database Link File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdw/</guid><description>What is an ACCDW file? A file wiht .accdw extension is a link file created with Microsoft Access and contains information about the link to download an Access database file i.e. ACCDB from SharePoint server. This lets the users to share database files that are hosted remotely. Opening the ACCDW file downloads the linked ACCDB file as a local copy on the user&amp;rsquo;s computer. The downloaded file is saved to the default download location and can be accessed by navigating to it.</description></item><item><title>ACCDC - Microsoft Access Signed Package</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdc/</guid><description>What is an ACCDC file? A file with .accdc extension is a database package created with Microsoft Access and contains a digitally-signed database. Such type of files are usually created by signing an existing Microsoft Access Database file (i.e. ACCDB) for sending over the internet to other users. The signing of these files are meant to ensure the trust worthiness of these files recevied by end users. Microsoft Access is a relational Database Management system that is used to create and publish databases for use in desktop as well as web-based content management systems.</description></item><item><title>ADB - Alpha Five Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adb/</guid><description>What is an ADB file? A file with .adb extension is a database file created with Alpha Five (now known as Alpha Anywhere). It contains the filenames of all tables and sets that are members of the project workspace. In addition, it contains the names of all the libraries that are incorporated in the workspace. Alpha Anywhere is an IDE used to develop web applications. In addition to ADB files, an Alpha Anywhere&amp;rsquo;s workspace may contain many files that starts table&amp;rsquo;s or set&amp;rsquo;s name, but have different file extensions.</description></item><item><title>ADE - Access Project Extension File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ade/</guid><description>What is an ADE file? A file with .ade extension is a Microsoft Access Project file that contains the compiled output of the information contained in the Microsoft Access ADP project file. Information in the Access project file, other than Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), is available in compiled form in ADE files. Data is stored in compressed format in these files to reduce the file size and improve performance in Access.</description></item><item><title>ADF - ACT! Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/adf/</guid><description>What is an ADF file? A file with .adf extension is a database file created with ACT CRM (Customer Relationship Management) software to store relationship data about customers. It stores information about customer&amp;rsquo;s name, email, contact, business information, and relationship history. CRM systems are more often integrated with call centres established by businesses to automatically retrieve user information for incoming calls. ADF files can be opened with SwiftPage ACT software on Windows OS.</description></item><item><title>ANB - Analyst's Notebook Chart</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/anb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/anb/</guid><description>What is an ANB file? A file with .anb extension is IBM i2 Analyst&amp;rsquo;s Notebook chart that contains relationship information between different data. As the name suggests, the Analyst&amp;rsquo;s Notebook software helps in linking the data, resulting in a more concise form of connectivity between difference pieces of information and providing intelligence output for analysis. This helps to identify and disrupt malicious activities such as criminal, cyber, and fraudulent threats. ANB files can be opened with IBM i2Analyst&amp;rsquo;s Notebook software.</description></item><item><title>TRC - SQL Server Trace File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/trc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/trc/</guid><description>What is a TRC file? A file with .trc extension contains the trace results of the activity of a Miscrosoft SQL server database. These files are created by a software SQL Server Profiler; usually packaged with Microsoft SQL Server software. The database administrators can analyze a sequence of database statements and can review the trace log if some kind of errors or warnings are suspected. These files are usually located in the typical LOG folder of MSSQL inside the Program Files directory on a Windows operating system.</description></item><item><title>WDB - SQL Server Trace File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/wdb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/wdb/</guid><description>What is a WDB file? A file with .wdb extension is actually a database file created by Microsoft Works which was used to perform functions like a database management system. The WDB file is similar as the Access Database (MDB) file, but less efficient and greater limitations. The WDB files can&amp;rsquo;t be opened by using Microsoft Access. However, you can open the WDB file in Microsoft Works and then export it to MDB file, in order the open a WDB file in MS Access.</description></item><item><title>4DB File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4db/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4db/</guid><description>What is a 4DB file? Database structure built using 4th Dimension, a software design program that comprises 4D code, interfaces, and resource information is known as 4DB. It is used in 4D&amp;rsquo;s integrative software design framework only during the development process. The files of 4DB are found both on desktop and mobile platforms and the operating system of Windows is also an option. The popularity rating of the major 4DB files is &amp;ldquo;Low&amp;rdquo; which means the 4DB files are usually present on a typical mobile or desktop device.</description></item><item><title>4DD - 4th Dimension Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4dd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/4dd/</guid><description>What is a 4DD file? 4DD files are mostly associated with the 4th Dimension by the 4D, Inc. This 4th Dimension item range includes various Windows and Mac OS technologies that may be utilized as standalone elements or as part of a completely functional, Browser, bridge database creation solution. The database fork is as follows:
The capacity fork is known as 4DR. It contains the real data that a 4D database architecture file refers to, and it can be compressed using the Compress file instruction in 4D Builder or 4D Client.</description></item><item><title>UDL - Microsoft Universal Data Link File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/udl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/udl/</guid><description>What is a UDL file? The file with .udl extension is called Microsoft Universal Data Link file; specifying connection attributes; used by Windows apps to establish a connection with the database. The UDL file contains the connection string for an OLE DB data source; with username and password and essential connection string properties. To avoid directly specifying the properties by hand in a connection string, a Data Link Properties dialog box can be used to save connection information in a .</description></item><item><title>DBC - CAN Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbc/</guid><description>What is a DBC file? The files with .dbc extension are also known as CAN database files. The DBC file is a simple text file that consists of information for decoding raw CAN bus data to physical values or in human readable form. The DBC file is introduced, because this is the very common way to manage identification and translation of the data. The DBC file type was developed to provide the means of record keeping as described in a CAN network.</description></item><item><title>CDB - Constant Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/cdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/cdb/</guid><description>What is a CDB file? The CDB files are used in mission-critical applications like email. The CDB stands for &amp;ldquo;constant database&amp;rdquo;, a fast, reliable and simple package for creating or reading constant databases. Database replacement is safe against system crashes. Users don&amp;rsquo;t have to pause during a rewrite. CDB performs as an associative array (on-disk), mapping keys to values, and enables multiple values to be stored in a single key.</description></item><item><title>DB File - Generic Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db/</guid><description>What is a DB file? A file with db extension is a generic database file to store data. There are no official specifications to be followed for such a database file. Data is organized in a structured format inside the file in the form tables, fields, data types, and field values. DB files can also be created by reading from data sheet files having data in rows and columns. Contents of DB files can further be exported to CSV and PDF file formats for reporting purpose.</description></item><item><title>DBF - dBase Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dbf/</guid><description>What is a DBF file? The file with .dbf extension is a database file used by a database management system application called dBASE. Inititally, the dBASE database was named as Project Vulcan; started by Wayne Ratliff in 1978. The DBF file type was introduced with dBASE II in 1983. It arranges multiple data records with Array type fields. The xBase database software which is pupular beacuse of its compatibility with a wide range of file formats; also supports the DBF files.</description></item><item><title>DAT - General Data File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dat/</guid><description>What is a DAT file? A file with .dat extension belongs to a generic file format. Usually these are niether encrypted nor binary, but they could be almost anything. Variety of applications are using the DAT files as references to certain operations in their respective program. So we can&amp;rsquo;t say that a specific software or program is responsible to create DAT files. These files are particularly accessed only by the application that created them.</description></item><item><title>LOG - Log File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/log/</guid><description>What is a LOG file? A file with .log extension contains the list of plain text with timestamp. Usually, certain activity detail is logged by the softwares or operating systems to help the developers or users to track what was happening at a certain time period. Users can edit these files very easily by using any text editors. Usually the error reports or login activities are logged by the operating systems, but other softwares or web servers also generate log files to track visitors and to monitor bandwidth usage.</description></item><item><title>SAV - SPSS Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sav/</guid><description>What is a SAV file? SAV file is a data file created by the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences(SPSS), which is an application widely used by market researchers, health researchers, survey companies, government, education researchers, marketing organizations, data miners for statistical analysis. The SAV saved in a proprietary binary format and consists of a dataset as well as a dictionary that represent the dataset, saves data in rows and columns.</description></item><item><title>SDF - SQL Server Compact Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sdf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sdf/</guid><description>What is an SDF file? A file with .sdf extension contains the Microsoft SQL Server Compact (SQL CE) database which is also known as a compact relational database; produced by Microsoft for the applications made for mobile devices and desktops. It supports both 32 and 64 bits operating system and the complete content of database is included in a single SDF file and can occupy more than 4GB disk space. For the security purpose, a .</description></item><item><title>ACCDB File Format - Microsoft Access 2007 Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdb/</guid><description>What is an ACCDB file? A file with .accdb extension is a Microsoft Access 2007 database file that stores users data in tables. It supports storing custom forms, SQL queries, and other data. ACCDB files replaced MDB files after Microsoft shifted to XML based file structure. ACCDB files can still be converted to MDB with old compatibility. However, the ACCDB are the widely used Access database file format now. Microsoft also supported additional features in ACCDB format such as possibility of storing file attachments, binary data, and multi-valued field support.</description></item><item><title>ACCDE File Format - Microsoft Access 2007 Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accde/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accde/</guid><description>What is an ACCDE file? A file with .accde extension is a Microsoft Access 2007 file format for creating Execute Only database files to protect custom database code. It compiles all VBA code into executable only so that it cannot be viewed or edited. ACCDE file format is replacement fo MDE file format that was used by earlier versions of Microsoft Access. ACCDE are ACCDB files in executable only mode and more compact due to absence of any source code.</description></item><item><title>ACCDT - Microsoft Access 2007 Template Database File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accdt/</guid><description>What is an ACCDT file? A file with .accdt extension is a Microsoft Access database template file that contains pre-defined database elements. These elements are a collection of structures that define a database applications such as database schemas for storing data, layout description for views of the data, and metadata describing the database. Being template files, ACCDT files can be used to create databases based on the template settings available in these.</description></item><item><title>ACCFT - Microsoft Access 2007 Database Field Template File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/accft/</guid><description>What is an ACCFT file? A file with .accft extension is a Microsoft Access template file that holds definition of field data types for the tables of a database. Microsoft Access is a desktop Relational Database Management System (RDBMS) that is used to create tables based databases, forms, queries and views. The ACCFT file can be used to define the data types for the table fields and database tables can be created using this template file as starting point.</description></item><item><title>BAK File Format - Database Backup File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bak/</guid><description>What is a BAK file? A file with .bak extension is usually a backup file that is used by different software tools to store backups of data. From database perspective, a BAK file is used by Microsoft SQL Server for storing the contents of a database. All the data and files associated with the database are stored in this file format to be retrieved in case the database may become corrupt or invalid for any reason.</description></item><item><title>BCP - SQL Server Bulk Copy File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bcp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/bcp/</guid><description>What is a BCP file? BCP (Bulk Copy Format) is Microsoft SQL Server&amp;rsquo;s technical data format that defines data structures to store different database data type values for import/export. The format fully defines the interpretation of each data column so that the set of values specified in the data file could be read. The BCP utility uses the BCP file format to read data from such a file and identify it.</description></item><item><title>DDL File Format - A Data Definition Language File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ddl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ddl/</guid><description>What is an DDL file? A file with .ddl extension is a Data Definition Language file that is used to define the schema of a database. It contains statements/commands for working with database structures such as tables, columns, records, and other fields. Commands in a DDL file are written in SQL and can perform operations such as create table in database, drop and update. A database schema is owned by its created and all the CRUD operations can be performed on it.</description></item><item><title>DTSX File Format - SQL Server DTS Settings File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dtsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/dtsx/</guid><description>What is a DTSX file? A file with .dtsx (Data Transformation Services Package XML) extension is a Data Transformation Services (DTS) file that is used by Microsoft SQL for referring to data migration steps/rules for transfer of data from one database to another. This includes the transformations and any optional processing steps that may be required during the data transfer between the originating and destination points. SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), a component of Microsoft SQL Server, uses the DTSX files to identify the steps for processing of data between database servers.</description></item><item><title>LDF - SQL Server Master Database File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ldf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ldf/</guid><description>What is a LDF file? A file with .ldf extension is a log file maintained by Microsoft SQL Server which is a relational database management system (RDBMS). All the transactions performed on primary database files (MDF)(such as insertion, update, deletion) are recorded in the LDF file. LDF files are critical components of any database. In case of a system failure, the log file is used to restore the database to a consistent state.</description></item><item><title>MDB File Format - A Microsoft Access Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/mdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/mdb/</guid><description>What is a MDB file? A file with .mdb extension is a Microsoft Access database file which is a Relational Database Management System (RDBMS). It stores data in database tables that are linked to each other via primary and foreign keys. The MDB file contains complete structure of the database tables, queries, stored procedures. MDB is the default file format for Microsoft Access 2003. The lateral versions of Microsoft Access use the ACCDB file formats which is the latest file format to date.</description></item><item><title>MDF File Format - SQL Server Master Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/mdf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/mdf/</guid><description>What is a MDF file? A file with .mdf extension is a Master Database File used by Microsoft SQL Server to store user data. It is of prime importance as all the data is stored in this file. The MDF file stores users data in relational databases in the form columns, rows, fields, indexes, views, and tables. SQL Server allows to set autogrow and autoshrink settings to have a positive impact on the performance of the database.</description></item><item><title>MYI File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/myi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/myi/</guid><description>What is an MYI File? MYI is also known as the MySQL MyISAM Index file. It is used to store indexes for the MyISAM table by MySQL. MySQL database index defines the structure of the table and contains the control mechanism to check the integrity of tables.
MYI File Format MYI file has two parts, the header, and the key values.
MYI Header The header contains information about options, file sizes, and keys.</description></item><item><title>NDF File Format - SQL Server Master Database File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ndf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/ndf/</guid><description>What is a NDF file? A file wiht .ndf extension is a secondary database file used by Microsoft SQL Server to store user data. NDF is secondary storage file because SQL server stores user specified data in primary storage file known as MDF. NDF data file is optional and is user-defined to manage data storage in case the primary MDF file uses all the allocated space. It is usually stored on separate disk and can spread to multiple storage devices.</description></item><item><title>NSF File Format - Lotus Notes Database Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nsf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/nsf/</guid><description>What is an NSF file? A file with .nsf (Notes Storage Facility) extension is a database file format used by the IBM Notes software, which was previously known as Lotus Notes. It defines the schema to store different kind of objects such like emails, appointments, documents, forms and views. All this information is contained in a single NSF file for business collaboration similar to a PST/OST file. Some of the applications that can open NSF files include IBM Lotus Notes and IBM Domino.</description></item><item><title>SQL File Format - A Structured Query Language Data File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sql/</guid><description>What is an SQL file? A file with .sql extension is a Structured Query Language (SQL) file that contains code to work with relational databases. It is used to write SQL statements for CRUD (Create, Read, Update, and Delete) operations on databases. SQL files are common while working with desktop as well as web-based databases. There are several alternatives to SQL such as Java Persistence Query Language (JPQL), LINQ, HTSQL, 4D QL, and several others.</description></item><item><title>DB3 File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/db3/</guid><description>What is a DB3 File? The DB3 file is a database file created by the SQLite software which is a lightweight, self-contained database program that creates databases using plain files; contains the database anatomy as well as data records; commonly used for retrieving or storing structured data using SQL. These files can be used in smart devices or where the record keeping or other data management required but on a low space environment.</description></item><item><title>SQLite File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sqlite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/database/sqlite/</guid><description>What is a SQLite File? A file with .sqlite extension is a lightweight SQL database file created with the SQLite software. It is a database in a file itself and implements a self-contained, full-featured, highly-reliable SQL database engine. SQLite database files can be used to share rich contents between systems by simple exchanging these files over the network. Almost all mobiles and computers use SQLite for storing and sharing of data, and is the choice of file format for cross-platform applications.</description></item></channel></rss>