<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Compression File Formats and APIs that can open and create archive files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Compression File Formats and APIs that can open and create archive files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SDOCX File - Samsung Notes Note - What is .sdocx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sdocx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sdocx/</guid><description>What is an SDOCX file? The SDOCX file format is associated with Samsung Notes which is used for creating and managing notes on Samsung Galaxy devices; SDOCX files are basically document files created within Samsung Notes; they store text, images, drawings, and other note elements; these files allow users to save formatted text, multimedia content (such as images and voice recordings), handwritten notes and sketches.
These files are only compatible with Samsung Notes and are commonly used on Samsung Galaxy devices and allow users to keep their notes organized; SDOCX files are essentially ZIP-compressed files that contain data files for each note element such as metadata, images and other attachments.</description></item><item><title>ZOO File - What is a .zoo file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zoo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zoo/</guid><description>What is a ZOO file? A .zoo file is an archive format that is used to compress and store files and directories; is similar to other archive formats like .zip, .tar, and .rar. The .zoo format was popular in early days of computing but has become less common in recent years. It was originally developed by Rahul Dhesi and was used primarily on Unix and DOS systems.
A .zoo file typically contains one or more files and directories that have been compressed and archived into single file.</description></item><item><title>PZZ File - What is a .pzz file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pzz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pzz/</guid><description>What is a PZZ file? A PZZ file is a compressed scene file generated using Poser, a software for designing and animating 3D figures. It contains data like 3D figures, props, lighting settings, camera angles, and motion sequences stored within it. Poser is a 3D computer graphics program that allows users to create and animate 3D characters and scenes. Poser typically uses its own file formats to save scenes and content.</description></item><item><title>CXARCHIVE File Format - CrossOver Bottle Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cxarchive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cxarchive/</guid><description>What is a CXARCHIVE file? In context of CrossOver, CXARCHIVE files are related to program&amp;rsquo;s functionality for running Windows programs on Mac and Linux. The .CXARCHIVE files contain data and settings for specific &amp;ldquo;bottles&amp;rdquo; which are virtual Windows environments where Windows applications can be installed and run.
CXARCHIVE File Key Points Here are some key points about .CXARCHIVE files created by CrossOver:
Purpose: .CXARCHIVE files are used to store data, configuration settings and installed Windows software within specific bottle.</description></item><item><title>BIN File Format - MacBinary Encoded File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bin/</guid><description>What is a BIN file? A BIN file, in the context of Macintosh computers, can refer to a file saved in the MacBinary format. MacBinary is a file format specifically designed for transferring Macintosh files over the internet, email, FTP, or portable media. The purpose of MacBinary is to preserve the complete file structure and attributes of Macintosh files, including both the data fork and resource fork, within a single file.</description></item><item><title>PAR File Format - Parchive Index File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/par/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/par/</guid><description>What is a PAR file? Within Parchive (PAR) archives, a .par file refers to an index file that contains a group of parity volumes or parity blocks. This index file is used for error detection and recovery purposes when one or more files in the archive are lost or damaged.
A Parchive archive typically consists of both the original data files and the corresponding parity volumes. Parity volumes are created using Reed-Solomon error correction algorithms.</description></item><item><title>CB7 File Format - Comic Book 7-Zip Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cb7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cb7/</guid><description>What is a CB7 file? A CB7 file refers to Comic Book 7-Zip Archive. It is compressed file format commonly used for storing and distributing comic book collections digitally. CB7 files are created using 7-Zip compression software, which is known for its high compression ratio.
How to open CB7 file? To open and extract the contents of CB7 file, you will need file archiver or comic book reader that supports the 7-Zip format.</description></item><item><title>CBA File Format - Comic Book Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cba/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cba/</guid><description>What is a CBA file? A Comic Book Archive (CBA) file, also known as Comic Book Archive or Comic Book Reader file, is a popular format used to store and distribute digital comic books. It typically contains collection of individual comic book pages or images bundled together in single file for easy organization and reading.
One of the common formats for creating Comic Book Archive files is the TAR (Tape Archive) format.</description></item><item><title>PWA File Format - Password Agent File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pwa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pwa/</guid><description>What is a PWA file? PWA file is related to Password Agent. The Password Agent software uses compressed and secure encrypted database file format to store password and other sensitive information. The specific file format used by Password Agent is proprietary and may not be publicly documented.
Password Agent typically saves its encrypted database as a single file with &amp;ldquo;.pwa&amp;rdquo; extension. This file contains all the password entries and other data securely encrypted to protect information from unauthorized access.</description></item><item><title>R2 File Format - WinRAR Multi-Volume Archive Part 2</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/r2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/r2/</guid><description>What is a R2 file? R2 file is related to WinRAR multi-volume archive, also known as split archive. It is a compressed file that has been split into multiple parts. This feature allows large archives to be divided into smaller segments, making it easier to transfer or store them on multiple disks or devices.
When you create multi-volume archive using WinRAR, the file is divided into separate volumes, each with its own file extension (such as .</description></item><item><title>SMPF File Format - Sprite Monkey Project</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/smpf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/smpf/</guid><description>What is a SMPF file? SMPF file is a compressed project file format utilized by Sprite Monkey, a lightweight application designed for efficient editing of sprite images. These files store both the sprite images themselves and the corresponding coordinate information specified within the user&amp;rsquo;s project.
Sprite Monkey Application Sprite Monkey is a lightweight application specifically designed for editing sprite images. It provides users with a convenient and efficient way to work with sprite graphics.</description></item><item><title>XIP File Format - MacOS Signed Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xip/</guid><description>What is a XIP file? A .xip file is a compressed archive format commonly used on macOS. It stands for &amp;ldquo;Xcode Archive&amp;rdquo; and it is primarily associated with Apple&amp;rsquo;s Xcode development environment.
The .xip file format is used to distribute software, particularly Xcode applications or updates in a compressed form. It combines the benefits of traditional archive file (such as .zip or .tar) with the added security of digital signature.</description></item><item><title>SQX File Format - SQX Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sqx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sqx/</guid><description>What is a SQX file? SQX file is typically associated with SQX Archiver which is file compression and archiving utility. SQX Archiver is alternative to other popular compression formats like ZIP or RAR.
SQX Archiver uses its own proprietary compression algorithm to reduce file sizes and create compressed archives. It offers various compression levels and options to balance compression efficiency and processing speed. The resulting &amp;ldquo;.sqx&amp;rdquo; file contains compressed data and can be extracted using SQX Archiver or compatible software.</description></item><item><title>CPIO File - Unix CPIO Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cpio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cpio/</guid><description>What is a CPIO file? A CPIO file is an archive file created in Unix&amp;rsquo;s Copy In Copy Out (CPIO) format. It is similar to the TAR file format other than that it is uncompressed. CPIO files can store device files, symbolic links and extended file attributes.
CPIO File Format A CPIO archive is created as a binary file that is not human-readable. It stores the collection of files and directories.</description></item><item><title>CIT File - Cite Report Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/cit/</guid><description>What is a CIT file? A CIT file is a project file generated by the citation-based investigative report writing application In8 Cite. It contains details of the incident in the form of a report and also has a catalog that contains support documentation and evidence cited in the report. Criminal investigators use CIT files for referencing criminal cases during their investigations.
CIT File Format CIT files are saved to disc in compressed file format.</description></item><item><title>APZ File - Autoplay Media Studio Exported Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/apz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/apz/</guid><description>What is an APZ file? An APZ file is a project file created with AutoPlay Media Studio, a software tool that allows for efficient development of applications. It is exported and saved in a compressed archive format. This format is convenient for several reasons. First, it reduces the size of the project file, making it easier to transfer to other systems or share with others. Second, the compressed file serves as a backup of the project, protecting against data loss or corruption.</description></item><item><title>ZST File - Zstandard Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zst/</guid><description>What is a ZST file? A ZST file is a compressed file that is generated with the Zstandard (zstd) compression algorithm. It is a compressed file that is created with lossless compression by the algorithm. ZST files can be used to compress different types of files such as databases, file systems, networks, and games. The Zstandard is governed by RFC 8878 that describes the overall compression mechanism, media type, and content encoding.</description></item><item><title>ECS File Format - Sony Ericsson Phone Backup File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ecs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ecs/</guid><description>What is an ECS File? An ECS file is a data backup file created by Sony Ericsson mobile phones. It is used to store a backup copy of user data, allowing for data recovery in case of device reset, data loss, or migration to a new phone. These files help users restore contacts, messages, settings, and other personal data.
ECS File Format &amp;amp; Structure ECS files are actually compressed ZIP archives, designed to reduce storage space and enable faster data transfers, especially over low-speed internet connections.</description></item><item><title>B1 File Format - B1 Compressed Archive File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/b1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/b1/</guid><description>What is a B1 file? A B1 file is a compressed archive file created with the free file compression utility B1 Free Archiver. It may contain one or more compressed files and folders that can be decompressed/expanded back to original form using the same B1 Free Archiver. B1 files are small in size due to compression and are easy to transfer over internet. B1 Free Archiver is cross platform and is available for Windows, Linux and MacOS platforms.</description></item><item><title>WHL File Format - Python Wheel Package File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/whl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/whl/</guid><description>What is a WHL file? A WHL (Wheel) file is a distribution package file saved in Python&amp;rsquo;s wheel format. It is a standard format installation of Python distributions and contains all the files and metadata required for installation. The WHL file also contains information about the Python versions and platforms supported by this wheel file. Similar to an MSI setup file, WHL file format is a ready-to-install format that allows running the installation package without building the source distribution.</description></item><item><title>BNDL File Format - Game Data Bundle File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bndl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bndl/</guid><description>What is a BNDL file? A BNDL file is a game data bundle archive file used by game Need for Speed: Most Wanted by Electronic Arts. It is a bundle file that stores game sounds and audio streams to be used for sound effects in the game. These sound effects are used when the player plays the game. BNDL is short for bundle.
BNDL File Format BNDL is proprietary file format used by Need for Speed game.</description></item><item><title>S00 File Format - ZipSplitter Part 1 File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/s00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/s00/</guid><description>What is a S00 file? A file with .s00 extension is the first part of a compressed file that is split using the ZipSplitter software. Splitting the files into such smaller files reduces the overall size of the compressed archive and makes it easy for transportation over the internet. Remaining parts of the split archive are named with extensions .S01, .S02 and so on. When the file is supposed to be extracted, the .</description></item><item><title>GZIP File Format - GNU Zipped Archive File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/gzip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/gzip/</guid><description>What is a GZIP file? A GZIP file is a compressed archive that is created with the standard gzip (GNU zip) compression algorithm. The compressed archive may contain multiple files including compressed files, directories and file stubs. Most of the Unix systems include the open source gzip (GNU Zip) compressor utility for compression/decompression of files. GZIP files can be opened with applications such as WinZip.
GZIP File Format - More Information GZIP uses the DEFLATE algorithm to compress files to archives.</description></item><item><title>SY_ File Format - Compressed SYS File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sy_/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sy_/</guid><description>What is a SY_ file? A SY_ file is a compressed .sys file that is used by software installers to reduce the size of the installation files packaged inside the installer. This reduces the overall size of the installer. SY_ files can be expanded using the Microsoft Expand command line utility that expands one or more compressed files.
SY_ File Format - More Information SY_ files are saved to disc as compressed binary files.</description></item><item><title>PET File Format - Puppy Linux Install Package File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pet/</guid><description>What is a Linux PET file? A PET file is an application installation package file created and used with PuppyLinux variant of Linux Operating System. It is created as a compressed TGZ file that reduces the file size of the compressed archive. The integrity of PET file format is ensured by the md5sum checksum that is appended to the end of the file for verification at the remote end. PET files can be extracted using the standard TGZ file extractor and WinRAR.</description></item><item><title>PF File Format - Stuffit Deluxe Private File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pf/</guid><description>What is a PF file? A PF file is a compressed and encrypted file that is created with Stuffit Deluxe software. It is password-protected file and can only be decrypted and decompressed by applying the password. Stuffit Deluxe is a well known file compressor and expander for Mac OS and can handle more than 30 file formats including RAR, 7zip, and other popular file formats. PF files can be opened with Stuffit Deluxe software.</description></item><item><title>PUP File Format - Puppy Linux DotPup Installer Package File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pup/</guid><description>What is a Linux PUP file? A Linux PUP file is an installation package used by Puppy Linux operating system. It executes as an installer and starts installing the package files. On Linux, it is often referred to as DotPup file and is similar to the .exe and .msi installer files used on Windows OS. The newer versions of Puppy Linux use .pet file format instead of the PUP file format.</description></item><item><title>NPK File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/npk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/npk/</guid><description>What is an NPK file? An NPK file is a software upgrade package file used by MikroTik routers for upgrade of router operating system. It comes as a compressed binary archive that is loaded in the router for installing software updates. Information contained inside an NPK files include networking information such as IP address and IP service, connectors information (ethernet interfaces and serial port), email setup, bridge configuration, and local user management.</description></item><item><title>FZPZ File Format - Fritzing Part File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/fzpz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/fzpz/</guid><description>What is a FZPZ file? An FZPZ file is a component/part used in an electronic circuit design created with the circuit prototyping and design application Fritzing. It is a compressed archive that contains an FZP file and four SVG images describing the overall part in Fritzing. The advantage of using these files is that users can share their FZPZ files with each from reusability point of view. The sharing of FZPZ parts help in integrating circuit parts to create larger PCB designs in a quick manner.</description></item><item><title>MINT File Format - Linux Mint Installer File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mint/</guid><description>What is a MINT file? A MINT file is an installation package file used by the Linux Mint distribution. It contains compressed source code files that are extracted and used to start the Linux Mint OS installation. Linux Mint OS has easy to use GUI (Graphical User Interface) and was the first one to have an elegant GUI design. MINT files are decompressed and stored in a temporary directory along with the installer package.</description></item><item><title>XPI - Cross-platform Installer Package File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xpi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xpi/</guid><description>What is an XPI file? An XPI file is an installation archive that is compressed to reduce the size of the file. It is used by Mozilla applications for installation of plugins and add-on files. It contains an installation script or a manifest at the root of the file along with a number of data files. An XPI file may contain themes, toolkit, or Firefox plugins that user can install to become part of the Firefox browser, Thunderbird or SeaMonkey.</description></item><item><title>TPSR File Format - TeamViewer Pilot Session Report File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tpsr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tpsr/</guid><description>What is a TPSR file? A TPSR is a connection protocol file used by the TeamViewer Assist AR (previously known as TeamViewer Pilot). Information stored in a TPSR file is stored in compressed ZIP file format. TPSR contains detailed history of TeamViewer connection between an expert and a technician for resolving issue and reviewal purpose. Information contained inside a TPSR file includes device type, name, Assist AR ID, Expert ID, date and time, and duration of the connection.</description></item><item><title>ZIP</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zipx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zipx/</guid><description>What is a ZIPX file? A ZIPX file is an extended version of the standard ZIP file that has been compressed using an advanced version of compression. This advanced compression method is developed by CorelWinZip that compresses all the files using the extended ZIPX format. ZIPX files are smaller in size than ZIP file format and makes data transfer over the internet more efficient. ZIPX files require WinZip to be installed on the system in order to open them.</description></item><item><title>P7Z File Format - S/MIME Compressed Email Message file</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/p7z/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/p7z/</guid><description>What is a P7Z file? A P7Z file is a compressed file that contains an email message in the S/MIME encryption standard. It was introduced by Microsoft Corporation and is categorized as Email related data file. P7Z files have application/pkcs7-mime media type. It contains one or more parts of a message that is compressed with zlib compression algorithm.
P7Z File Format - More Information The internal file format details of P7Z file format are not known.</description></item><item><title>PAGES File Format - What is an Apple PAGES file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pages/</guid><description>What is a PAGES file? A PAGES file is a word document created with Apple pages application which is a word processor developed by Apple Inc. Document saved as a PAGES file can contain a variety of different content types such as reports, posters, brochures, newsletter, and books. Apple PAGES also provides a number of different templates to create these document types. Contents of a PAGES file may contain text, images, graphs, tables and charts.</description></item><item><title>TZ - Zipped Tar Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tz/</guid><description>What is a TZ file? A TZ file is a TAR archive compressed with Unix compression algorithm. It is a combination of TAR archive and Z compressed files, and is a native compression format for Unix OS. TZ files can be opened using standard compression utilities such as WinZIP and WinRAR.
TZ File Format TZ files are saved as binary files using the UNIX compression algorithm. The use of Z files makes formatting, running and opening of files easier.</description></item><item><title>TGZ File - Gzipped Tar File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tgz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tgz/</guid><description>What is a TGZ file? A file with .tgz extension is a TAR archive file, comprising of multiple files and folders, that has been compressed using the Gnu Zip (gzip) compression software. A TAR file usually combines multiple files into a single file for backup or distribution over the internet. It is uncompress file until it is compressed using the gzip software after which it becomes the TGZ file. TGZ files, being compressed files, take less space on disc and are easily transferrable using internet via email.</description></item><item><title>VPK File - PlayStation Vita Application Package File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/vpk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/vpk/</guid><description>What is a VPK file? A file with .vpk extension is a compressed archive package file that is used to install third-party apps on Sony PlayStation Vita gaming console. These files can be installed only on jailbreak Vita PlayStation by HENkaku that enabled the PS Vita and PSTV to use customized user created content. A VPK archive file contains all the contents that make up the game including images such as PNG files, setting files such as .</description></item><item><title>WUX File - Compressed Wii U Disk Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/wux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/wux/</guid><description>What is a WUX file? A WUX file is the compressed version of a Wii U Disk Image WUD file. It is generated using the Wii U image compression tool to reduce the file size of WUD segmented files which are around 20 GB in size otherwise. This much large size game information files are reduced to around 2 GB in compressed WUX files that makes file transfer easier. WUX files can be opened and played with video game emulators such as Cemu.</description></item><item><title>XZ File - XZ Compressed Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xz/</guid><description>What is an XZ file? XZ is a compressed file format that utilizes the LZMA2 compression algorithm. It was designed as a replacement for the popular gzip and bzip2 formats, and offers a number of advantages over these older standards. XZ files are well-supported across many platforms, and can be decompressed quickly and easily. While they are not as common as ZIP or RAR files, XZ archives can be used to store large amounts of data without sacrificing compression quality.</description></item><item><title>Z Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/z/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/z/</guid><description>What is a Z file? A Z file is a category of files belonging to the UNIX Compressed data files. Compressed Unix files are the most popular and widely used extension type of the Z file. Z file makes formatting, running and opening of files easier as they are used to create small computer files that can be easily run on Linux/Unix operating systems. It is beneficial for users looking to save disk space, as by compressing large files into one Z file, users can save a lot of storage space and make their files more organized.</description></item><item><title>LZH File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzh/</guid><description>What is an LZH file? A file with .lzh and .lha extension usually relates to archive compression file format. This file format is the same as other file compression formats like ZIP, RAR, etc. The main purpose of these file formats is to reduce the size of the format for easily sending as well as to keep them together in compressed form. AS compare to other western companies LZH files are very popular in Japan and usually used for compressing video game data.</description></item><item><title>LZO File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzo/</guid><description>What is an LZO file? A file with .lzo extension is combined with file archiving features that can decrease all files size in the compressed file. All the compressed files may comprise one or more files or even groups of binders with several files of different kinds and dimensions. The size of a compressed file is smaller as compared to the joint size of all files and folders stored in an LZO compressed file.</description></item><item><title>MBW File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mbw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mbw/</guid><description>What is an MBW file? A file with .mbw extension is primarily associated with MBRWizard by Firesage Solutions. The Master Boot Record Wizard (MBRWizard) backs up your computer&amp;rsquo;s MBR and saves it to an MBW file that can be restored if needed. In addition to MBR and VBR (Volume Boot Record) copies, these files can contain GPT, user-defined sectors, or whole disk images. The MBR is a vital, 512-byte long record on your hard drive that allows your Operating System to boot.</description></item><item><title>MPQ File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mpq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mpq/</guid><description>What is an MPQ file? A file with .mpq extension mainly belongs to Blizzard Game by Blizzard Entertainment. The main specifications of any MPQ files are compressed graphics, sounds, level data, etc. If we talk about MPQ archives, these were first familiarized with the game Diablo and now very much popular in numerous games. The MPQ file is a big binary source container for level maps, and item mockups, music plus video, etc.</description></item><item><title>ALZ File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/alz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/alz/</guid><description>What is an ALZ file? A file with extension .alz is a compressed file, mainly related to ALZip by ESTsoft, Corp. The ALZ file format as a compressed file is also defined as ALZip archives. The developers have developed the file compression tool called ALZip and the same technology of encoding and compression is used by ALZ file format. This software is created by ESTsoft for private distribution under extensively used versions of Microsoft Windows.</description></item><item><title>BKF File Format - How to open .bkf file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bkf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bkf/</guid><description>What is a BKF file? A file with extension .bkf is related to the WindowsXP by Microsoft Corporation. All the operating systems that comprehend a catalog of files use a BKF file, that has been supported by the utility. If the data on a user&amp;rsquo;s computer becomes corrupt, overwritten, or removed, the BKF file is very useful to reestablish the information on the user&amp;rsquo;s system. There is also a specification of the BKF file, it is used by the Moto Racer computer game.</description></item><item><title>DMG - Apple Disk Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dmg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dmg/</guid><description>What is a DMG file? A file with a .dmg extension is an Apple Disk Image file and known as a Mac OS X Disk Image file. DMG file format is the most widely used disk image file intended to allocate applications and files among the Apple PCs. It’s very convenient to mount DMG files into a virtual drive or can use Apple Disk Utility software to open and view the content of DMG file format.</description></item><item><title>LQR File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lqr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lqr/</guid><description>What is an LQR file? The LQR file type is mainly related to a compressed archive file that covers one or more files that have been abridged in terms of file size for easy distribution via the Internet or through transferrable media like optical disks such as DVDs and CDs among other exterior data storage devices. Any file stored in LQR File format can be combined with compression provisions executed by a certain compression algorithm.</description></item><item><title>LZX File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzx/</guid><description>What is an LZX file? A file with .lzx extension was developed by Open Source, which is also known as an Amiga LZX Compressed File, for the associated software of Cabextract. The LZX files are commonly used by the users of the United States, running Windows 10 in their systems. Amiga LZX compressed file is classified as a compressed file combined with compression standards used in files saved in the LZX format.</description></item><item><title>PTK File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ptk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ptk/</guid><description>What is a PTK File? A PTK file is a data file format associated with Intuit Quicken, a leading personal finance management software. Quicken used .ptk files to facilitate financial tracking and data import from online banking services and financial institutions.
What is Quicken? Quicken is a personal finance software developed by Intuit (now owned by Quicken Inc.). It helps users manage budgets, track expenses, monitor investments, and import financial data from banks and other financial institutions.</description></item><item><title>SFG File - Synfig Studio Compressed Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sfg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sfg/</guid><description>What is a SFG file? An SFG file is the file format used by Synfig Studio to save project files. Synfig Studio is a free and open-source 2D animation software that allows users to create high-quality animations using bitmap and vector graphics. SFG file contains all of the information necessary to recreate an animation, including the layers, timing, and keyframes for each layer. It also includes any images or assets used in the project, as well as any audio tracks or other media.</description></item><item><title>SIFZ File Format - Synfig Studio Compressed Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sifz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sifz/</guid><description>What is a SIFZ file? A SIFZ file is a gzip compressed SIF file created by the open source 2d animations creation application Synfig Studio. It contains multiple graphical elements that make up for the animation. The overall animation contents are built using a combination of a canvas that is filled with shapes, brush or pencil strokes, and text. All these are arranged at their own positions, radius, tangent, angle, vertex, and width handles.</description></item><item><title>SIT File Format - StuffIt Archive File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sit/</guid><description>What is a SIT file? A SIT file is a compressed archive file created with Micro StuffIt software. This is the original standard file format that was introduced by StuffIt. SIT file format is commonly used on Macintosh systems, but now it is supported on both Windows and Macintosh platforms. StuffIt extended the SIT file format to SITX which offers more compression as compared to SIT files. SIT files can be opened with Smith Micro StuffIt Deluxe Mac 16 software.</description></item><item><title>SITX - StuffIt X Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sitx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/sitx/</guid><description>What is a SITX file? A file with .sitx extension is a compressed archive file created with StuffIt software. This format was introduced as an extension to the original standard Stuffit (.sit) file format and offers comparatively more compression to its predecessor. SITX files are more compact and occupy less space along with the support for 512-bit compression aimed for security. SITX files are recognized by their Internet media types as application/x-stuffitx and application/x-sitx with Uniform Type Identifier as com.</description></item><item><title>ACE - WinAce Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ace/</guid><description>What is an ACE file? A file with .ace extension is an ACE compressed file format that was developed by Marcel Lemke. It is the primary file format used by the WinAce compression application which was developed and available for Microsoft Windows platform only. The format was developed as an alternative to the ZIP file format but with discontinuation of the WinAce, the format couldn&amp;rsquo;t be carried out for long.</description></item><item><title>PEA - PeaZip Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pea/</guid><description>What is a PEA file? A file with .pea extension, acronym for Pack, Encrypt, and Authenticate, is a zip archive created with PeaZip archiving software application. It features compression and multiple volume output, and offers a flexible security model through Authenticated Encryption and cryptography. This provides both privacy and authentication of the data. The PeaZip utility is available as open-source engine that can be compiled for different OS as per requirements.</description></item><item><title>XAPK - Meta Package File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xapk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xapk/</guid><description>What is a XAPK file? A file with .xapk extension is a compressed package file that is used to install Android apps on mobile devices. It is a container file format that incorporates APK and additional associated files required for the installation. The other associated file is an OBB file that stores additional files such as graphics, media files, and app data that are required to keep the application running. XAPK files are not supported by Google Play and are used for distributing on third-party Android app download websites only.</description></item><item><title>DAR - Disk Archiver File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dar/</guid><description>What is a DAR file? A file with .dar extension is a compressed archive created using the DAR Disk archive. It can create backup/archive for full disk or a group of files. It was created to replace the TAR file format on UNIX OS and can be created as split archive files for large number of files. DAR archive supports option of deleting files from the system which are linked to the main files in the archive.</description></item><item><title>DEB - Bzip Compressed Tar Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/deb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/deb/</guid><description>What is a DEB file? A file with .deb extension is a Debian binary package file format available for distribution of software packages on Linux OS. It consists of two TAR archive files. The DPKG provides the mechanism to read and install the DEB packages. DEB packages can be installed using the APT package software management interface. DEB files have Internet Media Type as application/vnd.debian.binary-package.
DEB File Format A DEB file consists of two TAR archive files.</description></item><item><title>DZ - Dzip Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/dz/</guid><description>What is a DZ file? A file with .dz extension is a compressed archive created with the command line utility Dzip. It offers a higher compression ratio than other compression file formats. Dzip can also decompress compressed files and extraction of files is more quicker. Dzip comes with full integration for Windows shell to accept dragged files with the feature to avoid duplication of files when dragged to archive. Like RAR files, Dzip is able to create self-extracting executable files from its .</description></item><item><title>ICE - Bzip Compressed Tar Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/ice/</guid><description>What is an ICE file? A file with .ice extension is a compressed archive created with ICEOWS (Interface de Compression Ergonomique pour windOWS) software utility that was formerly known as ArjFolder. It provides excellent compression for reducing the size of text files. ICEOWS was developed originally with the support of Polish language, but now is available in other languages as well including English, French, German, Polish, Portuguese, Spanish, Italian, Chinese, Hebrew, Ukrainian, and Swedish.</description></item><item><title>ISO - Disk Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/iso/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/iso/</guid><description>What is an ISO file? A file with .iso extension is an uncompressed archive disk image file that represents the contents of entire data on an optical disc such as CD or DVD. Based on the ISO-9660 standard, the ISO image file format contains the disc data along with the filesystem information that is stored in it. The capability of ISO files to contain an exact replica of the content makes it the perfect file type for creating copies of CDs/DVDs and are mostly used to store bootable data for installation.</description></item><item><title>KGB - KGB Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/kgb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/kgb/</guid><description>What is a KGB file? A file with .kgb extension is a compressed archive file created with the KGB archiver software. KGB archiver uses the PAQ6 compression algorithm to compress the files into a KGB archive. KGB archiver has been discontinued and is no more used. KGB file format offers higher compression rates but at the cost of its minimum hardware requirements (recommend processor with 1,5GHz clock and 256MB of RAM) and extended compression/decompression time.</description></item><item><title>LBR - LU Library Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lbr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lbr/</guid><description>What is a LBR file? A file with .lbr extension is an archive file created with LU program and used on CP/M and DOS operating systems during 1980s. It is no longer being used and has been replaced by modern archiving file formats. The format does not compress the member files and acts as container archive for these. The archiving feature was mostly used for transfer of archived files over the internet.</description></item><item><title>LZ - Lzip Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lz/</guid><description>What is an LZ file? A file with .lz extension is a compressed archive file created with Lzip, which is a free command-line tool for compression. It supports concatenation to compress support files. LZ files have media type application/lzip and support higher compression rations than BZ2. LZ are based on the LZMA (Lempel-Ziv-Markov chain) algorithm and include a 32-bit CRC checksum and ident bytes for checking the integrity of the file.</description></item><item><title>LZ4 - LZ4 Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lz4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lz4/</guid><description>What is an LZ4 file? A file with .lz4 extension is a compressed archive file created with applications/utilities that support LZ4 compression. The LZ4 algorithm focuses on trade-off between speed and compression ratio. Compressed LZ4 archives can be created using the LZ4 command-line utility and can be decompressed using the same.
LZ4 File Format The LZ4 file format, based on the LZ4 compression algorithm, is independent of CPU type, operating system, file system and character set.</description></item><item><title>LZMA - LZMA Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/lzma/</guid><description>What is a LZMA file? A file with .lzma extension is a compressed archive file created using the LZMA (Lempel-Ziv-Markov chain Algorithm) compression method. These are mainly found/used on Unix operating system and are similar to other compression algorithms such as ZIP for minimising file size. LZMA is a legacy file format, which is being or has been replaced by the .xz format. The MIME type of the .lzma format is `application/x-lzma&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>OAR - OpenSimulator Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/oar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/oar/</guid><description>What is an OAR file? A file with .oar extension is an archive file used by the OpenSimulator application which is an open-source 3D application server for creating a virtual environment accessible to multi-users over the network. The OAR file format provides necessary asset data required to fully load the terrain, object textures, and inventories on a different system. OpenSimulator also has optional hypergrid that allows users to visit other OpenSimulator installations across the web.</description></item><item><title>PKG - Extensible Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pkg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/pkg/</guid><description>What is a PKG file? A file with .pkg extension is an installer package file that is used to install software on the macOS. In addition to to Macintosh computers, it is used on the iPhone as well. The builtin Apple installer application can be used to install the contents of a PKG file. A PKG file is similar to an MSI file used on Windows Operating System for installation of software.</description></item><item><title>RPM - Red Hat Package Manager File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rpm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rpm/</guid><description>What is a RPM file? A file with .rpm extension is a Red Hat Linux operating system package for installations of programs on Linux systems. The Red Hat Package Manager uses the RPM file format and is free and open-source package management system. Though RPM files can be used as it is for installation of programs, these can be converted to other package formats such as DEB using Debian program called Alien.</description></item><item><title>RTE - RTE Encoded File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rte/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rte/</guid><description>What is an RTE file? A file with .rte extension is an encoded file used to exchange copyrighted files. These are data files compressed and encoded to ensure the protection of such files. The compression standard of these RTE encoded files can vary and reduce the file size accordingly. The compression and encoding mechanism ensure the security of the copyright content. The RTE file format is reliably used for exchange of copyrighted content over the internet or through storage media devices like DVDs, CDs, USB flash drives, and external hard disk drives.</description></item><item><title>XAR - Extensible Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/xar/</guid><description>What is an XAR file? A file with .xar (Extensible Archive Format) extension is a UNIX archive that may be in compressed or non-compressed format. It is also used on Mac OS for installation of packages. XAR is open-source and been part of Mac OS X 10.5 for usage with Safari browser.
XAR File Format A XAR file has three main regions.
Header Table of Contents Heap XAR Header The XAR header is structured as follow.</description></item><item><title>ARC File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/arc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/arc/</guid><description>What is an ARC file? ARC is a lossless data compression and archival format developed by System Enhancement Associates (SEA). The file format and the application that creates it both are called ARC. ARC was very popular during the early days of the dial-up BBS as it combined the features of compression and archiving multiple files in the same file. ARC was later replaced by ZIP that offered better compression ratios.</description></item><item><title>ARJ File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/arj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/arj/</guid><description>What is an ARJ file? ARJ (Archived by Robert Jung) is a high efficiency compressed archive file developed by Robert K. Jung. ARJ was developed for DOS and early versions of Windows in the early 1990s. ARJ files are useful for backing up or sharing a large number of files as you do not have to keep track of all those files and there is only a single file to handle.</description></item><item><title>DAA - Direct Access Archive File Format - How to open DAA file</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/daa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/daa/</guid><description>What is a DAA file? DAA (Direct Access Archive) is a proprietary file format for disk image files developed by PowerISO Computing. DAA supports features like compression, password protection, and splitting into multiple volumes. The advantage of using DAA instead of ISO is that DAA files are smaller in size and can be split into multiple files. DAA is also secure to transfer as it can be encrypted and password-protected.</description></item><item><title>ZIM File Format - OpenZIM Archive File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zim/</guid><description>What is a ZIM file? Files with .zim extension are archives created to store Wiki content offline. It is considered as the most suitable open file format for storing Wikipedia on a USB. It stores site contents in a compact format. Its name comes from &amp;ldquo;Zeno IMproved&amp;rdquo; which was the earlier Zeno file format. ZIM is maintained by openZIM project which is sponsored by Wikimedia CH, and supported by the Wikimedia Foundation.</description></item><item><title>ZIP</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zip/</guid><description>What is a ZIP file? A file with .zip extension is an archive that can hold one or more files or directories. The archive can have compression applied to the included files in order to reduce the ZIP file size. ZIP file format was made public back in February 1989 by Phil Katz for achieving archiving of files and folders. The format was made part of PKZIP utility, created by PKWARE, Inc.</description></item><item><title>ZL - ZLIP Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/zl/</guid><description>What is a ZL file? A file with .zl extension is a ZLIP compressed file format that uses a variant of DEFLATE compression algorithm for compressing files. It is independent of CPU type, operating system, file system, and character set, and hence can be used for interchange of information. Technical specifications of ZLIP compression are available on the IETF site and can be referred from developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
ZL File Format A zlib stream has the following structure:</description></item><item><title>7Z - 7-ZIP Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/7z/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/7z/</guid><description>What is a 7Z file? 7z is an archiving format for compressing files and folders with a high compression ratio. It is based on Open Source architecture which makes it possible to use any compression and encryption algorithms. The format is now supported by a number of software applications such as 7-ZIP which is publicly available for download and usage to manipulate .7z files. Files with .7z extension have mime-type application/x-7z-compressed.</description></item><item><title>APK - What is an APK file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/apk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/apk/</guid><description>What is an APK file? A file with .apk extension is a Google Android app file that is used to install apps (applications) on the Android devices. It is created as an executable file using the official IDE Google Android Studio, and is uploaded to Google Play store to be downloaded and installed by end users. APK files can be generated and made available for manual installation as well prior to publishing to Google Play store.</description></item><item><title>B6Z - B6ZIP Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/b6z/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/b6z/</guid><description>What is a B6Z file? A file with .b6z extension is a compressed archive file created macOS software application B6Zip that is used to compress and decompress files. It is comparatively new archive format that allows higher compression ration. B6Z has open architecture and supports file sizes upto 900000 PB. It supports data compression, error recovery, and file spanning. The B6Zip utility software is available for free on MacOS to open different type of compressed files including B6Z.</description></item><item><title>BZ2 - Compressed File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bz2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/bz2/</guid><description>What is a BZ2 file? BZ2 are compressed files generated using the BZIP2 open source compression method, mostly on UNIX or Linux system. It is used for compression of a single file and is not meant for archiving of multiple files. This is in contrast to the TAR file format on the same platforms that archives multiple files into a single file but without compression. Files compressed as BZ2 can be decompressed with applications like WinZip.</description></item><item><title>GZ File Format - GNU Zipped Archive File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/gz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/gz/</guid><description>What is a GZ file? A GZ file is a compressed archive that is created using the standard gzip (GNU zip) compression algorithm. It may contain multiple compressed files, directories and file stubs. This format was initially developed to replace compression formats on UNIX systems. and is still one of the most common archive types on Linux systems. Applications such as WinZip can open GZ files to view its contents on both Windows and MacOS.</description></item><item><title>MPKG File Format - Meta Package File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mpkg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/mpkg/</guid><description>What is a MPKG file? A file with .mpkg extension is an archive installer file, mostly found on MacOS Operating Systems. It contains all required installation files of the application without the need to keep associated files separately. A single MPKG file can contain package files PKG as one of the installation files in addition to other files. MPKG files can not be opened with any general software and are executed automatically on MacOS using Apple Installer.</description></item><item><title>RAR</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/rar/</guid><description>What is a RAR file? Files with .rar extension are archive files that are created for storing information in compressed or normal form. RAR, which stands for Roshal ARchive file format, is a proprietary file format created by Eugene Roshal in 1995 who was a Russian software engineer. The format is used to archive files with different methods including various compression techniques. There are several application software available for Windows, Linux and MacOS for extraction of RAR files.</description></item><item><title>TAR - Unix Archive File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tar/</guid><description>What is a TAR file? Files with .tar extension are archives created with Unix-based utility for collecting one or more files. Multiple files are stored in an uncompressed format with the support of adding files as well as folders to the archive. TAR utility on Unix is Command based, but files hence created are supported by most file archiving systems on almost all operating systems. It was first created in 1979 by the AT&amp;amp;T Bell Laboratories and subsequent versions were published with the passage of time.</description></item><item><title>TBZ - Bzip Compressed Tar Archive</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tbz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tbz/</guid><description>What is a TBZ file? A file with .tbz extension is a compressed archive that uses BZIP compression for reducing the size of the content files. The TBZ files are actually UNIX TAR archived files that are compressed with BZIP then. The most recent second level compression is BZIP2 that replaced BZIP. TBZ file format is suitable for transferring large files. TBZ files can be opened/extracted using software applications such as 7-Zip, PeaZip, and jZip.</description></item><item><title>TGS - Telegram Animated Sticker File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tgs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/compression/tgs/</guid><description>What is a TGS file? A file with .tgs extension is an animated sticker file that was introduced by the cross-platform messaging service, Telegram. Animated stickers are used by messaging apps users to send more enhanced and lively content in messages unlike the static graphics that are still images. Telegram initially used the WEBP file format for still image stickers. The TGS file format can store animation data at higher resolutions and smaller file size as compared to the static WEBP stickers.</description></item></channel></rss>