<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Audio File Formats and APIs that can open and create Audio files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Audio File Formats and APIs that can open and create Audio files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PTX File - Pro Tools Session File - What is .ptx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ptx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ptx/</guid><description>What is a PTX file? The .ptx file format is specifically designed for Pro Tools, a popular digital audio workstation (DAW) software developed by Avid Technology. This file format is used for saving session information, including audio tracks, MIDI data, mixer settings, edits, and effects used in a recording project.
Here are key features about PTX file.
Session Data: .ptx files store all data related to a Pro Tools session, like track settings, audio clip arrangement, timeline edits, and mixing configurations.</description></item><item><title>MUS File - Finale Notation Legacy File - What is .mus file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mus/</guid><description>What is a MUS file? The &amp;lsquo;.mus&amp;rsquo; file extension represents the proprietary Finale Notation File format, a legacy container specifically for musical scores created within MakeMusic&amp;rsquo;s industry-leading Finale software. As the native file type for this powerful music notation program, the &amp;lsquo;.mus&amp;rsquo; format enables composers, arrangers, and musicians to comprehensively save their work, facilitating detailed creation, editing, and printing of sheet music. Within its structure, a &amp;lsquo;.mus&amp;rsquo; file meticulously stores all essential elements of a composition, including individual notes, rests, dynamic tempo markings, key and time signatures, and a wide array of other critical musical annotations.</description></item><item><title>MUS File - Minecraft Music File - What is .mus file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mus-minecraft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mus-minecraft/</guid><description>What is a MUS file? The .mus file format in the context of Minecraft typically refers to a file used for music or sound effects within the game. Minecraft&amp;rsquo;s music files are often stored in formats such as .ogg, but older versions or specific mods might use .mus files. These files can contain music or sounds that enhance the game&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere.
What is Minecraft? Minecraft is a popular sandbox video game that allows players to explore, build, and survive in block-based, procedurally generated worlds.</description></item><item><title>QCP File - PureVoice Audio File - What is .qcp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/qcp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/qcp/</guid><description>What is a QCP file? The QCP file format is associated with PureVoice Audio, developed by Qualcomm for efficient voice transmission. These .qcp files typically store audio data optimized for speech rather than general sounds or music.
The key features of QCP file format include
It was originally created to enhance the quality of voice communication on mobile devices. PureVoice codec prioritizes clarity in spoken language rather than high-fidelity music or sound effects.</description></item><item><title>SESX File - Audition Session - What is .sesx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sesx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sesx/</guid><description>What is an SESX file? An SESX file is a session file created by Adobe Audition, a powerful audio production application. Unlike traditional audio files, .sesx files store a multitrack audio project in an XML format. This includes essential information about mixing, effects settings, and the organization of audio tracks within the session. Importantly, .sesx files do not contain the actual audio data. Instead, they save the pathnames to the audio files used in your project, allowing Audition to access the audio without embedding it in the session file.</description></item><item><title>PKF File - Adobe Audition Peak File - What is .pkf file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/pkf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/pkf/</guid><description>What is a PKF file? The PKF file format is commonly associated with Adobe Audition, a professional audio editing software. It stands for &amp;ldquo;Peak&amp;rdquo; file, and it is generated by Audition to store information about audio peak levels. This information is used for various purposes, including waveform display, audio editing, and processing.
PKF File Format - More Information When you import audio files into Adobe Audition, it analyzes audio and generates corresponding .</description></item><item><title>MUSX File - Finale Notation File - What is .musx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/musx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/musx/</guid><description>What is a MUSX file? The &amp;lsquo;.musx&amp;rsquo; file is the proprietary project format for MakeMusic Finale, the industry-standard music notation software. Functioning as a comprehensive digital score, a MUSX file encapsulates the complete blueprint of a musical piece—including every note, rhythmic value, dynamic marking, and articulation symbol. Beyond the raw musical data, this versatile format also stores essential metadata such as the work&amp;rsquo;s title, the composer&amp;rsquo;s name, and copyright details, making it a self-contained repository for both the artistic and administrative aspects of a composition.</description></item><item><title>TG File - TuxGuitar Document - What is .tg file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/tg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/tg/</guid><description>What is a TG file? A TG file is a guitar tablature document created by TuxGuitar. It contains both musical score and guitar tablature. Guitar tablature is a form of musical notation that represents finger positions on instrument&amp;rsquo;s fretboard.
About TuxGuitar TuxGuitar is an open-source, cross-platform music notation program that allows users to create, edit and play back musical scores. It is similar to popular commercial programs like Guitar Pro and Power Tab.</description></item><item><title>GP File - Guitar Pro 7 File - What is .gp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/gp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/gp/</guid><description>What is a GP file? A file with &amp;ldquo;.gp&amp;rdquo; extension typically refers to a Guitar Pro file. Guitar Pro is a software application developed by Arobas Music that allows musicians to create, edit and play back guitar tablature and musical scores. The &amp;ldquo;.gp&amp;rdquo; file format is specific to Guitar Pro and contains musical notation, tablature and other information related to a musical composition.
Guitar Pro files store musical scores for multiple instruments.</description></item><item><title>ENC File - Encore Musical Notation - What is an .enc file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/enc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/enc/</guid><description>What is an ENC file? An ENC file could also represent a musical composition crafted using Passport Music Software&amp;rsquo;s Encore, a scorewriting application compatible with both Windows and macOS platforms; within this file, you will discover a rich tapestry of musical notation, encompassing elements like notes, measures, time signatures and key signatures. Additionally, the file encapsulates essential details such as score&amp;rsquo;s title and information about composer who brought musical piece to life.</description></item><item><title>CDR File Format - Raw CD Audio Data, Two Formats, One Extension</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/cdr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/cdr/</guid><description>What is a CDR file? A file with a .CDR extension containing &amp;ldquo;Raw CD Audio Data&amp;rdquo; typically holds digital information extracted directly from the source tracks of an audio CD. This &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; designation signifies that the data is unprocessed, preserving the original binary structure as it exists on the physical disc. The content includes the precise audio samples alongside subcode information like track timings. These .CDR files are not designed for direct playback in standard media players.</description></item><item><title>CAF File Format - Core Audio File &amp; Versatile Audio Container</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/caf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/caf/</guid><description>What is a CAF file? The .CAF file, an acronym for Core Audio Format, is a versatile audio container developed by Apple Inc. Engineered as a modern and flexible solution for storing digital audio, it sees common use across Apple&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, including macOS and iOS devices. A key strength of the Core Audio Format is its remarkable adaptability; it can house a wide variety of audio data types within a single file.</description></item><item><title>IT File Format - Impulse Tracker Module, The Powerhouse of Tracker Music</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/it/</guid><description>What is an IT file? Originating in the mid-1990s from developer Jeffrey Lim, the IT file format is the native module file format for the influential Impulse Tracker music software. These versatile files function as comprehensive digital containers, housing not just audio but the entire musical blueprint—including intricate musical patterns, detailed sample data, custom instrument settings, and essential sequencing information. This unique structure empowers composers to create rich, layered compositions within a single, highly efficient IT file.</description></item><item><title>STY File Format - Yamaha or Korg Keyboard Style</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sty/</guid><description>What is a STY file? STY file typically refers to a file format used by Yamaha electronic keyboards and synthesizers. Yamaha &amp;ldquo;.sty&amp;rdquo; files contain style data defining the rhythm, accompaniment patterns, and other musical elements used by instrument, are used to enhance the playback of MIDI files by providing pre-programmed styles and arrangements.
To use a .sty file with a Yamaha keyboard or synthesizer, you typically transfer the file to instrument using a USB connection or a memory card.</description></item><item><title>MSCZ File Format - MuseScore Compressed Score File, Music Producers' Choice</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mscz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mscz/</guid><description>What is a MSCZ file? The .mscz file format is the proprietary and default project file for MuseScore, the widely-used open-source music notation software. As the core file type for this powerful application, MuseScore relies on the .mscz extension to save and store musical compositions in their entirety. This comprehensive container holds every detail of a score, encapsulating all musical notations, symbols, and layout settings for a specific piece. Within a single .</description></item><item><title>AIF File Format - Audio Interchange File Format, A Lossless Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aif/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aif/</guid><description>What is an AIF file? A staple in professional audio production, the Audio Interchange File Format (AIF) was pioneered by Apple Inc. as a solution for storing high-fidelity, uncompressed audio data. Renowned for its exceptional sound quality, the AIF format is a top choice for musicians, sound engineers, and audio professionals.
Its core strength lies in its use of PCM (Pulse Code Modulation), a method that captures the original audio waveform directly without any data compression.</description></item><item><title>M4R File Format - Complete Guide to iPhone Ringtone File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4r/</guid><description>What is a M4R file? Unlock the secret to custom iPhone sounds with the M4R file format, a specialized audio type dedicated exclusively to iOS ringtones. At its core, an M4R file is a standard MPEG-4 AAC audio file, but its unique .m4r extension acts as a direct signal to Apple&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, designating it as a ringtone rather than a standard song. You can craft these custom ringtones using a variety of audio editing and conversion software.</description></item><item><title>WPROJ File Format - Wwise Project File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wproj/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wproj/</guid><description>What is a WPROJ file? A file with the .WPROJ file extension is typically a Wwise Project file. Wwise is a software application developed by Audiokinetic that is used for sound design and audio integration in video games and other interactive media. A Wwise Project file is a project file created by Wwise that stores information related to sound assets, sound banks, mix settings, and other project-specific data. The file is used to manage and organize the audio assets and settings for a specific project.</description></item><item><title>EFS File Format - Ensoniq SQ-80 File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/efs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/efs/</guid><description>What is an EFS file? The EFS Ensoniq SQ-80 file is a specialized format dedicated to the iconic Ensoniq SQ-80 synthesizer, a revered analog/digital hybrid from the 1980s. Renowned for its powerful and unique sonic character, the SQ-80 achieved its distinctive sound by masterfully blending digital wavetable synthesis with analog filtering. This synthesis method utilized short digital waveforms to construct rich, complex textures. The term EFS itself refers to the Ensoniq File System, the proprietary system used by these synthesizers to organize and manage sound data.</description></item><item><title>RIP File Format - Hit'n'Mix Audio Mashup File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/rip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/rip/</guid><description>What is a RIP file? The RIP file format is a proprietary file format used by the Hit&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Mix audio editing software. RIP files are project files that contain audio tracks and other project-related data, such as edits, effects, and other settings. These files are not audio files themselves, but rather they contain references to the audio data stored in other files.
The Hit&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Mix software allows users to &amp;ldquo;rip&amp;rdquo; individual components from audio files, such as vocals, drums, or melodies, and manipulate them independently.</description></item><item><title>EC3 File Format - Create &amp; Open Enhanced Audio Codec 3 File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ec3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ec3/</guid><description>What is an EC3 file? Experience immersive sound with the EC3 file format (Enhanced AC-3), the advanced audio coding standard developed by Dolby Laboratories. Serving as a powerful extension of the foundational AC-3 (Dolby Digital) codec, EC3 is engineered to deliver superior, high-fidelity audio for today&amp;rsquo;s premium entertainment. It elevates movies, television broadcasts, and digital streaming media with stunning clarity and depth.
Some characteristics of the EC3 (Enhanced AC-3) audio format include:</description></item><item><title>MTM File Format - MultiTracker Module, Audio Channels of MTM</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mtm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mtm/</guid><description>What is a MTM file? The MTM file extension, an acronym for MultiTracker Module, represents a specialized audio file format historically used for dynamic music playback in video games and multimedia applications. Functioning as a container, a single MTM file bundles a collection of individual music tracks or patterns that can be triggered independently or seamlessly combined to form a complete, interactive composition. This structure was ideal for creating adaptive soundtracks that could respond to in-game events.</description></item><item><title>FLP File Format - FL Studio Project File for Music Production</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/flp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/flp/</guid><description>What is a FLP file? The FLP file extension represents the native project format for FL Studio, the powerful digital audio workstation (DAW) from Image-Line. These FLP files act as comprehensive containers, storing the entire blueprint of a music production project. Within a single FLP file, producers save all their creative work, including musical patterns, sequence arrangements, audio samples, virtual instrument settings, effect chains, and automation data. This makes the format essential for both saving work-in-progress and collaborating with other FL Studio users.</description></item><item><title>MUI File Format - Myriad User Instrument File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mui/</guid><description>What is a MUI file? The acronym MUI in this context refers to Myriad User Instrument, a specialized and proprietary file format integral to the Harmony Assistant software. Developed by Myriad Software, Harmony Assistant is a comprehensive application for music notation, composition, and sequencing. The primary function of an MUI file is to act as a container for digital instrument sounds, housing detailed sample data and synthesis parameters that define the timbre and behavior of a virtual instrument.</description></item><item><title>SF2 File Format - SoundFont 2 Sound Bank</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sf2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sf2/</guid><description>What is a SF2 file? The .SF2 file extension is most commonly associated with SoundFont 2 files, which are a type of sample-based sound format used in digital music production. SoundFont 2 files contain collections of instrument sounds and samples that can be loaded and played back using software synthesizers and sequencers.
A sample-based sound format is a type of audio format that is created by recording and storing short snippets or &amp;ldquo;samples&amp;rdquo; of real-world sounds, such as instruments or vocalizations.</description></item><item><title>WEBA - What is a WebA file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/weba/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/weba/</guid><description>What is a WEBA file? A WEBA is an audio file format that only contains the audio extracted from WEBM video files. It is compressed using the OGG Vorbis compression codec, resulting in a reduced file size. This makes transmission of WEBA files easier over the internet. The use of OGG Vorbis compression lets WEBA files to be supported in most media players.
Did you know? You can become a contributor at FileFormat.</description></item><item><title>WFP File Format - WaveFront Program File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wfp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wfp/</guid><description>What is a WFP file? A WFP file was a patch file used by the Turtle Beach WaveFront synthesizer cards. It is no more used as Turtle Beach has stopped producing sound cards and synthesizers. The WFP file contains a single program or patch that can be applied to the synthesizer. WFP files can also be converted to MP4 file format.
WFP File Format The internal file format details of WF files are not available.</description></item><item><title>MXL File Format - Compressed MusicXML File, Compare MXL vs. Proprietary Formats</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mxl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mxl/</guid><description>What is an MXL file? An MXL file is the compressed form of MusicXML file format that is an open standard format for exchange of digital sheet music. Plain text MusicXML files are large in size and the use of such files as a sheet distribution format was affected with the large file size. This issues was treated with MusicXML 2.0 by introducing the MXL file format that compresses the files enough to reduce the file size similar to that of original MIDI files.</description></item><item><title>NSA File Format - NullSoft Audio File, Compare NSA vs. DSS</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/nsa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/nsa/</guid><description>What is a NSA file? An NSA (NullSoft Streaming Audio) file is a streaming audio format developed by NullSoft for streaming audio over the internet. NullSoft also developed Winamp media player for streaming and playback of audio and video files. The NSA file format uses audio compression algorithms introduced and developed by NullSoft. NullSoft also has developed the NSV file format for streaming videos over the internet.
NSA File Format NSA files are streamed online using the NullSoft audio container file format.</description></item><item><title>M3U8 File Format - The Engine of Modern Video Streaming</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m3u8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m3u8/</guid><description>What is a M3U8 file? The M3U8 file format is used by audio and video playback programs to store playlists. The playlist consists of an Internet web path or URL, along with information about each track in the list (playtime duration). M3U8 files use UTF-8 character encoding as compared to M3U file types. M3U8 files can be opened using applications like VideoLAN VLC media player.
M3U8 File Format M3U8 files are stored to disc as text files and are a popular way to store playlists for music playback apps like Spotify, Apple Music and TIDAL.</description></item><item><title>VQF - TwinVQ Audio File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/vqf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/vqf/</guid><description>What is a VQF file? The .vqf file extension is used for TwinVQ files. The TwinVQ is an audio format which was developed by Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corporation and marketed by Yamaha by using the SoundVQ as name. It was announced by the developers that TwinVQ files are about 30 to 35% smaller than MP3 files of a certain quality. The higher quality is achieved at the cost of higher processor usage.</description></item><item><title>VOC - Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/voc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/voc/</guid><description>What is a VOC file? The VOC audio files are created by a voice récordee named RCA digital voice recorder. The interviews and lectures are recorded through this device. These files are portable and can be shared through the USB port. The VOC files are compatible with Windows operating systems. These VOC files can be converted into other file formats which are more popular such as MP3.
The data included in these files can be in raw form or container format.</description></item><item><title>VOX - Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/vox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/vox/</guid><description>What is a VOX file? At a low sampling rate, the VOX files are specified to store digitized voice data. These are audio files that are commonly used in the applications specified for telephonic communications. This type of file format uses an algorithm of lossy compression which has an optimization for voice.
Commonly used in speech applications the VOX files contain pre-recorded prompts of voice. This type of file format is also converted into other more popular formats.</description></item><item><title>ACT - File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/act/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/act/</guid><description>What is an ACT file? The .act file extension represents several specialized and unrelated formats, making its identification crucial. Primarily, in the Adobe ecosystem, an ACT file is an Adobe Color Table (or Color Lookup Table), a database format used in Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator. This type of ACT stores a predefined set of colors, allowing designers to add or remove specific swatches when saving images for online use. This control is essential for optimizing the balance between visual quality and smaller file sizes for web publishing.</description></item><item><title>MMF - Mobile Music File Format(The Sound of a Mobile Era)</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mmf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mmf/</guid><description>What is an MMF file? The MMF file format, identified by the .mmf extension, is a versatile multimedia container historically used in mobile devices. Developed by Yamaha, MMF stands for Mobile Music File and is the file-level component of the broader SMAF (Synthetic-music Mobile Application Format) standard. These files were engineered to store a variety of content, including system ringtones, alert sounds, and could even package basic graphics and text for a synchronized display.</description></item><item><title>RF64 - 8Bit Sampled Voice File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/rf64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/rf64/</guid><description>What is an RF64 file? The RF64 format has a maximum file size of 4 GB and is compatible with BWF. In Winamp, this format is called RIFF64 broadcast wave. Winamp is a multimedia playback software for Microsoft Windows. The RF64 store&amp;rsquo;s audio data in RIFF64 in broadcast wave format. Being a multichannel audio file format the RF64 is primarily designed to remove size restrictions on other file formats allowing users to store files over 4GB.</description></item><item><title>GSM - Global System for Mobile Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/gsm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/gsm/</guid><description>What is a GSM file? The GSM file format, more technically known as GSM 06.10 or Full Rate, represents a specialized audio compression standard engineered explicitly for crystal-clear human speech. Originally developed as the core codec for the groundbreaking Global System for Mobile Communications (GSM) network, this technology was instrumental in popularizing mobile phones worldwide. As an audio file type, its primary association is with Global System for Mobile Audio Format Files.</description></item><item><title>8SVX - 8Bit Sampled Voice File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/8svx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/8svx/</guid><description>What is an 8SVX file? Developed by Electronic Arts, the 8SVX file format is a digital audio standard specifically for Amiga computers, functioning as a dedicated data subtype of the broader IFF container format. It stores 8-bit audio samples within distinct data chunks, while separate descriptor chunks contain all the crucial metadata about the audio stream. While Amiga computer systems are now rarely in active use, the primary modern application of 8SVX files is the preservation and playback of classic video game music and retro audio samples from that era.</description></item><item><title>MOD - Music Module File, Computer Music &amp; Demoscene Culture</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mod/</guid><description>What is an MOD file? The MOD file format, recognized by its .mod extension, is a landmark in digital audio history. It was originally developed as the Amiga module format by Karsten Obarski and launched with the revolutionary Ultimate Soundtracker software for the Commodore Amiga. Functioning as a music module file, it operates on a principle similar to a MIDI file but with a critical difference: it is a self-contained package that includes both the note patterns and the actual sound samples for each instrument.</description></item><item><title>WV - WavPack Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wv/</guid><description>What is a WV file? The WV files are audio files that are compressed using WavPack Hybrid compression. Both lossless and lossy compressions are supported by WavPack. This audio format offers unparalleled functionality. WV files contain digital audios which are being compressed by WavPack Audio.
The lossless mode is perfect for archiving audio data and compression of data without any degradation and loss of a bit are abilities of Wavpack. It has an open-source library interface along with an unrestricted license.</description></item><item><title>AA - Audible AudioBook File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aa/</guid><description>What is an AA file? The .aa file extension specifies a proprietary digital audio format developed exclusively for Audible audiobooks. These files are specifically engineered to store spoken-word audio content, featuring integrated support for essential navigation features like chapter markers and bookmarks. The data within an AA file consists of a raw audio stream encoded in a specialized audio format. Crucially, every AA file is protected with Digital Rights Management (DRM) encryption, securing the audio clips and ensuring that the content is used only by authorized listeners.</description></item><item><title>MP2 - MPEG Layer 2 Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mp2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mp2/</guid><description>What is an MP2 file? An MP2 file, also widely known as an MPA file, is an audio format compressed using MPEG-1 or MPEG-2 Audio Layer II. This lossy audio compression standard was formally defined by ISO/IEC 11172-3, which also established the MPEG-1 Audio Layer I and the vastly more popular MPEG-1 Audio Layer III (MP3). The primary goal of the MP2 format, like its counterparts, was to significantly reduce audio file size.</description></item><item><title>WPL - Windows Media Player Playlist File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wpl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wpl/</guid><description>What is a WPL file? A file with .wpl extension contains the playlist of songs to be run on the Microsoft Windows Media Player. These files are usually created by users for their video and audio collections. The content written in a WPL file, is just directory paths or locations for the multimedia files selected by the creator of the .wpl file, so the media player application can promptly find and play the multimedia content from their directory locations.</description></item><item><title>CDA - CD Audio Track Shortcut File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/cda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/cda/</guid><description>What is a CDA file? A file with the .cda extension is a small stub file generated automatically by the Microsoft Windows operating system for every track on a standard audio CD. Contrary to common belief, these CDA files do not contain the actual music data. Instead, they function as intelligent pointers, holding essential information like track timing and serving as a direct Windows shortcut to the corresponding audio data on the disc.</description></item><item><title>M4B - MPEG-4 Audiobook File Format, M4B vs. MP3</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4b/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4b/</guid><description>What is an M4B file? Discover the power of the M4B audiobook format, a specialized file type recognized by its .m4b extension and celebrated for its advanced features. While it shares a foundation with the standard M4A format, M4B is distinctly engineered for audiobooks, offering crucial functionalities like chapter breaks and digital bookmarking to enhance your listening experience. At its core, the audio within an M4B file is encoded using high-efficiency AAC compression within an MPEG-4 container, ensuring excellent sound quality.</description></item><item><title>M4P - MPEG-4 Audiobook File Format, Protected Audio Container</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4p/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4p/</guid><description>What is an M4P file? The M4P file format, identified by its .m4p extension, is a protected audio standard pioneered by Apple for its iTunes Store. In essence, an M4P file is built upon the high-quality AAC audio codec but is secured with a robust Digital Rights Management (DRM) layer, specifically Apple&amp;rsquo;s FairPlay system. This integral copy protection restricts playback exclusively to authorized devices, creating a controlled ecosystem. Consequently, M4P files are designed for seamless performance within the Apple universe, meaning they are fully compatible with authorized MacBooks, iTunes on Windows, and iOS devices like the iPhone and iPad, but are inherently incompatible with unauthorized software or hardware.</description></item><item><title>AAX - Advanced Audio Coding File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aax/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aax/</guid><description>What is an AAX file? The .aax file extension designates a specialized format for digital audiobooks, developed and pioneered by Audible—a leading American online audiobook and podcast service owned by Amazon.com Inc. As the enhanced successor to the older AA file format, AAX files offer a significantly richer, multimedia experience. These files are the standard distribution format for platforms like AAudible; Audible Kids, and the iTunes Store. Unlike basic audio files, AAX files are sophisticated digital multimedia containers that can integrate features such as embedded graphics, video clips, interactive bookmarks, and a precise video timeline.</description></item><item><title>APE - Monkey's Audio Lossless Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ape/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ape/</guid><description>What is APE file? An APE file is a type of audio file that uses the Monkey’s Audio compression algorithm, designed specifically for lossless audio data compression. Unlike popular lossy formats such as MP3, AAC, Vorbis, or Opus, this algorithm preserves every bit of the original audio data, ensuring no quality is lost during encoding. With Monkey’s Audio, file sizes are typically reduced to nearly half of their original size, making storage and transfer more efficient while maintaining high fidelity.</description></item><item><title>AMR - Adaptive Multi-Rate Codec File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/amr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/amr/</guid><description>What is an AMR file? A file bearing the .amr extension is an audio format based on the Adaptive Multi-Rate (AMR) codec, a standard specifically engineered for efficient speech encoding. This technology utilizes a multi-rate narrowband speech codec that processes audio signals within a constrained frequency range optimal for the human voice. It operates across a spectrum of bit rates, from a low of 4.75 kbit/s up to 12.2 kbit/s, achieving what is recognized as toll quality speech—comparable to a traditional landline call—starting at just 7.</description></item><item><title>AIFF - Audio Interchange File Format, The Gold Standard for Uncompressed Audio</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aiff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aiff/</guid><description>What is an AIFF file? Developed by Apple in 1988, the AIFF (Audio Interchange File Format) is a high-fidelity, uncompressed audio standard. Its underlying structure is based on the EA IFF 85 format from Electronic Arts, originally created for Amiga systems. This foundation provides exceptional flexibility, allowing the format to store monaural or multichannel sampled sounds at a wide range of sample rates and bit depths. A key characteristic of AIFF is its uncompressed nature, which results in significantly larger file sizes compared to lossy alternatives like MP3.</description></item><item><title>DSS - Digital Speech Standard File, Professional Standard for Digital Speech Recording</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/dss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/dss/</guid><description>What is a DSS file? The DSS file, which stands for Digital Speech Standard, is a proprietary digital audio format originally established by the International Voice Association, a joint venture founded by industry leaders Philips, Olympus, and Grundig Business Systems. As an older codec specifically engineered for speech, its primary design goal was efficiency rather than high-fidelity music reproduction. The format compresses voice audio data to enable fundamental recording functions like playback and capture while maintaining a very compact file size.</description></item><item><title>M4A - MPEG-4 Audio File, The Modern Standard for Digital Audio</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m4a/</guid><description>What is an M4A file? The M4A file format, an abbreviation for MPEG 4 Audio, is a versatile audio container known for its high-quality, lossy compression via the Advanced Audio Coding (AAC) codec. Identified by the .m4a file extension, it is the standard for un-protected audio content and can store a diverse range of media, including songs, podcasts, and audiobooks. Technologically, M4A is recognized as a more advanced successor to the MP3 format.</description></item><item><title>ALAC - Apple Lossless Audio Codec File Format with Efficient Compression</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/alac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/alac/</guid><description>What is a ALAC file? The Apple Lossless Audio Codec, commonly known as ALAC, is a high-efficiency audio format that utilizes the MPEG-4 compliant QuickTime container (.m4a). Initially launched as a proprietary technology in 2004, Apple transitioned ALAC to an open-source and royalty-free model in 2011, significantly broadening its accessibility. This format provides a perceptible audio upgrade over lossy codecs like AAC and MP3 by preserving all the original data. While functionally similar to FLAC (Free Lossless Audio Codec), ALAC typically achieves a slightly different compression ratio.</description></item><item><title>MPC - Musepack Audio Compression File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mpc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mpc/</guid><description>What is a MPC file? A file with .mpc extension is a Musepack audio file format that uses audio compression with a strong emphasis on high quality. This makes it possible for you to not even notice the sound quality differences of original WAV file and the compressed MPC file. It uses MPEG-1 Layer-2 algorithms to achieve highly optimized compression. Musepack MPC file format is open source with BSD/GNU LGPL license.</description></item><item><title>OPUS</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/opus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/opus/</guid><description>What is an OPUS file? Opus is an audio file format created by Xiph.Org foundation and later being standardized by IETF (Internet Engineering Task Force). It has been developed mainly for internet streaming, Voice over IP (VOIP), video conferencing and in-game chat that is why it is designed to retain low-latency while maintaining a real time interactive communication. Keeping the sound quality of an Opus file, many blind listening tests have marked Opus as high quality audio format than any other audio format at any given bitrate.</description></item><item><title>WMA - Windows Media Audio File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wma/</guid><description>What is a WMA file? A file with .wma extension represents an audio file that is saved in the Advanced Systems Format (ASF) format. ASF is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s proprietary format that contains bitstreams encoded by Windows Media Audio 9. In addition to the the audio content, a WMA file also contains metadata objects such as title, album, artist, and genre of the track. WMA files are primarily used for streaming over the web similar to .</description></item><item><title>AAC - Advanced Audio Coding File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/aac/</guid><description>What is an AAC file? AAC (Advanced Audio Coding) is a standardized digital audio coding technology designed for lossy audio compression. Officially defined in the MPEG-2 Part 7 (ISO/IEC 13818-7) and later enhanced in MPEG-4 Part 3 (ISO/IEC 14496-3) standards, it was developed to succeed the older MP3 file format. A key driver for its creation was to overcome the technical limitations of MP3, which hindered the implementation of new, more efficient audio encoding and data compression methods.</description></item><item><title>AC3 - Audio Codec 3 File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ac3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ac3/</guid><description>What is an AC3 file? The .ac3 file extension signifies an Audio Codec 3 file, a proprietary audio format developed and introduced by Dolby Laboratories. Functioning as the technical container for Dolby Digital audio, this format is engineered to hold up to six discrete channels of audio, enabling rich 5.1 channel surround sound output. While originally developed for cinematic audio, the AC3 format has become a ubiquitous industry standard for a wide array of digital media applications.</description></item><item><title>FLAC File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/flac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/flac/</guid><description>What is a FLAC file? FLAC (Free Lossless Audio Codec) is a revolutionary lossless audio coding format developed by the Xiph.Org Foundation. As a completely royalty-free and open-source format, identified by the .flac file extension, it offers a significant advantage in digital audio storage and fidelity. The powerful FLAC compression algorithm efficiently reduces the size of digital audio files by an impressive 50 to 70 percent. Most importantly, this compression is entirely lossless, meaning FLAC files can be decompressed into a perfect, bit-for-bit identical copy of the original source, preserving every detail of the audio quality without any degradation.</description></item><item><title>M3U File Format - Your Guide to Playlists</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m3u/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/m3u/</guid><description>What is a M3U file? M3U (MP3 URL) is an audio playlist file stored with the .m3u extension. M3U is not an actual audio file, it just points to audio and sometimes video files. M3U was developed to be used with Winplay3 software by Fraunhofer. It is also supported by various media players and software.
M3U File Format There is no official specification for the M3U file format, it is a de-facto standard.</description></item><item><title>MIDI File Format - The Universal Language of Digital Music</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mid/</guid><description>What is a MID file? A file having .MID or.MIDI file extension is the Musical Instrument Digital (MID) Interface file. It is the difference from ordinary audio files such as WAVs or MP3s in that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t carry the actual audio content; hence, is quite smaller in size. The content includes the notes played, their timing, duration, and desired loudness for each note.
The MID file fundamentally consists of information explaining how should the sound be heard when linked with the playback device or loaded into a specific software that interprets audio data.</description></item><item><title>MP3 - Audio File Format, MPEG-1 Audio Layer III</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mp3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mp3/</guid><description>What is an MP3 file? The MP3 file format, instantly recognizable by its .mp3 extension, is a landmark in digital audio technology. Formally defined as MPEG-1 Audio Layer III or MPEG-2 Audio Layer III, it was developed by the Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) and revolutionized music consumption through its Layer 3 audio compression. This powerful compression algorithm can reduce an audio file to roughly 1/10th the size of an uncompressed .</description></item><item><title>OGG File - Ogg Vorbis Audio File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ogg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ogg/</guid><description>What is an OGG file? OGG is an Ogg Vorbis Compressed Audio File that is saved with the .ogg extension. OGG files are used for storing audio data and can include artist and track information and metadata as well. OGG is a free and open container format that is maintained by Xiph.Org Foundation.
Brief History of OGG File Format Ogg project started as a part of a larger project in 1993 and was named Squish but because of an existing trademark, it was renamed to OggSquish.</description></item><item><title>RA File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/ra/</guid><description>What is a RA file? RealAudio (RA) is a proprietary audio format developed by Real Networks, Inc. and released in April 1995. It uses the .ra extension for its files. It uses low-bitrate as well as high fidelity audio codecs. RA was used for audio streaming over the internet by many internet radio stations. The BBC website used RA heavily until 2009 but discontinued in March 2011.
File Extension by RealNetworks RealNetworks used the RA file format for audio.</description></item><item><title>SDT File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sdt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/sdt/</guid><description>What is a SDT file? SDT files are used as a means of storage for game sounds, including background music and sound effects. Some programs, like Dragon UnPACKer and MAStudio 2002, can open and copy the audio content from SDT files. SDT file is opened only by special software. There are 3 file types and each of them could be opened by different software. Old games that were released by Electronic Arts (for example Dungeon Keeper 2 (DK2), Theme Park World, Formula One (F1) series video games) audio package file with a collection of compressed audio files that can be saved using a MPEG-2 format.</description></item><item><title>STAP - Soundtrack Pro File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/stap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/stap/</guid><description>What is a STAP file? A file with .stap extension is mainly related to Soundtrack Pro by Apple Inc. Apple’s audio editing and sound design application enable users to express their sonic vision. With the Action-based waveform editor, multitrack editing, and repair and restoration features, users can design and edit their audio with flexibility. STAP file format is well-suited with software that can be installed on the Mac OS system platform.</description></item><item><title>WAV - Waveform Audio File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wav/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/wav/</guid><description>What is a WAV file? WAV, short for Waveform Audio File Format, is a subset of Microsoft’s Resource Interchange File Format (RIFF) used for storing high-quality digital audio. Unlike compressed formats, WAV files store audio data without any compression, preserving full sound fidelity across various sampling rates and bitrates. This format has long been a standard for audio CDs due to its superior sound quality. Although WAV files are larger compared to modern formats like MP3, which uses lossy compression to reduce file size, WAV files can still be compressed using Audio Compression Manager (ACM) codecs.</description></item><item><title>MKA(Ultimate Container for Multimedia) - Matroska Multimedia Container File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/audio/mka/</guid><description>What Are MKA files? Discover the power of the MKA file format, the specialized audio container within the renowned Matroska multimedia family. Instantly recognizable by its .mka file extension, this versatile container is engineered to support a vast range of advanced audio compression algorithms, including MP3, AAC, and the efficient Vorbis codec. Far more capable than a simple audio file, MKA is perfect for storing not just individual songs but complete albums in a single, highly-organized package.</description></item></channel></rss>