<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learn about Image File Formats and APIs that can create and open Image files on File Format Docs</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/</link><description>Recent content in Learn about Image File Formats and APIs that can create and open Image files on File Format Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.fileformat.com/image/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QTIF File - QuickTime Image Format - What is .qtif file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/qtif/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/qtif/</guid><description>The QTIF (QuickTime Image Format) is a file format developed by Apple Inc. for storing images within the QuickTime multimedia framework. It is based on the TIFF (Tagged Image File Format) but tailored for use in QuickTime-based applications. Although it was once useful in Apple’s ecosystem, QTIF has since become obsolete, with most modern applications no longer supporting it.
What is a QTIF File? Full Name: QuickTime Image Format File Extension: .</description></item><item><title>PDN File - Paint.net Image - What is .pdn file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pdn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pdn/</guid><description>What is a PDN file? The PDN file format is the native format used by Paint.NET, which is a popular free image and photo editing software. The format is specifically designed to store images created or edited in Paint.NET application. The format preserves all layers, settings and effects that occur during editing the image so that user can continue to edit the images without worrying to lose original information relating to source image.</description></item><item><title>JPG_LARGE File - Twitter Large JPEG Image - What is .jpg_large file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpg_large/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpg_large/</guid><description>What is a JPG_LARGE file? The .jpg_large file format is specific to Twitter and refers to a larger version of a JPEG image file. When users upload images to Twitter, they often get processed and resized for optimization across various devices and views. A jpg_large image typically retains higher resolution than the standard version displayed in a tweet. Twitter appends the _large suffix to the filename to indicate it&amp;rsquo;s a larger, higher-quality JPEG.</description></item><item><title>PNJ File - Portable Network JPEG Image - What is .pnj file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pnj/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pnj/</guid><description>What is a PNJ file? PNJ stands for Portable Network JPEG. It is an image file format that combines the features of JPEG (lossy compression for smaller file sizes) and PNG (support for transparency). This hybrid format compresses image data using JPEG&amp;rsquo;s lossy compression but stores it in a PNG container, allowing for transparency (alpha channel). The format was created by the PNG Development Group for use in animations within MNG (Multiple-Image Network Graphics) files.</description></item><item><title>PPF File - Picture Publisher Image File - What is .ppf file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ppf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ppf/</guid><description>What is a PPF file? The PPF file format, known as the Picture Publisher Image File, is associated with Picture Publisher, a graphics editing program that was popular in the late 1990s and early 2000s. Primarily used for storing image data and graphics created or edited in Picture Publisher, a .ppf file typically contains raster images that may include various layers, effects, and other graphical elements specific to the software. While it is mainly linked to Picture Publisher, there may be limited support in other graphics editing programs; however, direct compatibility is often an issue due to the proprietary nature of the format.</description></item><item><title>SPP File - Serif PhotoPlus Picture File - What is .spp file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/spp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/spp/</guid><description>What is an SPP file? The SPP file format is associated with Serif PhotoPlus, a discontinued photo editing software developed by Serif. Files with the .spp extension are Serif PhotoPlus Picture Files, and they store images in a proprietary format. These files often include layers, effects, and other editing information that allow users to continue editing the image without losing quality or important details.
The key features of SPP files include</description></item><item><title>MIX File - Microsoft Image Extension - What is .mix file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mix/</guid><description>What is a MIX File? A MIX file is a format associated with several applications, most notably Microsoft Picture It! and Microsoft PhotoDraw. The acronym MIX stands for Microsoft Image Extension, and these files are used to store images that can contain both vector and raster graphics. This dual capability allows the file to hold both pixel-based images (raster) and scalable shapes or lines (vector), offering flexibility in image editing and design.</description></item><item><title>SVS File - Aperio ScanScope Slide Image - What is .svs file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/svs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/svs/</guid><description>What is an SVS file? An SVS file (Slide and Viewable Storage) is a digital slide image file commonly created by Aperio ScanScope slide scanners. Designed for the medical and research fields, SVS files store a series of TIFF images that represent various views of a specimen slide.
Key characteristics of SVS files include:
Multi-Resolution Storage: SVS files contain multiple images at different resolutions. This structure allows for efficient viewing, enabling users to zoom in on high-resolution details or navigate using lower-resolution images.</description></item><item><title>RPF File - Rich Pixel Format File - What is .rpf file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/rpf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/rpf/</guid><description>What is an RPF file? An RPF file, which stands for &amp;ldquo;Rich Pixel Format,&amp;rdquo; is a proprietary image format associated with Alias/Wavefront&amp;rsquo;s Maya software. RPF files are typically used for storing various types of information about a rendered image, such as depth, motion vectors, object IDs, and other rendering passes. This format allows for greater flexibility and control when compositing rendered images in post-production software such as Adobe After Effects or Nuke.</description></item><item><title>FIG File - Xfig Drawing - What is .fig file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/fig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/fig/</guid><description>What is a FIG file? A FIG file format is a type of file associated with line drawings, and it can be generated using either Xfig or WinFIG applications. It belongs to category of vector image files, containing information about shapes, arcs, splines, arrows and text objects. In addition to these elements, users have flexibility to incorporate images, colors and patterns into their FIG drawings.
About Xfig Xfig is an open-source vector graphics editor primarily designed for Unix/Linux systems; it provides user-friendly interface for creating and editing vector-based drawings.</description></item><item><title>CDX File - CorelDRAW Compressed File - What is .cdx file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cdx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cdx/</guid><description>What is a CDX file? CDX files are created by CorelDRAW, a vector graphics editing program. These files are a compressed version of the .CDR drawing files, which are the main file format used by CorelDRAW. The purpose of creating CDX files is to reduce the amount of storage space required for a drawing.
About CorelDRAW CorelDRAW is a popular vector graphics editing program that is part of the CorelDRAW Graphics Suite software package.</description></item><item><title>PVT File - Live Photo File - What is .pvt file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pvt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pvt/</guid><description>What is a PVT file? A PVT file is a type of Live Photo, a combination of pictures and videos created by an iPhone. Usually, Live Photos have a different name like .HEIC, but sometimes when you share them using services like AirDrop, they might end up with a .pvt extension by mistake. Normally, when you send a Live Photo, it should be in .HEIC format (or changed to .JPG in some cases).</description></item><item><title>INK File - Pantone Reference - What is an .ink file and how to open it?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ink/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ink/</guid><description>What is an INK file? The &amp;ldquo;.ink&amp;rdquo; file format is associated with Pantone, a well-known company in field of color matching and printing. A Pantone Reference File in the &amp;ldquo;.ink&amp;rdquo; format typically contains information about Pantone ink colors; these files are used in printing industry to ensure accurate color reproduction and consistency.
Pantone is known for its Pantone Matching System (PMS), which is standardized color reproduction system widely used in various industries including graphic design, printing and manufacturing; the PMS provides set of ink colors, each identified by specific code such as &amp;ldquo;PMS 185&amp;rdquo; for specific shade of red.</description></item><item><title>PAT File Format - CorelDRAW Pattern File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pat-coreldraw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pat-coreldraw/</guid><description>What is a PAT file? A &amp;ldquo;.PAT file is typically associated with CorelDRAW, a popular vector graphics editing software. In CorelDRAW, &amp;ldquo;.PAT&amp;rdquo; file is &amp;ldquo;Pattern File&amp;rdquo; that contains information about patterns or textures that can be applied to objects in your design. Patterns can be used to fill objects with various repeating designs, such as stripes, dots or custom textures. These patterns are stored in &amp;ldquo;.PAT&amp;rdquo; files for easy reuse.</description></item><item><title>PAT File Format - Pattern File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pat-pattern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pat-pattern/</guid><description>What is a PAT file? A &amp;ldquo;.PAT&amp;rdquo; file, short for &amp;ldquo;Pattern File&amp;rdquo; is specific file format used in various graphics and design software. These files typically contain information about pattern or texture that can be applied to elements within design or illustration. The pattern information may include the arrangement of pixels, colors and other details required to create repeating pattern.
These &amp;ldquo;.PAT&amp;rdquo; files are commonly used in software like Adobe Photoshop to apply custom patterns to shapes, backgrounds or other elements in design, allowing designers to easily replicate and use complex or custom patterns in their projects without having to recreate them manually.</description></item><item><title>ARW File Format - Sony Alpha Raw Digital Camera Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/arw/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/arw/</guid><description>What is an ARW file? ARW file is also know as Alpha Raw file. It is a type of digital image used by Sony cameras and contains raw, unprocessed data captured by camera&amp;rsquo;s image sesnor. The captured data is uncompressed and retains all the original information captured by camera allowing greater flexibilty in post processing.
ARW files typically store a high level of detail, dynamic range and color depth. They provide photographers with more control over aspects such as white balance, exposure, and noise reduction during editing process.</description></item><item><title>BAY File Format - Casio RAW Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bay/</guid><description>What is a BAY file? A .bay file format is a raw image format taken from Casio digital cameras. It is a proprietary raw image format and contains unprocessed data directly from camera&amp;rsquo;s image sesors. The data contained by it is also uncompressed. They typically store a higher level of image data and provide more flexibility for post-processing and editing compared to compressed image formats like JPEG.
How to open BAY file?</description></item><item><title>RAF File Format - Fujifilm RAW Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/raf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/raf/</guid><description>What is a RAF file? The RAF file format is associated with Fuji RAW image files, which are generated by Fujifilm digital cameras. The acronymn RAF stands for &amp;ldquo;Fuji Raw Image File.&amp;rdquo;
RAF files contain minimally processed image data directly from camera&amp;rsquo;s image sensor. Unlike JPEG or other compressed image formats, RAF files are considered &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; because they preserve all the original data captured by camera, including color information, exposure settings, white balance and other camera-specific metadata.</description></item><item><title>RAW File Format - Raw Image Data</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/raw/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/raw/</guid><description>What is a RAW file? A raw file format refers to file format that stores unprocessed and uncompressed data directly from digital image sensor or other sources. It is commonly used in digital photography and imaging.
Other formats apply compression and processing algorithms to reduce file size and optimize image for display or printing, raw files contain all data captured by sensor without any alterations. This includes information such as color, brightness and other sensor-specific data.</description></item><item><title>PEF File Format - Pentax Electronic File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pef/</guid><description>What is a PEF file? A PEF file is a file format commonly associated with digital photography and is used by Pentax cameras. PEF stands for Pentax Electronic File and is a raw image file format, meaning it contains minimally processed data directly from the camera&amp;rsquo;s image sensor.
PEF files store raw image data captured by camera, including information such as color temperature, exposure settings and sensor data. They retain a higher level of detail and provide greater flexibility for post-processing compared to compressed image formats like JPEG.</description></item><item><title>APM File Format - Aldus Placeable Metafile Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/apm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/apm/</guid><description>What is an APM file? An APM file is a vector image file format saved in Aldus Placeable Metafile format. It was developed by Aldus Corporation which is now part of Adobe Systems.
Vector graphics are images created using geometric shapes such as points, lines and curves rather than pixels. Vector graphics can be scaled up or down without losing quality and are commonly used in graphic design, illustrations, and other applications where high-resolution images are needed.</description></item><item><title>BIF File - Ventana Whole Slide Image Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bif/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bif/</guid><description>What is a BIF file? A BIF file is a raster image file that contains the slide specimen image. It consists multiple TIFF images that are combined by slide viewing applications into a single composite image. BIF files are created by Ventana Medical systems digital slide scanner and are fully compliant with the BigTIFF-variant of the TIFF v 6.0 definition.
BIF File Format A BIF file is saved as binary image file and consist of as many as 200,000 x 200,000 pixels.</description></item><item><title>JXL File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jxl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jxl/</guid><description>What is a JXL file? JXL stands for JPEG XL. It is an image file that is saved in JPEG XL file format. It supports both lossy as well as lossless compression. JXL is extended version of the JPEG XL file format that was developed by the Joint Photographic Experts Group (JPEG). It can contain an image, illustrations, or screenshot that has been compressed using the JPEG XL compression algorithm.</description></item><item><title>AGIF File - Auto FX PhotoGraphic Edges Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/agif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/agif/</guid><description>What is an AGIF file? An AGIF file is a GIF file created with Active GIF Creator. It is a project file that can be opened and viewed in Active GIF Creator projects. When opened in Active GIF Creator, it shows sequence of images that finally make up for the finalized GIF file with .gif extension.
AGIF File Format AGIF is a project file that is saved as raster image file format.</description></item><item><title>AGP File - ArtGem Project File File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/agp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/agp/</guid><description>What is an AGP file? An AGP file is a 32-bit image file with multiple layers. It is created with the ArtGem software that provides the features of working with images and is similar to Adobe Photoshop in basic features. AGP is a project file that contains all the settings for creating the final image.
AGP files could be opened with RL Vision ArtGem. However, ArtGem has long been discontinued after getting sold.</description></item><item><title>AFPHOTO File - Affinity Photo Document File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/afphoto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/afphoto/</guid><description>What is an AFPHOTO file? An AFPHOTO file is an image file created by the image creation software, Serif Affinity Photo. It contains the overall contents of the image in the form of multiple image layers, shapes, text, paint strokes, swatches, coloring effects and lighting. Serif Affinity Photo is similar to Adobe Photoshop, rather it is an alternative to Adobe Photoshop with almost the same features and capabilities. Adobe Photoshop saves the files as .</description></item><item><title>AFX File - Auto FX PhotoGraphic Edges Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/afx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/afx/</guid><description>What is an AFX file? An AFX file is an image file used by the Auto FX PhotoGraphic Edges software that is used for enhancement of digital images. It contains the raster overlay image that is used on top of another image to give the PhotoGraphic effect. This process enhances the the output image by creating digital effect to client images. It also gives an enhanced digital look to the photographs that are much better to present.</description></item><item><title>HDR File Format - What is an HDR image file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/hdr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/hdr/</guid><description>What is an HDR file? An HDR file is a High Dynamic Range (HDR) raster image file format for storing digital camera photos. It allows photo editors to enhance the color and brightness of digital images that have limited dynamic range. This modification can improve the brightness around the corners, resulting in a close-to-natural image. HDR files are usually saved as 32-bit raster images. Adobe Photoshop can create and open HDR files.</description></item><item><title>PSP File Format - PaintShop Pro Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psp/</guid><description>What is a PSP file? A PSP file is a colored bitmap image created with PaintShop Pro. It is the native file format of PaintShop Pro and supports uncompressed, RLE compressed, LZ77 compressed, and JPEG compressed files (including Lossless JPEG). It also supports layers similar to PSD files and can have other information such as guides, metadata, and relevant objects within the image file. Each layer can be edited and integrated with the main image by its own.</description></item><item><title>PSPIMAGE File Format - PaintShop Pro Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pspimage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pspimage/</guid><description>What is a PSPIMAGE file? A PSPIMAGE file is a graphics image saved using Corel PaintShop Pro software that is used for image and digital photo editing. It supports saving image data in both raster and vector file formats. PSPIMAGE files support edits made to an image such as layers, transparency, filters and other image effects. PSPIMAGE files can be saved and exported to other popular image file formats such as JPEG, PNG, and BMP.</description></item><item><title>NEF File Format - Nikon Electronic Format RAW Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/nef/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/nef/</guid><description>What is an NEF file? NEF is Nikon&amp;rsquo;s RAW image file format, captured with Nikon digital cameras. It stores the raw image data as captured by the camera sensor as well as metadata about the image such as camera identification, its settings, and other related information. It is stored to the camera memory card as uncompressed or lossless compressed form.
NEF File Format - More Information NEF files are written to the camera memory card as binary files in Nikon&amp;rsquo;s proprietary file format.</description></item><item><title>JPC File Format - JPEG 2000 Code Stream File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpc/</guid><description>What is a JPC file? A JPC file is an image file format that is encoded using the JPEG2000 code stream. These are also sometimes referred as Japan Picture files. JPC files uses JPEG 2000 advanced wavelet compression that is also used by the JPEG2000 encoded files. These support color depths of 8, 24, and 32 bits per pixel in the grayscale, RGB, YCbCr, XYZ, and Lab colro spaces.
JPC files can be opened with Adobe Photoshop 2022, Adobe Photoshop Elements, and Adobe Illustrator 2021.</description></item><item><title>DDS File Format- DirectDraw Surface Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dds/</guid><description>What is a DDS file? A DDS file is a raster image file that utilizes the DirectDraw Surface (DDS) container format. It stores uncompressed and compressed (DXTn) textures and implements different types for storing different types of data. It also supports several different type of data such as single layer textures, textures with mipmaps, cube maps, volume maps and texture arrays. This enables the DDS files to store video game texture unit models in addition to digital photos and Windows desktop backgrounds.</description></item><item><title>ART - AOL Compressed Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/art/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/art/</guid><description>What is an ART file? An ART file is a compressed bitmap image file created and used by America Online (AOL) service and client software. It was built to reduce the image size for quick downloading over the internet. The compression algorithm applied on image to generate .art files is similar to the JPEG format, but at times reduces the image quality while favouring the reduction of file size. ART files can be opened using the AOL File Viewer.</description></item><item><title>CR2 File Format - Canon Raw 2 Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cr2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cr2/</guid><description>What is a CR2 file? A CR2 (Camera RAW 2) file is a RAW image file created by Canon digital cameras. It stores the original non-processed lossless image data captured by the camera. CR2 file format was developed by Canon for its digital cameras and can record high-qulaity images of up to 14 bits of RGB. This produces high quality images with enough room of post processing. CR2 image format has been used by Canon in their 350D, 20D and 1D camera models.</description></item><item><title>CR3 File Format - Canon Raw 3 Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cr3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cr3/</guid><description>What is a CR3 file? A CR3 file is a Canon RAW image file format that is created by selected Canon digital cameras. It was introduced by Canon to replace the CR2 file format and is used by some of the Canon digital devices. CR3 files store the original non-processed lossless image data captured by the camera. The use of these raw images provide high quality images and allow plenty of room for editing to photographers.</description></item><item><title>CSL File Format - Corel Symbol Library File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/csl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/csl/</guid><description>What is a CSL file? A Corel Symbol Library (CSL) file is a library of symbols used within CorelDRAW software. It stores symbols that can be used in other files. CSL files can be stored locally or on a network to let them accessible for easy deployment and management. These are saved with the CorelDRAW file along with all the symbol instances used within the document.
CSL File Format CSL files are saved in CorelDRAW proprietary file format.</description></item><item><title>CT File Format - Scitex Continuous Tone File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ct/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ct/</guid><description>What is a CT file? A CT (Continuous Tone) file is a raster image file used by Scitex graphics processing equipment. Several graphics suites such as Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, and QuarkXPress supports its usage for rendering. Data image is stored inside the CT file in CMYK (Cyan, Magenta, Yellow Key), RGB, and grayscale image formats, but they don&amp;rsquo;t support alpha channels. CT files can be opened with applications such as Adobe Photoshop 2022, Adobe InDesign 2022, and XnViewMP.</description></item><item><title>XPR File Format - Microsoft Expression Design Graphic File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/xpr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/xpr/</guid><description>What is an XPR file? An XPR file is a vector image file created with the now-discontinued Microsoft Expression Graphics (EGD) software. It contains graphics information that can used as user interface mockup. XPR files were later replaced by .design files in Microsoft Expression Design. XPR files could be opened with Microsoft Expression Studio that has been discontinued for quite some time now.
XPR File Format Vulnerability XPR files were identified to benefit a vulnerability in Microsoft Expression Design, leading to allow execution of remote code.</description></item><item><title>DCX - Zsoft Multi-Page Paintbrush File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcx/</guid><description>What is a DCX file? A DCX file is an image file that consists of multiple-pages for generating digital fax files. Each DCX file starts with a 4-byte header identifying the DCX file as signature, followed by individual images, stored as embedded PCX files. The 4-byte signature identifies the DCX file and it is followed by a list of up to 1023 4-byte file offsets. DCX file format was developed by Zsoft.</description></item><item><title>PCT File Format - What is a PCT file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pct/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pct/</guid><description>What is a PCT file? A PCT file is a Macintosh Picture Image file format that was the default file format for Apple QuickDraw programme. It was developed by Apple but after the discontinuation of QuickDraw programme, it is no more in use. PDF, at large, has replaced the PCT and similar file formats. PCT files can also be sometimes found with .pict file extension, though both PCT and PICT have the same file format.</description></item><item><title>PCX File Format - Paintbrush Bitmap Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pcx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pcx/</guid><description>What is a PCX file? A PCX file, Picture Exchange file, is a raster image file format that was used as native file format for PC Paintbrush application. It was developed by ZSoft Corporation, USA for DOS and Windows platforms and was adopted as the main imaging file format before the arrival of BMP, JPEG, and PNG file formats. PCX files are smaller in size as they are compressed using the RLE encoding.</description></item><item><title>PICT File Format - What is a PICT file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pict/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/pict/</guid><description>What is a PICT file? A PICT file is a a graphics image saved in the Apple Macintosh picture file format. It can store image data as both raster and vector file formats. It was default picture file format for Apple QuickDraw programme. PICT files allow the exchange of raster as well as vector data between Mac applications. The format has long been replaced by the more flexible PDF file format.</description></item><item><title>PPP File - PhotoPad Project File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ppp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ppp/</guid><description>What is a PPP file? A PPP file is a graphics project file created with NCH PhotoPad Editor Software. It comprises of the edited image in PhotoPad along with the record of all the edits made to different components (such as layers, text, adjustments) of that image. This lets you revert to a previous editing stage and start editing from that point. PPP Project files can be opened in PhotoPad software and can be exported to popular image file formats such as JPG, PNG, TIFF, GIF, and PSD.</description></item><item><title>MP File - LaTeX MetaPost File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mp/</guid><description>What is a MP file? An MP file is a vector image file generated by MetaPost programming language to create pictures. Vector images created using MP file format are saved as EPS (Encapsulated PostScript) files. In addition, MetaPost comes distributed with TeX and Metafont frameworks and MP files can be generated from within the TEX and LTX files used by these applications. MP files contain drawing statements and mathematical algorithmic drawing for rendering the output EPS file.</description></item><item><title>MPO File - Multi Picture Object File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mpo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mpo/</guid><description>What is a MPO file? An MPO file is a stereoscopic 3D image which comes into existence after overlapping of two 2D images. These kinds of images are created by digital cameras and are widely used in 3D video gaming consoles and 3D TV. MPO files are also known as multi – picture objects because they contain two or more JPEG images.
Brief History of MPO File Format MPO file format was developed by Camera and Imaging Products Association (CIPA).</description></item><item><title>CLIP File - Clip Studio Format File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/clip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/clip/</guid><description>What is a CLIP file? A CLIP file is a raster image file generated by the 2D drawing application Clip Studio Paint. It is similar to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s PSD file and contains multiple layers to manage different graphics elements in the form of layers such as text, images, pen, pencil, brushes, and shapes. CLIP file format is used to design a number of different graphics types such as illustrations and animations. Clip Studio Paint application was developed by a Japanese company CELSYS, Inc.</description></item><item><title>THM File - Video Thumbnail File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/thm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/thm/</guid><description>What is a THM file? A THM file is a Thumbnail image automatically created from the first frame of a video file on digital camcorders, cameras, and smartphones. It is generated when a video file is saved by the device camera. The thumbnail preview images from all the videos are displayed to the user for choosing the video of interest from the videos collection. THM files are saved in compressed binary format in memory to reduce space utilization.</description></item><item><title>CUR - Cursor File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cur/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cur/</guid><description>What is a CUR file? A CUR file is a static Microsoft Windows cursor file format. Basically, they are stationary images identical to ICO (icon) files in every way except the extension. Both CUR and ICO are established on the basis of the Device-Independent Bitmap DIB (Device-Independent Bitmap) specification. Default, as well as custom cursor such as Windows mouse pointer for Windows operating system, are stored in CUR files. It can be an arrow for normal use, a spinning hourglass to demonstrate waiting periods, or an I-bar for text editing.</description></item><item><title>ICNS - Apple Icon Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/icns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/icns/</guid><description>What is an ICNS file? An icon format used by macOS programs is called an ICNS file. It allows 1-bit and 8-bit alpha bands and saves one or more pictures, usually made from PNG documents. The program icon in the macOS browser and interface is displayed using ICNS files.
Based on the location, the same style icon can have multiple settings. The ICNS format has undergone numerous alterations and has evolved to the point where it may now be used as the foundation for various compatible formats.</description></item><item><title>JPF - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpf/</guid><description>What is a JPF file? A file with .jpf extension is an extension to the JPEG 2000 image coding system ISO/IEC 15444 and is referred to as its Part 2 ISO/IEC 15444-2. It defines and specifies a set of lossless (bit-preserving) and lossy compression methods for coding continuous-tone, bi-level, grey-scale, colour digital still images, or multi-component images. The first part of ISO/IEC 15444-1 is referred to the JP2 that uses the wavelet technology to code lossless content and is the base for JPEG 2000 image file formats.</description></item><item><title>JPX - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpx/</guid><description>What is a JPX file? A file with .jpx extension is an extension to the JPEG 2000 file format. It uses the JPEG 2000 compression primarily and also provides advanced features such as multiple layers for an image, various colour spaces, opacity, and fragmented code streams. JPX also allows other compressions such as JBIG, CCITT Group3, CCITT Group4, etc. in addition to the JPEG 2000 compression. The JPX file format was approved as ISO/IEC 15444-2 standard, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t receive a warm reception due to the extensive usage of JPEG file format.</description></item><item><title>AI - Adobe Illustrator Artwork File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ai/</guid><description>What is an AI file? A file with an .ai extension is an Adobe Illustrator Artwork file that contains vector graphics in a single page. it uses points to create paths for displaying the image data, thus making it safe from losing image quality if it is enlarged. AI file format is base don the PGF file format which are similar to AI files. AI format finds its major usage for logos and print media, and its initial versions were considered similar to that of EPS files.</description></item><item><title>AVIF File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/avif/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/avif/</guid><description>What is an AVIF file? AVIF (AV1 Image File Format) is an image file format that stores images compressed with AV1 in HEIF file format. AVIF files are stored with the .avif extension. Version 1 of the AVIF was finalized in February 2019. It has features like High Dynamic Range (HDR), support for 8, 10, and 12 color depth, support for any color space(ISO/IEC CICP and ICC profiles, wide color gamut), etc.</description></item><item><title>BPG File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bpg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bpg/</guid><description>What is a BPG file? BPG (Better Portable Graphics) is a file format created by Fabrice Bellard in 2014 for digital images. He proposed BPG as a replacement for JPEG as BPG was more compression or size efficient. BPG uses the intra-frame encoding of the HEVC (High-Efficiency Video Coding) video compression standard.
BPG is designed as a portable memory-efficient format to work on handheld and IoT devices. Currently, web browsers do not support BPG format, but websites can still deliver BPG images by using a JavaScript library written by Bellard.</description></item><item><title>CPC File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cpc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cpc/</guid><description>What is a CPC file? CPC (Cartesian Perceptual Compression) is a proprietary image file format that uses the .cpc extension for its files. CPC was designed for high compression black-and-white archival scans. CPC is a lossy file format and is restricted by bi-tonal images. CPC is intended for web distribution of legal documents, design plans, and geographical plot maps.
JSTOR converted its online archives to CPC in 1997. JSTOR converts CPC on their servers to GIF for display and to PDF for printing.</description></item><item><title>FLIF File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/flif/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/flif/</guid><description>What is a FLIF file? FLIF (Free Lossless Image Format) is a lossless image format that uses the .flif extension for its files. FLIF claims to outperform PNG, lossless WebP, lossless BPG, and lossless JPEG 2000 in terms of compression ratio. FLIF uses progressive interlacing, due to which any partial download of the image can be used as a lossy encoding for the entire image.
Brief History FLIF was announced in September 2015, and the alpha version was released in October 2015.</description></item><item><title>JFIF File - What is a .jfif file?</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jfif/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jfif/</guid><description>What is a JFIF file? JFIF (JPEG File Interchange Format (JFIF)) is an image format file that uses the .jfif extension. JFIF builds over JIF (JPEG Interchange Format) by reducing complexity and solving its limitations.
Brief History of JFIF JFIF document development was led by Eric Hamilton and an agreement on the first version was established in late 1991. Version 1.02 was published on September 7, 1992. RFC 2046 specified that the JFIF format is used to transmit JPEG images over the internet.</description></item><item><title>JXR File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jxr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jxr/</guid><description>What is a JXR file? JPEG XR (JPEG extended range) is a file format for continuous tone photographic images. It is a still-image compression standard that is based on HD Photo developed by Microsoft. It supports both lossy and lossless compression.
Brief History Windows Media Photo was first announced by Microsoft at WinHEC 2006. It was renamed HD Photo in November 2006. JPEG XR was approved as International Standard ISO/IEC 29199-2 on 19 June 2009.</description></item><item><title>DIB</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dib/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dib/</guid><description>What is a DIB file? A Device-Independent bitmap (DIB) is a raster image file that is similar in structure to the standard Bitmap files(BMP/image/bmp/)). It contains a color table that describes the mapping of RGB colors to the pixel values. This enables DIB to represent image on any device. It can be opened with almost all applications that can open a standard BMP file on Windows as well as macOS. DIB are binary files and have a complex file format similar to BMP.</description></item><item><title>OTG - OpenDocument Drawing Template File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/otg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/otg/</guid><description>What is an OTG file? An OTG file is a drawing template that is created using the OpenDocument standard that follows the OASIS Office Applications 1.0 specification. It represents the default organization of drawing elements for a vector image that can be used to further enhance the contents of the file. OTF files are like any other OpenDocument format based files that are based on XML format to represent the contents of the document.</description></item><item><title>JPEG - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpeg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpeg/</guid><description>What is a JPEG file? A JPEG is a type of image format that is saved using the method of lossy compression. The output image, as result of compression, is a trade-off between storage size and image quality. Users can adjust the compression level to achieve the desired quality level while at the same time reduce the storage size. Image quality is negligibly affected if 10:1 compression is applied to the image.</description></item><item><title>JPM - JPEG 2000 Compound File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jpm/</guid><description>What is a JPM file? JPM refers to JPEG 2000 image coding system Part 6 which is used for document imaging. It is based on the Mixed Raster Content Standard (ISO/IEC 16485) and contains layered still images that use JPEG 2000 and other encodings. In addition to its own specifications, JPM file format inherits features from its parent i.e. the jp2 file format.
JPM File Format The JPM file format is defined by ISO/IEC 15444-6:2003 &amp;ndash; the JPEG 2000 image coding system &amp;ndash; Part 6: Compound image file format.</description></item><item><title>APNG File Format - Animated Portable Network Graphic File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/apng/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/apng/</guid><description>What is a APNG file? A file with .apng (Animated Portable Network Graphics) extension is a raster graphic format and is an unofficial extension to the Portable Network Graphic (PNG ). It comprises of multiple frames (each of PNG image) that represents an animation sequence. This gives similar visualization as a GIF file. APNG files support 24-bit images and 8-bit transparency. APNG is backward compatible with non-animated GIF files. APNG files use the same .</description></item><item><title>BMP - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bmp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/bmp/</guid><description>What is a BMP file? Files having extension .BMP represent Bitmap Image files that are used to store bitmap digital images. These images are independent of graphics adapter and are also called device independent bitmap (DIB) file format. This independency serves the purpose of opening the file on multiple platforms such as Microsoft Windows and Mac. The BMP file format can store data as two-dimensional digital images in both monochrome as well as color format with various colour depths.</description></item><item><title>CDR File Format - Vector Drawing Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cdr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cdr/</guid><description>What is a CDR file? A CDR file is a vector drawing image file that is natively created with CorelDRAW for storing digital image encoded and compressed. Such a drawing file contains text, lines, shapes, images, colours and effects for vector representation of image contents. CDR files can be opened with CorelDRAW as the primary application and can also be converted to other formats such as PDF, JPG, PNG, BMP and AI.</description></item><item><title>CMX - Corel Metafile Exchange Image</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cmx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/cmx/</guid><description>What is a CMX file? Files with .cmx extension are Corel Exchange image file format (also known as Corel Metafile Exchange) that is used as presentation by CorelSuite applications. It contains image data as vector graphics as well as metadata that describes the image. CMX files can be opened by CorelDraw, Corel Presentations, Paint Shop Pro and some versions of Adobe Illustrator. CMX files can be converted to other formats such as JPG and EPS.</description></item><item><title>DCM File Format - Digital Medical Information File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcm/</guid><description>What is a DCM file? Files with .dcm extension represent digital image which stores medical information of patients such as MRIs, CT scans and ultrasound images. DCM files use DICOM (Digital Imaging and Communications in Medicine) image file format and can include patient’s information for reference. It was developed by the National Electrical Manufacturers Association (NEMA) and was meant to standardize the imaging file format for distribution and viewing of medical images.</description></item><item><title>DICOM - Digital Imaging and Communications File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dicom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dicom/</guid><description>What is a DICOM file? DICOM is the acronym for Digital Imaging and Communications in Medicine and pertains to the field of Medical Informatics. DICOM is used for the integration of medical imaging devices like printers, servers, scanners etc from various vendors and also contains identification data of each patient for uniqueness. DICOM files can be shared between two parties if they are capable of receiving image data in DICOM format.</description></item><item><title>DJVU File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/djvu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/djvu/</guid><description>What is a DJVU file? DjVu, pronounced as “déjà vu”, is a graphics file format intended for scanned documents and books especially those which contain the combination of text, drawings, images and photographs. It was developed by AT&amp;amp;T Labs. It uses multiple techniques like image layer separation of text and background images, progressive loading, arithmetic coding and lossy compression for bitonal images. Since DJVU file can contain compressed yet high-quality colour images, photographs, text, and drawings and can be saved in less space therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s used on web as eBooks, manuals, newspapers, ancient documents, etc.</description></item><item><title>DNG - Digital Camera Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dng/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dng/</guid><description>What is a DNG file? DNG is a digital camera image format used for the storage of raw files. It has been developed by Adobe in September 2004. It was basically developed for digital photography. DNG is an extension of TIFF/EP standard format and uses metadata significantly. In order to manipulate raw data from digital cameras with the ease of flexibility and artistic control, photographers opt camera raw files. JPEG and TIFF formats store images that are processed by the camera, therefore, not much room for alteration is available in such formats.</description></item><item><title>EMF - Enhanced Metafile Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/emf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/emf/</guid><description>What is an EMF file? Enhanced metafile format (EMF) stores graphical images device-independently. Metafiles of EMF comprises of variable-length records in chronological order that can render the stored image after parsing on any output device. These variable-length records can be definitions of enclosed objects, commands for drawing, and graphics properties critical to render the image accurately. When a device opens an EMF metafile using its own graphics environment, the proportions, dimensions, colors and other graphic properties of original image remains same regardless of the opening device platform.</description></item><item><title>EMZ File Format - A Windows Compressed Enhanced Meta file</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/emz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/emz/</guid><description>What is an EMZ file? A file with .emz extension is a compressed container of Enhanced Metafile (EMF file). These are compressed using the GZIP compression technique which is the commonly used compression method on UNIX and LINUX operating systems. Unlink ZIP (/compression/zip/), GZIP compresses the archive as a whole instead of compressing individual files. EMZ files are smaller in size as compared to the EMF files and help in fast transfer during online file sharing.</description></item><item><title>EXIF</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/exif/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/exif/</guid><description>What is an EXIF file? EXIF stands for “Exchangeable Image File Format”, the definition first given by Japan Camera Industry Association (JCIA) in 1985. The standard is managed by Japan Electronics and Information Technology Industries Association (JEITA) as of today. EXIF is a standard for the specifications of image and sound formats mainly used by digital cameras and scanners.
EXIF standard includes the tagging and metadata information with the image file.</description></item><item><title>FODG - OpenDocument Drawing File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/fodg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/fodg/</guid><description>What is a FODG file? A file with .fodg extension is an Apache OpenOffice Drawing file format for storing drawing elements. It is based on the file format specifications outlined by Advancement of Structural Information Standards (OASIS). Another similar file format for OpenOffice graphics is ODG that stores drawing elements as a vector image. FODG files can be opened with OpenOffice as well as LibreOffice. Other file formats supported by OpenOffice, for example, include ODT, ODF, ODP and ODS.</description></item><item><title>GBR File Format - Gerber File Format for PCB</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/gbr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/gbr/</guid><description>What is a GBR file? A file with .gbr extension is a Gerber image file format for exchange of printed circuit board (PCB) design data transfer. It was developed by Ucamco. PCB design data is the main component required by the fabrication industry for handling. A GRB file contains PCB data such as copper layers, solder mask, legend, and drill and route data. It can be used to transfer data such as PCB fabrication characteristics including thickness or finish in a standardized format.</description></item><item><title>GIF - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/gif/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/gif/</guid><description>What is a GIF file? A GIF or Graphical Interchange Format is a type of highly compressed image. Owned by Unisys, GIF uses the LZW compression algorithm that does not degrade the image quality. For each image GIF typically allow up to 8 bits per pixel and up to 256 colours are allowed across the image. In contrast to a JPEG image, which can display up to 16 million colours and fairly touches the limits of the human eye.</description></item><item><title>HEIC - High-Efficiency Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/heic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/heic/</guid><description>What is an HEIC file? An HEIC file is a High-Efficiency Container Image file format that can store multiple images as a collection in a single file. The format was adopted by Apple as variant of the HEIF with the launch of iOS 11. It was adopted as the default file format for storing images in compressed form on mobile devices. HEIC, like HEIF, are compressed using the High Efficiency Video Coding (HEVC) standard and are smaller in size without compromising the quality.</description></item><item><title>HEIF - High-Efficiency Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/heif/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/heif/</guid><description>What is a HEIF file? An HEIF file is a High-Efficiency Container Image file format that is capable of storing a single image or a sequence of images in a single file. It, thus, is basically a container having multiple images stored. HEIF file format compresses the images using the High Efficiency Video Coding (HEVC) standard. It is is more efficient and light weight as compared other image file formats such as JPEG.</description></item><item><title>ICO - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ico/</guid><description>What is a ICO file? Files with ICO extension are image file types used as icon for representation of an application on Microsoft Windows. These come in different size, colour support and resolution to suit the requirements of the display. Another similar image file format on Microsoft Windows is CUR for cursor representation and defines a hotspot in the image header. On MacOS, ICNS file formats serve the same purpose as ICO files.</description></item><item><title>J2C</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/j2c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/j2c/</guid><description>What is a J2C file? A file with .j2c extension is a variant of JPEG file format and is compressed with the wavelet compression. It has nearly identical system of markers and segments to JPEG 2000 file format. The J2C file format is as defined in the Part 1 of the JPEG 2000 stand that supports both lossy and lossless compression. The JPEG 2000 codestream was designed to be embedded in JP2 or another file format, although it may appear in a file by itself.</description></item><item><title>J2K</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/j2k/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/j2k/</guid><description>What is a J2K file? A J2K file is an image that is compressed using the wavelet compression instead of DCT compression. This file format is used by the Joint Photographic Experts Group (JPEG) 2000 files. J2K files store metadata information about the image file in XML unlike .jpeg or .jpg that use the EXIF format for this purpose. J2K files support 15-bit color, alpha transparency, and lossless compression. Several commercial APIs exist to decode JPEG 2000 imags such as J2K-Codec.</description></item><item><title>JP2 - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jp2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/jp2/</guid><description>What is a JP2 file? JPEG 2000 (JP2) is an image coding system and state-of-the-art image compression standard. It use wavelet technology to code lossless content in any quality at once. Moreover, without any substantial penalty in coding efficiency, JPEG 2000 have the capability to access and decode the same content efficaciously into a variety of other resolutions and qualities. The code streams in JPEG 2000 is significantly scalable having regions of interest that provide the facility for spatial random access.</description></item><item><title>MNG File Format - Multiple Image Network Graphics File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mng/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/mng/</guid><description>What is a MNG file? A file with .mng extension is a Mutliple-image Network Graphics file format that is similar to PNG image format but supports animated images. It was developed to avoid overloading the PNG format with additional feature of animations. MNG is also similar to GIF files but uses more compression and supports full alpha feature. The unofficial MIME media type for MNG files is video/x-mng. MNG files can be opened in applications such as ImageMagik and IrfanView.</description></item><item><title>ODG File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/odg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/odg/</guid><description>What is an ODG file? The ODG file format is used by Apache OpenOffice&amp;rsquo;s Draw application to store drawing elements as a vector image. It follows the XML based file format specifications outlined by Advancement of Structural Information Standards (OASIS). ODG represents drawings as vector images using points, lines and curves. Besides OpenOffice, LibreOffice and other applications also provide support for working with ODG file format. Other formats supported by OpenOffice, for example, include ODT, ODF, ODP and ODS.</description></item><item><title>PNG File Format - Raster Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/png/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/png/</guid><description>What is a PNG file? A PNG (Portable Network Graphics) file is a raster image file format that uses lossless compression. This file format was created as a replacement of Graphics Interchange Format (GIF) and has no copyright limitations. However, PNG file format does not support animations. PNG file format supports lossless image compression that makes it popular among its users. With the passage of time, PNG has evolved as one of the widely used image file formats.</description></item><item><title>PSB - Photoshop Big Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psb/</guid><description>What is a PSB file? Adobe photoshop saves files in two formats. Files having 30,000 by 30,000 pixels in size are saved with PSD extension and files larger than PSD upto 300,000 by 300,000 pixels are saved with PSB extension known as “Photoshop Big”. More specifically, PSB files can be as large as 4 EB (over 4.2 billion GB) with images that have a height and width of up to 300,000 pixels.</description></item><item><title>PSD - Photoshop Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/psd/</guid><description>What is a PSD file? PSD, Photoshop Document, represents Adobe Photoshop&amp;rsquo;s native file format used for graphics designing and development. PSD files may include image layers, adjustment layers, layer masks, annotations, file information, keywords and other Photoshop-specific elements. Photoshop files have default extension as .PSD and has a maximum height and width of 30,000 pixels, and a length limit of two gigabytes.
PSD File Format Specifications Data in a PSD file is stored in big endian byte order.</description></item><item><title>SKP File Format - SketchUp Document File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/skp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/skp/</guid><description>What is an SKP file? An SKP file is a proprietary three-dimensional model file created with the 3D design program SketchUp. It can comprise of several different 3D elements or components such as shades, wireframes, and textures. An SKP file can contain the entire architecture or may consist of smaller designs (such as door or a chair) of a larger design. This lets the models defined in such files to be reusable by inserting into other SketchUp documents.</description></item><item><title>SVGZ File Format - A Windows Compressed Enhanced Metafile</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/svgz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/svgz/</guid><description>What is an SVGZ file? A file with .svgz extension is a compressed version of Scalable Vector Graphics (.SVG) file. It is compressed with gzip compression and contains data in XML format. SVGZ files support transparency, gradients, animations, and filters. SVGZ files are smaller in size as compared to the default SVG files and this reduced file size helps transfer the graphics files online. Graphics designer create SVGZ files using tools like Adobe Illustrator, Corel PaintShop Pro, and others.</description></item><item><title>TGA File Format - A TARGA Graphic Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/tga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/tga/</guid><description>What is a TGA file? A file with .tga extension is a raster graphic format and was created by Truevision Inc. It was designed for the TARGA (Truevision Advanced Raster Adapter) boards and provided Highcolor/truecolor display support for IBM-compatible PCs. It supports 8, 16, 24 and 32 bits per pixel and 8-bit alpha channel. It also supports lossless RLE compression that can be applied to reduce the image size. Digital photos and textures use the TGA image format.</description></item><item><title>TIFF - Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/tiff/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/tiff/</guid><description>What is a TIFF file? TIFF or TIF, Tagged Image File Format, represents raster images that are meant for usage on a variety of devices that comply with this file format standard. It is capable of describing bilevel, grayscale, palette-color and full-color image data in several color spaces. It supports lossy as well as lossless compression schemes to choose between space and time for applications using the format. The format is not machine dependent and is free from bounds like processor, operating system, or file systems.</description></item><item><title>WEBP - Google Raster Image File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/webp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/webp/</guid><description>What is a WEBP file? WebP, introduced by Google, is a modern raster web image file format that is based on lossless and lossy compression. It provides same image quality while considerably reducing the image size. Since most of the web pages use images as effective representation of data, the use of WebP images in web pages results in faster loading of web pages. As per Google, WebP lossless images are 26% smaller in size compared to PNGs, while WebP lossy images are 25-34% smaller than comparable JPEG images.</description></item><item><title>WMF - Microsoft Windows Metafile Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/wmf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/wmf/</guid><description>What is a WMF file? Files with WMF extension represent Microsoft Windows Metafile (WMF) for storing vector as well as bitmap-format images data. To be more accurate, WMF belongs to the vector file format category of Graphics file formats that is device independent. Windows Graphical Device Interface (GDI) uses the functions stored in a WMF file to display an image on the screen. A more enhanced version of WMF, known as Enhanced Meta Files (EMF), was published later that makes the format more feature rich.</description></item><item><title>WMZ File Format - Compressed Windows Metafile</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/wmz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/wmz/</guid><description>What is an WMZ file? A file with .wmz extension is a compressed version of WMF and is used to store metafiles. It is an intermediate level file generated by older versions of Microsoft Office applications and is not very popularly used. WMZ files are generated while saving documents to HTML format. These may also be generated while emailing documents that contain embedded clip art, equations, etc. Applications that can open WMZ files include (but not limited to) Corel Winzip and Apple Archive Utility.</description></item><item><title>XPM - X PixMap File Format</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/xpm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/xpm/</guid><description>What is an XPM file? A file with .xpm extension is an image file format that was used by the X Windows System. It supports transparent pixels and usually targets creating icon pixmaps. It supports monochrome, gra-scale, and color pixmap data. These were designed to be editable by hand and can be included in C code. For this purpose, XPM files are in plain text file format and follow the C programming language syntax.</description></item><item><title>DCR - Digital Camera RAW Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/dcr/</guid><description>What is a DCR file? A file with dcr extension contains the content of a digital photograph saved in the Kodak Digital Camera RAW (DCR) format. The DCR is short for Digital Camera Raw; contains the uncompressed and lossless version of the images data captured by a Kodak digital camera. The professional photographers like to use these files, because they store images at a higher quality than low quality compressed image formats.</description></item><item><title>ECW - Enhanced Compression Wavelet Image File</title><link>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ecw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.fileformat.com/image/ecw/</guid><description>What is a ECW file? An ECW file consists of an image designed for use with geospatial data. The containing image is actually compressed image created in the Enhanced Compression Wavelet format. ECW files are generally used for storing satellite map projection and aerial images. To support geospatial applications, map projection information can be embedded into the ECW files.
ECW file format ECW is a proprietary image format based on wavelet compression; optimized for satellite imagery and aerial photography.</description></item></channel></rss>